HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON
HILLARY CLINTON OFFICIALLY
LAUNCHED
LAUNCHED HER
HILLARY CLINTON OFFICIALLY
LAUNCHED HER CAMPAIGN
LAUNCHED HER CAMPAIGN WITH
LAUNCHED HER CAMPAIGN WITH A
RALLY
RALLY IN
LAUNCHED HER CAMPAIGN WITH A
RALLY IN NEW
RALLY IN NEW YORK
LAUNCHED HER CAMPAIGN WITH A
RALLY IN NEW YORK CITY.
IT
IT IS
RALLY IN NEW YORK CITY.
IT IS HER
IT IS HER FIRST
RALLY IN NEW YORK CITY.
IT IS HER FIRST MAJOR
IT IS HER FIRST MAJOR CAMPAIGN
SPEECH
SPEECH SINCE
IT IS HER FIRST MAJOR CAMPAIGN
SPEECH SINCE ANNOUNCING
SPEECH SINCE ANNOUNCING HER
IT IS HER FIRST MAJOR CAMPAIGN
SPEECH SINCE ANNOUNCING HER RUN
FOR
FOR PRESIDENT
SPEECH SINCE ANNOUNCING HER RUN
FOR PRESIDENT LAST
FOR PRESIDENT LAST APRIL.
SPEECH SINCE ANNOUNCING HER RUN
THE
FOR PRESIDENT LAST APRIL.
THE EVENT
THE EVENT WAS
FOR PRESIDENT LAST APRIL.
THE EVENT WAS HELD
THE EVENT WAS HELD AT
FOR PRESIDENT LAST APRIL.
THE EVENT WAS HELD AT THE
FRANKLIN
FRANKLIN D.
THE EVENT WAS HELD AT THE
ROOSEVELT
FRANKLIN D.
ROOSEVELT FOR
THE EVENT WAS HELD AT THE
FRANKLIN D.
ROOSEVELT FOR FREEDOM
ROOSEVELT FOR FREEDOM PARK
FRANKLIN D.
ROOSEVELT FOR FREEDOM PARK ON
ROOSEVELT
FRANKLIN D.
ROOSEVELT FOR FREEDOM PARK ON
ROOSEVELT ISLAND.
FOLLOWING
ROOSEVELT FOR FREEDOM PARK ON
ROOSEVELT ISLAND.
FOLLOWING THIS
ROOSEVELT FOR FREEDOM PARK ON
ROOSEVELT ISLAND.
FOLLOWING THIS RALLY,
FOLLOWING THIS RALLY, SHE
ROOSEVELT ISLAND.
FOLLOWING THIS RALLY, SHE IS
HEADED
HEADED TO
FOLLOWING THIS RALLY, SHE IS
HEADED TO IOWA
HEADED TO IOWA FOLLOWED
FOLLOWING THIS RALLY, SHE IS
HEADED TO IOWA FOLLOWED BY
SEVERAL
SEVERAL DATES
HEADED TO IOWA FOLLOWED BY
SEVERAL DATES OF
SEVERAL DATES OF CAMPAIGNING
HEADED TO IOWA FOLLOWED BY
SEVERAL DATES OF CAMPAIGNING IN
NEW
NEW HAMPSHIRE,
SEVERAL DATES OF CAMPAIGNING IN
NEW HAMPSHIRE, SOUTH
NEW HAMPSHIRE, SOUTH CAROLINA.
SEVERAL DATES OF CAMPAIGNING IN
(music)
NEW HAMPSHIRE, SOUTH CAROLINA.
I
I WANT
I WANT TO
I WANT TO SEE
I WANT TO SEE YOU
I WANT TO SEE YOU BE
BRAVE (music)
(music)
[CHEERING]
[CROWD
CHANTING "HILLARY!"]
HILLARY
HILLARY CLINTON:
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK
HILLARY CLINTON: THANK YOU.
THANK
THANK YOU
THANK YOU SO
THANK YOU SO VERY,
THANK YOU SO VERY, VERY
THANK YOU SO VERY, VERY MUCH.
IT
IT IS
IT IS WONDERFUL
IT IS WONDERFUL TO
IT IS WONDERFUL TO BE
IT IS WONDERFUL TO BE HERE
IT IS WONDERFUL TO BE HERE WITH
ALL
ALL OF
IT IS WONDERFUL TO BE HERE WITH
ALL OF YOU,
ALL OF YOU, TO
IT IS WONDERFUL TO BE HERE WITH
ALL OF YOU, TO BE
ALL OF YOU, TO BE IN
ALL OF YOU, TO BE IN NEW
YORK
YORK WITH
YORK WITH MY
YORK WITH MY FAMILY,
YORK WITH MY FAMILY, SO
YORK WITH MY FAMILY, SO MANY
FRIENDS,
FRIENDS, INCLUDING
YORK WITH MY FAMILY, SO MANY
FRIENDS, INCLUDING SO
FRIENDS, INCLUDING SO MANY
FRIENDS, INCLUDING SO MANY NEW
YORKERS
YORKERS WHO
FRIENDS, INCLUDING SO MANY NEW
YORKERS WHO GAVE
YORKERS WHO GAVE ME
FRIENDS, INCLUDING SO MANY NEW
YORKERS WHO GAVE ME THE
YORKERS WHO GAVE ME THE HONOR
FRIENDS, INCLUDING SO MANY NEW
YORKERS WHO GAVE ME THE HONOR OF
SERVING
SERVING THEM
YORKERS WHO GAVE ME THE HONOR OF
SERVING THEM IN
SERVING THEM IN THE
YORKERS WHO GAVE ME THE HONOR OF
SERVING THEM IN THE SENATE
SERVING THEM IN THE SENATE FOR
YORKERS WHO GAVE ME THE HONOR OF
EIGHT
SERVING THEM IN THE SENATE FOR
EIGHT YEARS.
TO
TO BE
EIGHT YEARS.
TO BE RIGHT
TO BE RIGHT ACROSS
EIGHT YEARS.
TO BE RIGHT ACROSS THE
TO BE RIGHT ACROSS THE WATER
FROM
FROM THE
TO BE RIGHT ACROSS THE WATER
FROM THE HEADQUARTERS
FROM THE HEADQUARTERS OF
FROM THE HEADQUARTERS OF THE
UNITED
UNITED NATIONS
FROM THE HEADQUARTERS OF THE
UNITED NATIONS WHERE
UNITED NATIONS WHERE I
FROM THE HEADQUARTERS OF THE
REPRESENTED
UNITED NATIONS WHERE I
REPRESENTED OUR
REPRESENTED OUR COUNTRY
UNITED NATIONS WHERE I
REPRESENTED OUR COUNTRY MANY
TIMES.
TO
TO BE
TIMES.
TO BE HERE
TO BE HERE IN
TIMES.
TO BE HERE IN THIS
TO BE HERE IN THIS BEAUTIFUL
PARK
PARK DEDICATED
TO BE HERE IN THIS BEAUTIFUL
PARK DEDICATED TO
PARK DEDICATED TO FRANKLIN
ROOSEVELT
ROOSEVELT VISION --
ROOSEVELT VISION -- ENDURING
VISION
VISION OF
ROOSEVELT VISION -- ENDURING
VISION OF AMERICA.
IN
IN A
VISION OF AMERICA.
IN A PLACE
IN A PLACE WITH
VISION OF AMERICA.
IN A PLACE WITH ABSOLUTELY
IN A PLACE WITH ABSOLUTELY NO
VISION OF AMERICA.
CEILINGS.
IN A PLACE WITH ABSOLUTELY NO
>> [CHEERING]
CEILINGS.
>> [CHEERING] HILLARY
>> [CHEERING] HILLARY CLINTON:
PRESIDENT
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT FOUR
FREEDOMS
FREEDOMS ARE
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT FOUR
FREEDOMS ARE TESTAMENT
FREEDOMS ARE TESTAMENT TO
FREEDOMS ARE TESTAMENT TO OUR
NATION'S
NATION'S UNMATCHED
NATION'S UNMATCHED ASPIRATIONS
AND
AND REMINDER
NATION'S UNMATCHED ASPIRATIONS
AND REMINDER OF
AND REMINDER OF OUR
AND REMINDER OF OUR UNFINISHED
WORK
WORK AT
AND REMINDER OF OUR UNFINISHED
WORK AT HOME
WORK AT HOME AND
AND REMINDER OF OUR UNFINISHED
WORK AT HOME AND ABROAD.
HIS
HIS LEGACY
WORK AT HOME AND ABROAD.
HIS LEGACY LIFTED
HIS LEGACY LIFTED UP
WORK AT HOME AND ABROAD.
HIS LEGACY LIFTED UP A
HIS LEGACY LIFTED UP A NATION
AND
AND INSPIRED
AND INSPIRED PRESIDENT
AND INSPIRED PRESIDENT TO
FOLLOWED.
ONE
ONE IS
FOLLOWED.
ONE IS A
ONE IS A MAN
FOLLOWED.
ONE IS A MAN I
ONE IS A MAN I SERVED
ONE IS A MAN I SERVED AS
SECRETARY
SECRETARY OF
ONE IS A MAN I SERVED AS
SECRETARY OF STATE,
SECRETARY OF STATE, BARACK
OBAMA.
>> [CHEERING]
>> [CHEERING] HILLARY
>> [CHEERING] HILLARY CLINTON:
ANOTHER
ANOTHER IS
>> [CHEERING] HILLARY CLINTON:
ANOTHER IS MY
ANOTHER IS MY HUSBAND,
ANOTHER IS MY HUSBAND, BILL
CLINTON.
TWO
TWO DEMOCRATS --
THAT
THAT WILL
THAT WILL MAKE
THAT WILL MAKE HIM
THAT WILL MAKE HIM SO
THAT WILL MAKE HIM SO HAPPY.
THEY
THEY ARE
THEY ARE TWO
THEY ARE TWO DEMOCRATS
THEY ARE TWO DEMOCRATS GUIDED
THEY ARE TWO DEMOCRATS GUIDED BY
THE
THE FUNDAMENTAL
THE FUNDAMENTAL AMERICAN
THE FUNDAMENTAL AMERICAN BELIEF
THAT
THAT REAL
THE FUNDAMENTAL AMERICAN BELIEF
THAT REAL AND
THAT REAL AND LASTING
THAT REAL AND LASTING PROSPERITY
MUST
MUST BE
THAT REAL AND LASTING PROSPERITY
MUST BE BUILT
MUST BE BUILT BY
THAT REAL AND LASTING PROSPERITY
MUST BE BUILT BY ALL
MUST BE BUILT BY ALL AND
MUST BE BUILT BY ALL AND SHARED
BY
BY ALL.
PRESIDENT
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT CALLED
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT CALLED ON
EVERY
EVERY AMERICAN
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT CALLED ON
EVERY AMERICAN TO
EVERY AMERICAN TO DO
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT CALLED ON
EVERY AMERICAN TO DO IS --
EVERY AMERICAN TO DO IS -- TO
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT CALLED ON
EVERY AMERICAN TO DO IS -- TO DO
HIS
HIS OR
EVERY AMERICAN TO DO IS -- TO DO
HIS OR HER
HIS OR HER PART
EVERY AMERICAN TO DO IS -- TO DO
HIS OR HER PART IN
HIS OR HER PART IN EVERY
AMERICAN
AMERICAN ANSWERED.
HE
HE SAID,
AMERICAN ANSWERED.
HE SAID, THERE
HE SAID, THERE IS
AMERICAN ANSWERED.
HE SAID, THERE IS NO
HE SAID, THERE IS NO MYSTERY
ABOUT
ABOUT WHAT
HE SAID, THERE IS NO MYSTERY
ABOUT WHAT IT
ABOUT WHAT IT TAKES
HE SAID, THERE IS NO MYSTERY
ABOUT WHAT IT TAKES TO
ABOUT WHAT IT TAKES TO BUILD
HE SAID, THERE IS NO MYSTERY
ABOUT WHAT IT TAKES TO BUILD A
STRONG
STRONG AND
ABOUT WHAT IT TAKES TO BUILD A
STRONG AND PROSPEROUS
STRONG AND PROSPEROUS AMERICA.
EQUALITY
EQUALITY OF
EQUALITY OF OPPORTUNITY,
EQUALITY OF OPPORTUNITY, JOBS
FOR
FOR THOSE
EQUALITY OF OPPORTUNITY, JOBS
FOR THOSE WHO
FOR THOSE WHO CAN
EQUALITY OF OPPORTUNITY, JOBS
FOR THOSE WHO CAN WORK,
FOR THOSE WHO CAN WORK, SECURITY
FOR
FOR THOSE
FOR THOSE WHO CAN WORK, SECURITY
FOR THOSE WHO
FOR THOSE WHO NEED
FOR THOSE WHO CAN WORK, SECURITY
FOR THOSE WHO NEED IT,
FOR THOSE WHO NEED IT, THE
ENDING
ENDING OF
FOR THOSE WHO NEED IT, THE
ENDING OF SPECIAL
ENDING OF SPECIAL PRIVILEGE
ENDING OF SPECIAL PRIVILEGE FOR
THE
THE FEW --
ENDING OF SPECIAL PRIVILEGE FOR
[CHEERING]
THE FEW --
[CHEERING] THE
[CHEERING] THE PRESERVATION
THE FEW --
[CHEERING] THE PRESERVATION OF
CIVIL
CIVIL LIBERTIES
[CHEERING] THE PRESERVATION OF
CIVIL LIBERTIES FOR
CIVIL LIBERTIES FOR ALL,
CIVIL LIBERTIES FOR ALL, A
CIVIL LIBERTIES FOR ALL, A WIDER
AND
AND CONSTANTLY
CIVIL LIBERTIES FOR ALL, A WIDER
AND CONSTANTLY RISING
AND CONSTANTLY RISING STANDARD
OF
OF LIVING.
THAT
THAT STILL
THAT STILL SOUNDS
THAT STILL SOUNDS GOOD
THAT STILL SOUNDS GOOD TO
THAT STILL SOUNDS GOOD TO ME.
IT
IT IS
IT IS AMERICA'S
IT IS AMERICA'S BASIC
IT IS AMERICA'S BASIC BARGAIN,
IF
IF YOU
IT IS AMERICA'S BASIC BARGAIN,
IF YOU DO
IF YOU DO YOUR
IT IS AMERICA'S BASIC BARGAIN,
IF YOU DO YOUR PART,
IF YOU DO YOUR PART, YOU
IT IS AMERICA'S BASIC BARGAIN,
IF YOU DO YOUR PART, YOU OUGHT
TO
TO BE
IF YOU DO YOUR PART, YOU OUGHT
TO BE ABLE
TO BE ABLE TO
IF YOU DO YOUR PART, YOU OUGHT
TO BE ABLE TO GET
TO BE ABLE TO GET AHEAD.
WHEN
WHEN EVERYBODY
TO BE ABLE TO GET AHEAD.
WHEN EVERYBODY DOES
WHEN EVERYBODY DOES THEIR
WHEN EVERYBODY DOES THEIR PART,
AMERICA
AMERICA GETS
AMERICA GETS AHEAD,
AMERICA GETS AHEAD, TOO.
THAT
THAT BARGAIN
THAT BARGAIN INSPIRED
GENERATIONS
GENERATIONS OF
THAT BARGAIN INSPIRED
GENERATIONS OF FAMILIES,
INCLUDING
INCLUDING MY
GENERATIONS OF FAMILIES,
INCLUDING MY OWN.
IT
IT IS
INCLUDING MY OWN.
IT IS WHAT
IT IS WHAT KEPT
INCLUDING MY OWN.
IT IS WHAT KEPT MY
IT IS WHAT KEPT MY GRANDFATHER
GOING
GOING TO
IT IS WHAT KEPT MY GRANDFATHER
GOING TO WORK
GOING TO WORK IN
IT IS WHAT KEPT MY GRANDFATHER
GOING TO WORK IN THE
GOING TO WORK IN THE SAME
SCRANTON
SCRANTON MILL
GOING TO WORK IN THE SAME
SCRANTON MILL EVERY
SCRANTON MILL EVERY DAY
SCRANTON MILL EVERY DAY FOR
SCRANTON MILL EVERY DAY FOR 50
YEARS.
IT
SCRANTON MILL EVERY DAY FOR 50
YEARS.
IT IS
SCRANTON MILL EVERY DAY FOR 50
YEARS.
IT IS WHAT
SCRANTON MILL EVERY DAY FOR 50
YEARS.
IT IS WHAT LED
IT IS WHAT LED MY
YEARS.
IT IS WHAT LED MY FATHER
IT IS WHAT LED MY FATHER TO
BELIEVE
BELIEVE THAT
IT IS WHAT LED MY FATHER TO
BELIEVE THAT HE
BELIEVE THAT HE SCRIMPED
IT IS WHAT LED MY FATHER TO
BELIEVE THAT HE SCRIMPED AND
SAVED,
SAVED, HIS
BELIEVE THAT HE SCRIMPED AND
SAVED, HIS SMALL
SAVED, HIS SMALL BUSINESS
BELIEVE THAT HE SCRIMPED AND
PRINTING
SAVED, HIS SMALL BUSINESS
PRINTING DRAPERY
PRINTING DRAPERY FABRIC
SAVED, HIS SMALL BUSINESS
PRINTING DRAPERY FABRIC IN
CHICAGO
CHICAGO WOULD
PRINTING DRAPERY FABRIC IN
CHICAGO WOULD PROVIDE
CHICAGO WOULD PROVIDE US
CHICAGO WOULD PROVIDE US WITH
CHICAGO WOULD PROVIDE US WITH A
MIDDLE-CLASS
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE.
CHICAGO WOULD PROVIDE US WITH A
AND
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE.
AND IT
CHICAGO WOULD PROVIDE US WITH A
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE.
AND IT DID.
WHEN
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE.
AND IT DID.
WHEN PRESIDENT
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE.
AND IT DID.
WHEN PRESIDENT CLINTON
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE.
AND IT DID.
WHEN PRESIDENT CLINTON HONORED
THE
AND IT DID.
WHEN PRESIDENT CLINTON HONORED
THE BARGAIN,
AND IT DID.
WHEN PRESIDENT CLINTON HONORED
THE BARGAIN, WE
AND IT DID.
WHEN PRESIDENT CLINTON HONORED
THE BARGAIN, WE HAD
THE BARGAIN, WE HAD THE
WHEN PRESIDENT CLINTON HONORED
THE BARGAIN, WE HAD THE LONGEST
PEACETIME
PEACETIME EXPANSION
THE BARGAIN, WE HAD THE LONGEST
PEACETIME EXPANSION IN
PEACETIME EXPANSION IN HISTORY,
A
A BALANCED
A BALANCED BUDGET,
A BALANCED BUDGET, AND
A BALANCED BUDGET, AND FOR
A BALANCED BUDGET, AND FOR THE
FIRST
FIRST TIME
A BALANCED BUDGET, AND FOR THE
FIRST TIME IN
FIRST TIME IN DECADES,
FIRST TIME IN DECADES, WE
FIRST TIME IN DECADES, WE ALL
GREW
GREW TOGETHER
GREW TOGETHER WITH
GREW TOGETHER WITH THE
GREW TOGETHER WITH THE BOTTOM
20%
20% OF
GREW TOGETHER WITH THE BOTTOM
20% OF WORKERS
20% OF WORKERS INCREASING
20% OF WORKERS INCREASING THEIR
INCOMES
INCOMES BY
20% OF WORKERS INCREASING THEIR
INCOMES BY THE
INCOMES BY THE SAME
INCOMES BY THE SAME PERCENTAGE
AS
AS THE
INCOMES BY THE SAME PERCENTAGE
AS THE TOP
AS THE TOP 5%.
WHEN
WHEN PRESIDENT
AS THE TOP 5%.
WHEN PRESIDENT OBAMA
WHEN PRESIDENT OBAMA HONORED
WHEN PRESIDENT OBAMA HONORED THE
BARGAIN,
BARGAIN, WE
BARGAIN, WE PULLED
BARGAIN, WE PULLED BACK
BARGAIN, WE PULLED BACK FROM
BARGAIN, WE PULLED BACK FROM THE
BRINK
BRINK OF
BRINK OF DEPRESSION,
BRINK OF DEPRESSION, SAVED
BRINK OF DEPRESSION, SAVED THE
AUTO
AUTO INDUSTRY,
BRINK OF DEPRESSION, SAVED THE
AUTO INDUSTRY, PROVIDED
AUTO INDUSTRY, PROVIDED HEALTH
CARE
CARE TO
AUTO INDUSTRY, PROVIDED HEALTH
CARE TO 16
CARE TO 16 MILLION
AUTO INDUSTRY, PROVIDED HEALTH
CARE TO 16 MILLION WORKING
PEOPLE
AND
AND REPLACED
AND REPLACED THE
AND REPLACED THE JOBS
AND REPLACED THE JOBS WE
AND REPLACED THE JOBS WE LOST
FASTER
FASTER THAN
AND REPLACED THE JOBS WE LOST
FASTER THAN THE
FASTER THAN THE HISTORICAL
AND REPLACED THE JOBS WE LOST
AVERAGE
FASTER THAN THE HISTORICAL
AVERAGE AFTER
AVERAGE AFTER A
FASTER THAN THE HISTORICAL
AVERAGE AFTER A FINANCIAL
AVERAGE AFTER A FINANCIAL CRASH.
IT
IT IS
IT IS NOT
IT IS NOT 1941
IT IS NOT 1941 OR
IT IS NOT 1941 OR 1993
IT IS NOT 1941 OR 1993 OR
IT IS NOT 1941 OR 1993 OR EVEN
2009.
2009. WE
2009. WE FACE
2009. WE FACE NEW
2009. WE FACE NEW CHALLENGES
2009. WE FACE NEW CHALLENGES IN
OUR
OUR ECONOMY
2009. WE FACE NEW CHALLENGES IN
OUR ECONOMY AND
OUR ECONOMY AND OUR
OUR ECONOMY AND OUR DEMOCRACY.
WE
WE ARE
OUR ECONOMY AND OUR DEMOCRACY.
WE ARE STILL
WE ARE STILL WORKING
OUR ECONOMY AND OUR DEMOCRACY.
WE ARE STILL WORKING OUR
WE ARE STILL WORKING OUR WAY
BACK
BACK FROM
BACK FROM A
BACK FROM A CRISIS
BACK FROM A CRISIS THAT
BACK FROM A CRISIS THAT HAPPENED
BECAUSE
BECAUSE TIME-TESTED
BECAUSE TIME-TESTED VALUES
BECAUSE TIME-TESTED VALUES WERE
REPLACED
REPLACED BY
REPLACED BY FALSE
REPLACED BY FALSE PROMISES.
INSTEAD
INSTEAD OF
INSTEAD OF AN
INSTEAD OF AN ECONOMY
INSTEAD OF AN ECONOMY BUILT
INSTEAD OF AN ECONOMY BUILT BY
EVERY
EVERY AMERICAN,
INSTEAD OF AN ECONOMY BUILT BY
EVERY AMERICAN, FOR
EVERY AMERICAN, FOR EVERY
AMERICAN,
AMERICAN, WE
EVERY AMERICAN, FOR EVERY
AMERICAN, WE WERE
AMERICAN, WE WERE TOLD
EVERY AMERICAN, FOR EVERY
AMERICAN, WE WERE TOLD THAT
AMERICAN, WE WERE TOLD THAT IF
EVERY AMERICAN, FOR EVERY
WE
AMERICAN, WE WERE TOLD THAT IF
WE LET
WE LET THOSE
AMERICAN, WE WERE TOLD THAT IF
WE LET THOSE AT
WE LET THOSE AT THE
AMERICAN, WE WERE TOLD THAT IF
WE LET THOSE AT THE TOP
WE LET THOSE AT THE TOP PAY
AMERICAN, WE WERE TOLD THAT IF
LOWER
WE LET THOSE AT THE TOP PAY
LOWER TAXES
LOWER TAXES AND
WE LET THOSE AT THE TOP PAY
LOWER TAXES AND BEND
LOWER TAXES AND BEND THE
WE LET THOSE AT THE TOP PAY
LOWER TAXES AND BEND THE RULES,
THEIR
THEIR SUCCESS
LOWER TAXES AND BEND THE RULES,
THEIR SUCCESS WOULD
THEIR SUCCESS WOULD TRICKLE
THEIR SUCCESS WOULD TRICKLE DOWN
TO
TO EVERYONE
THEIR SUCCESS WOULD TRICKLE DOWN
TO EVERYONE ELSE.
WHAT
WHAT HAPPENED?
TO EVERYONE ELSE.
WELL,
WHAT HAPPENED?
WELL, INSTEAD
WELL, INSTEAD OF
WHAT HAPPENED?
WELL, INSTEAD OF A
WELL, INSTEAD OF A BALANCED
BUDGET
BUDGET WOULD
WELL, INSTEAD OF A BALANCED
BUDGET WOULD SURPLUSES
BUDGET WOULD SURPLUSES THAT
WELL, INSTEAD OF A BALANCED
COULD
BUDGET WOULD SURPLUSES THAT
COULD HAVE
COULD HAVE EVENTUALLY
BUDGET WOULD SURPLUSES THAT
COULD HAVE EVENTUALLY PAID
COULD HAVE EVENTUALLY PAID OFF
OUR
OUR NATIONAL
COULD HAVE EVENTUALLY PAID OFF
OUR NATIONAL DEBT,
OUR NATIONAL DEBT, THE
COULD HAVE EVENTUALLY PAID OFF
REPUBLICANS
OUR NATIONAL DEBT, THE
REPUBLICANS TWICE
REPUBLICANS TWICE CUT
OUR NATIONAL DEBT, THE
REPUBLICANS TWICE CUT TAXES
REPUBLICANS TWICE CUT TAXES FOR
THE
THE WEALTHIEST,
REPUBLICANS TWICE CUT TAXES FOR
THE WEALTHIEST, BORROWED
THE WEALTHIEST, BORROWED MONEY
FROM
FROM OTHER
THE WEALTHIEST, BORROWED MONEY
FROM OTHER COUNTRIES
FROM OTHER COUNTRIES TO
FROM OTHER COUNTRIES TO PAY
FROM OTHER COUNTRIES TO PAY FOR
TWO
TWO WARS,
TWO WARS, AND
TWO WARS, AND FAMILY
TWO WARS, AND FAMILY INCOMES
DROPPED.
YOU
TWO WARS, AND FAMILY INCOMES
DROPPED.
YOU KNOW
TWO WARS, AND FAMILY INCOMES
DROPPED.
YOU KNOW WHERE
YOU KNOW WHERE WE
DROPPED.
YOU KNOW WHERE WE ENDED
YOU KNOW WHERE WE ENDED UP.
EXCEPT
EXCEPT IT
YOU KNOW WHERE WE ENDED UP.
EXCEPT IT WAS
EXCEPT IT WAS NOT
YOU KNOW WHERE WE ENDED UP.
EXCEPT IT WAS NOT THE
EXCEPT IT WAS NOT THE END.
AS
AS WE
EXCEPT IT WAS NOT THE END.
AS WE HAVE
AS WE HAVE SINCE
AS WE HAVE SINCE OUR
AS WE HAVE SINCE OUR FOUNDING,
AMERICANS
AMERICANS MADE
AMERICANS MADE A
AMERICANS MADE A NEW
AMERICANS MADE A NEW BEGINNING.
YOU
YOU WORKED
YOU WORKED EXTRA
YOU WORKED EXTRA SHIFTS,
YOU WORKED EXTRA SHIFTS, TOOK
SECOND
SECOND JOBS,
YOU WORKED EXTRA SHIFTS, TOOK
SECOND JOBS, POSTPONED
SECOND JOBS, POSTPONED HOME
REPAIRS,
REPAIRS, YOU
SECOND JOBS, POSTPONED HOME
REPAIRS, YOU FIGURED
REPAIRS, YOU FIGURED OUT
SECOND JOBS, POSTPONED HOME
REPAIRS, YOU FIGURED OUT HOW
REPAIRS, YOU FIGURED OUT HOW TO
SECOND JOBS, POSTPONED HOME
MAKE
REPAIRS, YOU FIGURED OUT HOW TO
MAKE IT
MAKE IT WORK.
NOW
NOW PEOPLE
MAKE IT WORK.
NOW PEOPLE ARE
NOW PEOPLE ARE BEGINNING
MAKE IT WORK.
NOW PEOPLE ARE BEGINNING TO
THINK
MAKE IT WORK.
NOW PEOPLE ARE BEGINNING TO
THINK ABOUT
MAKE IT WORK.
NOW PEOPLE ARE BEGINNING TO
THINK ABOUT THEIR
THINK ABOUT THEIR FUTURE
NOW PEOPLE ARE BEGINNING TO
THINK ABOUT THEIR FUTURE AGAIN,
GOING
GOING TO
THINK ABOUT THEIR FUTURE AGAIN,
GOING TO COLLEGE,
GOING TO COLLEGE, STARTING
THINK ABOUT THEIR FUTURE AGAIN,
GOING TO COLLEGE, STARTING A
BUSINESS,
BUSINESS, BUYING
GOING TO COLLEGE, STARTING A
BUSINESS, BUYING A
BUSINESS, BUYING A HOUSE,
FINALLY
FINALLY BEING
BUSINESS, BUYING A HOUSE,
FINALLY BEING ABLE
FINALLY BEING ABLE TO
BUSINESS, BUYING A HOUSE,
FINALLY BEING ABLE TO PUT
FINALLY BEING ABLE TO PUT AWAY
BUSINESS, BUYING A HOUSE,
SOMETHING
FINALLY BEING ABLE TO PUT AWAY
SOMETHING FOR
SOMETHING FOR RETIREMENT.
FINALLY BEING ABLE TO PUT AWAY
WE
SOMETHING FOR RETIREMENT.
WE ARE
WE ARE STANDING
SOMETHING FOR RETIREMENT.
WE ARE STANDING AGAIN,
WE ARE STANDING AGAIN, BUT
WE ARE STANDING AGAIN, BUT WE
ALL
ALL KNOW
WE ARE STANDING AGAIN, BUT WE
ALL KNOW WE
ALL KNOW WE ARE
WE ARE STANDING AGAIN, BUT WE
ALL KNOW WE ARE NOT
ALL KNOW WE ARE NOT YET
ALL KNOW WE ARE NOT YET RUNNING
THE
THE WAY
ALL KNOW WE ARE NOT YET RUNNING
THE WAY AMERICA
THE WAY AMERICA SHOULD.
YOU
YOU SEE
YOU SEE CORPORATIONS
YOU SEE CORPORATIONS MAKING
RECORD
RECORD PROFITS
RECORD PROFITS WITH
RECORD PROFITS WITH CEOS
RECORD PROFITS WITH CEOS MAKING
RECORD
RECORD PAY,
RECORD PROFITS WITH CEOS MAKING
RECORD PAY, BUT
RECORD PAY, BUT YOUR
RECORD PAY, BUT YOUR PAYCHECKS
HAVE
HAVE BARELY
RECORD PAY, BUT YOUR PAYCHECKS
HAVE BARELY BUDGED.
MANY
MANY OF
HAVE BARELY BUDGED.
MANY OF YOUR
MANY OF YOUR WORKING
HAVE BARELY BUDGED.
MANY OF YOUR WORKING MULTIPLE
JOBS
HAVE BARELY BUDGED.
MANY OF YOUR WORKING MULTIPLE
JOBS TO
JOBS TO MAKE
MANY OF YOUR WORKING MULTIPLE
JOBS TO MAKE ENDS
JOBS TO MAKE ENDS MEET,
JOBS TO MAKE ENDS MEET, YOU
JOBS TO MAKE ENDS MEET, YOU SEE
THE
THE TOP
JOBS TO MAKE ENDS MEET, YOU SEE
THE TOP 25
THE TOP 25 HEDGE
JOBS TO MAKE ENDS MEET, YOU SEE
THE TOP 25 HEDGE FUND
THE TOP 25 HEDGE FUND MANAGERS
MAKING
MAKING MORE
MAKING MORE THAN
MAKING MORE THAN ALL
MAKING MORE THAN ALL OF
AMERICA'S
AMERICA'S KINDERGARTEN
AMERICA'S KINDERGARTEN TEACHERS
COMBINED
COMBINED AND
AMERICA'S KINDERGARTEN TEACHERS
COMBINED AND OFTEN
COMBINED AND OFTEN PAYING
COMBINED AND OFTEN PAYING A
LOWER
LOWER TAX
LOWER TAX RATE.
YOU
YOU HAVE
YOU HAVE TO
YOU HAVE TO WONDER.
WHEN
WHEN DOES
WHEN DOES MY
WHEN DOES MY HEART
WHEN DOES MY HEART WORK
WHEN DOES MY HEART WORK PAY
WHEN DOES MY HEART WORK PAY OFF?
WHEN
WHEN DOES
WHEN DOES MY HEART WORK PAY OFF?
WHEN DOES MY
WHEN DOES MY FAMILY
WHEN DOES MY FAMILY GET
WHEN DOES MY FAMILY GET AHEAD.
I
SAY
SAY NOW.
[CHEERING]
PROSPERITY
PROSPERITY CANNOT
PROSPERITY CANNOT JUST
PROSPERITY CANNOT JUST BEFORE
CEO'S
CEO'S AND
CEO'S AND HEDGE
CEO'S AND HEDGE FUND
CEO'S AND HEDGE FUND MANAGERS.
DEMOCRACY
DEMOCRACY CANNOT
CEO'S AND HEDGE FUND MANAGERS.
DEMOCRACY CANNOT JUST
DEMOCRACY CANNOT JUST BEFORE
CEO'S AND HEDGE FUND MANAGERS.
BILLIONAIRES
DEMOCRACY CANNOT JUST BEFORE
BILLIONAIRES AND
BILLIONAIRES AND CORPORATIONS.
DEMOCRACY CANNOT JUST BEFORE
PROSPERITY
BILLIONAIRES AND CORPORATIONS.
PROSPERITY AND
PROSPERITY AND DEMOCRACY
BILLIONAIRES AND CORPORATIONS.
PROSPERITY AND DEMOCRACY ARE
PART
PART OF
PROSPERITY AND DEMOCRACY ARE
PART OF YOUR
PART OF YOUR BASIC
PROSPERITY AND DEMOCRACY ARE
PART OF YOUR BASIC BARGAIN,
PART OF YOUR BASIC BARGAIN, TOO.
PROSPERITY AND DEMOCRACY ARE
YOU
PART OF YOUR BASIC BARGAIN, TOO.
YOU BROUGHT
YOU BROUGHT OUR
PART OF YOUR BASIC BARGAIN, TOO.
YOU BROUGHT OUR COUNTRY
YOU BROUGHT OUR COUNTRY BACK
YOU BROUGHT OUR COUNTRY BACK AND
NOW
NOW IT
YOU BROUGHT OUR COUNTRY BACK AND
NOW IT IS
NOW IT IS TIME,
NOW IT IS TIME, YOUR
NOW IT IS TIME, YOUR TIME,
NOW IT IS TIME, YOUR TIME, TO
SECURE
SECURE THE
NOW IT IS TIME, YOUR TIME, TO
SECURE THE GAINS
SECURE THE GAINS AND
NOW IT IS TIME, YOUR TIME, TO
SECURE THE GAINS AND MOVE
SECURE THE GAINS AND MOVE AHEAD.
NOW IT IS TIME, YOUR TIME, TO
YOU
SECURE THE GAINS AND MOVE AHEAD.
YOU KNOW
YOU KNOW WHAT?
SECURE THE GAINS AND MOVE AHEAD.
AMERICA
YOU KNOW WHAT?
AMERICA CANNOT
AMERICA CANNOT SUCCEED
AMERICA CANNOT SUCCEED UNLESS
YOU
YOU SUCCEED.
THAT
THAT IS
YOU SUCCEED.
THAT IS WHY
THAT IS WHY I
THAT IS WHY I AM
THAT IS WHY I AM RUNNING
THAT IS WHY I AM RUNNING FOR
PRESIDENT
PRESIDENT OF
THAT IS WHY I AM RUNNING FOR
PRESIDENT OF THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
[CHEERING]
HERE
HERE ON
ROOSEVELT
ROOSEVELT ISLAND,
ROOSEVELT ISLAND, I
ROOSEVELT ISLAND, I BELIEVE
ROOSEVELT ISLAND, I BELIEVE WE
HAVE
HAVE A
ROOSEVELT ISLAND, I BELIEVE WE
HAVE A CONTINUING
HAVE A CONTINUING RENDEZVOUS
WITH
WITH DESTINY,
HAVE A CONTINUING RENDEZVOUS
WITH DESTINY, EACH
WITH DESTINY, EACH AMERICAN
WITH DESTINY, EACH AMERICAN AND
THE
THE COUNTRY
WITH DESTINY, EACH AMERICAN AND
THE COUNTRY WE
THE COUNTRY WE CHERISH
THE COUNTRY WE CHERISH OUR
RUNNING
RUNNING TO
THE COUNTRY WE CHERISH OUR
RUNNING TO MAKE
RUNNING TO MAKE OUR
THE COUNTRY WE CHERISH OUR
RUNNING TO MAKE OUR ECONOMY
RUNNING TO MAKE OUR ECONOMY WORK
FOR
FOR YOU
RUNNING TO MAKE OUR ECONOMY WORK
FOR YOU AND
FOR YOU AND FOR
RUNNING TO MAKE OUR ECONOMY WORK
FOR YOU AND FOR EVERY
FOR YOU AND FOR EVERY AMERICAN.
FOR
FOR THE
FOR YOU AND FOR EVERY AMERICAN.
FOR THE SUCCESSFUL
FOR THE SUCCESSFUL AND
FOR YOU AND FOR EVERY AMERICAN.
FOR THE SUCCESSFUL AND THE
STRUGGLING,
STRUGGLING, FOR
FOR THE SUCCESSFUL AND THE
STRUGGLING, FOR THE
STRUGGLING, FOR THE INNOVATORS
FOR THE SUCCESSFUL AND THE
AND
STRUGGLING, FOR THE INNOVATORS
AND ADVENTURES --
AND ADVENTURES -- INVENTORS,
AND ADVENTURES -- INVENTORS, FOR
THOSE
THOSE BREAKING
AND ADVENTURES -- INVENTORS, FOR
THOSE BREAKING BARRIERS
THOSE BREAKING BARRIERS AND
TECHNOLOGY
TECHNOLOGY AND
THOSE BREAKING BARRIERS AND
TECHNOLOGY AND DISCOVERING
TECHNOLOGY AND DISCOVERING CURES
THOSE BREAKING BARRIERS AND
FOR
TECHNOLOGY AND DISCOVERING CURES
FOR DISEASES,
FOR DISEASES, FOR
TECHNOLOGY AND DISCOVERING CURES
FOR DISEASES, FOR THE
FOR DISEASES, FOR THE FACTORY
TECHNOLOGY AND DISCOVERING CURES
WORKERS
FOR DISEASES, FOR THE FACTORY
WORKERS AND
TECHNOLOGY AND DISCOVERING CURES
FOR DISEASES, FOR THE FACTORY
WORKERS AND FOOD
WORKERS AND FOOD SERVERS
FOR DISEASES, FOR THE FACTORY
WORKERS AND FOOD SERVERS WHO
STAND
FOR DISEASES, FOR THE FACTORY
WORKERS AND FOOD SERVERS WHO
STAND ON
STAND ON THEIR
WORKERS AND FOOD SERVERS WHO
STAND ON THEIR FEET
STAND ON THEIR FEET ALL
STAND ON THEIR FEET ALL DAY.
FOR
THE
THE NURSES
THE NURSES WHO
THE NURSES WHO WORK
THE NURSES WHO WORK THE
THE NURSES WHO WORK THE NIGHT
SHIFT.
FOR
FOR THE
SHIFT.
FOR THE TRUCKERS
FOR THE TRUCKERS WHO
FOR THE TRUCKERS WHO DRIVE
FOR THE TRUCKERS WHO DRIVE FOR
HOURS
HOURS AND
FOR THE TRUCKERS WHO DRIVE FOR
HOURS AND THE
HOURS AND THE FARMERS
FOR THE TRUCKERS WHO DRIVE FOR
HOURS AND THE FARMERS WHO
HOURS AND THE FARMERS WHO FEED
US.
FOR
FOR THE
FOR THE VETERANS
FOR THE VETERANS WHO
FOR THE VETERANS WHO SERVED
FOR THE VETERANS WHO SERVED OUR
COUNTRY.
FOR
FOR THE
FOR THE SMALL
FOR THE SMALL BUSINESS
FOR THE SMALL BUSINESS OWNERS
WHO
WHO TOOK
FOR THE SMALL BUSINESS OWNERS
WHO TOOK A
WHO TOOK A RISK,
WHO TOOK A RISK, FOR
WHO TOOK A RISK, FOR EVERYONE
WHO
WHO HAS
WHO TOOK A RISK, FOR EVERYONE
WHO HAS EVER
WHO HAS EVER BEEN
WHO HAS EVER BEEN KNOCKED
WHO HAS EVER BEEN KNOCKED DOWN,
BUT
BUT REFUSED
WHO HAS EVER BEEN KNOCKED DOWN,
BUT REFUSED TO
BUT REFUSED TO BE
BUT REFUSED TO BE KNOCKED
BUT REFUSED TO BE KNOCKED OUT.
I
I AM
I AM NOT
I AM NOT RUNNING
I AM NOT RUNNING FOR
I AM NOT RUNNING FOR SOME
AMERICANS.
I
I AM
AMERICANS.
I AM RUNNING
I AM RUNNING FOR
AMERICANS.
I AM RUNNING FOR ALL
I AM RUNNING FOR ALL AMERICANS.
OUR
COUNTRY'S
COUNTRY'S CHALLENGES
COUNTRY'S CHALLENGES DID
COUNTRY'S CHALLENGES DID NOT
BEGIN
BEGIN WITH
COUNTRY'S CHALLENGES DID NOT
BEGIN WITH THE
BEGIN WITH THE GREAT
COUNTRY'S CHALLENGES DID NOT
BEGIN WITH THE GREAT RECESSION
AND
AND THEY
BEGIN WITH THE GREAT RECESSION
AND THEY WILL
AND THEY WILL NOT
AND THEY WILL NOT END
AND THEY WILL NOT END WITH
AND THEY WILL NOT END WITH THE
RECOVERY.
AMERICANS
AND THEY WILL NOT END WITH THE
RECOVERY.
AMERICANS HAVE
AND THEY WILL NOT END WITH THE
RECOVERY.
AMERICANS HAVE BEEN
AMERICANS HAVE BEEN BUFFETED
RECOVERY.
AMERICANS HAVE BEEN BUFFETED BY
POWERFUL
POWERFUL CURRENTS,
POWERFUL CURRENTS, ADVANCES
POWERFUL CURRENTS, ADVANCES IN
TECHNOLOGY
TECHNOLOGY AND
POWERFUL CURRENTS, ADVANCES IN
TECHNOLOGY AND THE
TECHNOLOGY AND THE RISE
POWERFUL CURRENTS, ADVANCES IN
TECHNOLOGY AND THE RISE OF
GLOBAL
GLOBAL TRADE
TECHNOLOGY AND THE RISE OF
GLOBAL TRADE HAVE
GLOBAL TRADE HAVE CREATED
TECHNOLOGY AND THE RISE OF
GLOBAL TRADE HAVE CREATED WHOLE
NEW
TECHNOLOGY AND THE RISE OF
GLOBAL TRADE HAVE CREATED WHOLE
NEW AREAS
TECHNOLOGY AND THE RISE OF
GLOBAL TRADE HAVE CREATED WHOLE
NEW AREAS OF
NEW AREAS OF ECONOMIC
GLOBAL TRADE HAVE CREATED WHOLE
NEW AREAS OF ECONOMIC ACTIVITY
AND
AND OPENS
NEW AREAS OF ECONOMIC ACTIVITY
AND OPENS NEW
AND OPENS NEW MARKETS
NEW AREAS OF ECONOMIC ACTIVITY
AND OPENS NEW MARKETS FOR
EXPORTS,
EXPORTS, BUT
AND OPENS NEW MARKETS FOR
EXPORTS, BUT THEY
EXPORTS, BUT THEY HAVE
AND OPENS NEW MARKETS FOR
EXPORTS, BUT THEY HAVE ALSO
DISPLACED
DISPLACED JOBS
EXPORTS, BUT THEY HAVE ALSO
DISPLACED JOBS AND
DISPLACED JOBS AND UNDERCUT
EXPORTS, BUT THEY HAVE ALSO
WAGES
DISPLACED JOBS AND UNDERCUT
WAGES FOR
WAGES FOR MILLIONS
DISPLACED JOBS AND UNDERCUT
WAGES FOR MILLIONS OF
WAGES FOR MILLIONS OF AMERICANS.
DISPLACED JOBS AND UNDERCUT
THE
WAGES FOR MILLIONS OF AMERICANS.
THE FINANCIAL
THE FINANCIAL INDUSTRY
THE FINANCIAL INDUSTRY AND
THE FINANCIAL INDUSTRY AND MANY
MULTINATIONAL
MULTINATIONAL CORPORATIONS
THE FINANCIAL INDUSTRY AND MANY
MULTINATIONAL CORPORATIONS HAVE
CREATED
CREATED HUGE
MULTINATIONAL CORPORATIONS HAVE
CREATED HUGE WEALTH
CREATED HUGE WEALTH FOR
MULTINATIONAL CORPORATIONS HAVE
CREATED HUGE WEALTH FOR A
CREATED HUGE WEALTH FOR A FEW
MULTINATIONAL CORPORATIONS HAVE
CREATED HUGE WEALTH FOR A FEW BY
FOCUSING
FOCUSING TOO
CREATED HUGE WEALTH FOR A FEW BY
FOCUSING TOO MUCH
FOCUSING TOO MUCH ON
CREATED HUGE WEALTH FOR A FEW BY
FOCUSING TOO MUCH ON SHORT-TERM
PROFIT
PROFIT AND
FOCUSING TOO MUCH ON SHORT-TERM
PROFIT AND TOO
PROFIT AND TOO LITTLE
FOCUSING TOO MUCH ON SHORT-TERM
PROFIT AND TOO LITTLE ON
LONG-TERM
LONG-TERM VALUES.
PROFIT AND TOO LITTLE ON
TOO
LONG-TERM VALUES.
TOO MUCH
TOO MUCH ON
LONG-TERM VALUES.
TOO MUCH ON COMPLEX
TOO MUCH ON COMPLEX TRADING
SCHEMES
SCHEMES AND
TOO MUCH ON COMPLEX TRADING
SCHEMES AND STOCK
SCHEMES AND STOCK BUYBACKS,
SCHEMES AND STOCK BUYBACKS, TOO
LITTLE
LITTLE ON
SCHEMES AND STOCK BUYBACKS, TOO
LITTLE ON INVESTMENTS
LITTLE ON INVESTMENTS IN
LITTLE ON INVESTMENTS IN NEW
BUSINESSES,
BUSINESSES, JOBS,
LITTLE ON INVESTMENTS IN NEW
BUSINESSES, JOBS, AND
BUSINESSES, JOBS, AND FAIR
LITTLE ON INVESTMENTS IN NEW
COMPENSATION.
BUSINESSES, JOBS, AND FAIR
[CHEERING]
COMPENSATION.
[CHEERING] OUR
[CHEERING] OUR POLITICAL
[CHEERING] OUR POLITICAL SYSTEM
IS
IS SO
[CHEERING] OUR POLITICAL SYSTEM
IS SO PARALYZED
IS SO PARALYZED BY
IS SO PARALYZED BY GRIDLOCK
IS SO PARALYZED BY GRIDLOCK AND
DYSFUNCTION
DYSFUNCTION THAT
IS SO PARALYZED BY GRIDLOCK AND
DYSFUNCTION THAT MOST
DYSFUNCTION THAT MOST AMERICANS
HAVE
HAVE LOST
DYSFUNCTION THAT MOST AMERICANS
HAVE LOST CONFIDENCE
HAVE LOST CONFIDENCE THAT
DYSFUNCTION THAT MOST AMERICANS
ANYTHING
HAVE LOST CONFIDENCE THAT
ANYTHING CAN
ANYTHING CAN ACTUALLY
HAVE LOST CONFIDENCE THAT
ANYTHING CAN ACTUALLY GET
ANYTHING CAN ACTUALLY GET DONE.
THEY
THEY HAVE
ANYTHING CAN ACTUALLY GET DONE.
THEY HAVE LOST
THEY HAVE LOST TRUST
ANYTHING CAN ACTUALLY GET DONE.
THEY HAVE LOST TRUST IN
THEY HAVE LOST TRUST IN THE
ANYTHING CAN ACTUALLY GET DONE.
ABILITY
THEY HAVE LOST TRUST IN THE
ABILITY OF
ABILITY OF BOTH
THEY HAVE LOST TRUST IN THE
ABILITY OF BOTH GOVERNMENT
ABILITY OF BOTH GOVERNMENT AND
THEY HAVE LOST TRUST IN THE
BIG
ABILITY OF BOTH GOVERNMENT AND
BIG BUSINESS
BIG BUSINESS TO
ABILITY OF BOTH GOVERNMENT AND
BIG BUSINESS TO CHANGE
BIG BUSINESS TO CHANGE COURSE.
ABILITY OF BOTH GOVERNMENT AND
WE
BIG BUSINESS TO CHANGE COURSE.
WE CAN
WE CAN BLAME
BIG BUSINESS TO CHANGE COURSE.
WE CAN BLAME HISTORIC
WE CAN BLAME HISTORIC FORCES
BEYOND
BEYOND OUR
WE CAN BLAME HISTORIC FORCES
BEYOND OUR CONTROL
BEYOND OUR CONTROL FOR
WE CAN BLAME HISTORIC FORCES
BEYOND OUR CONTROL FOR SOME
BEYOND OUR CONTROL FOR SOME OF
WE CAN BLAME HISTORIC FORCES
THIS,
BEYOND OUR CONTROL FOR SOME OF
THIS, BUT
THIS, BUT THE
THIS, BUT THE CHOICES
THIS, BUT THE CHOICES WE
THIS, BUT THE CHOICES WE HAVE
MADE
MADE AS
THIS, BUT THE CHOICES WE HAVE
MADE AS A
MADE AS A NATION,
THIS, BUT THE CHOICES WE HAVE
MADE AS A NATION, LEADERS
MADE AS A NATION, LEADERS AND
CITIZENS
CITIZENS ALIKE,
MADE AS A NATION, LEADERS AND
CITIZENS ALIKE, HAVE
CITIZENS ALIKE, HAVE ALSO
MADE AS A NATION, LEADERS AND
CITIZENS ALIKE, HAVE ALSO PLAYED
A
A BIG
CITIZENS ALIKE, HAVE ALSO PLAYED
A BIG ROLE.
OUR
OUR NEXT
A BIG ROLE.
OUR NEXT PRESIDENT
OUR NEXT PRESIDENT MUST
A BIG ROLE.
OUR NEXT PRESIDENT MUST WORK
WITH
WITH CONGRESS
OUR NEXT PRESIDENT MUST WORK
WITH CONGRESS AND
WITH CONGRESS AND EVERY
WITH CONGRESS AND EVERY OTHER
WILLING
WILLING PARTNER
WITH CONGRESS AND EVERY OTHER
WILLING PARTNER ACROSS
WILLING PARTNER ACROSS THE
WITH CONGRESS AND EVERY OTHER
ENTIRE
WILLING PARTNER ACROSS THE
ENTIRE COUNTRY --
ENTIRE COUNTRY -- AND
WILLING PARTNER ACROSS THE
ENTIRE COUNTRY -- AND I
ENTIRE COUNTRY -- AND I WILL
WILLING PARTNER ACROSS THE
ENTIRE COUNTRY -- AND I WILL DO
JUST
WILLING PARTNER ACROSS THE
ENTIRE COUNTRY -- AND I WILL DO
JUST THAT.
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] TO
[CHEERING] TO TURN
[CHEERING] TO TURN THE
[CHEERING] TO TURN THE TIDE
[CHEERING] TO TURN THE TIDE SO
THESE
THESE CURRENTS
[CHEERING] TO TURN THE TIDE SO
THESE CURRENTS START
THESE CURRENTS START WORKING
THESE CURRENTS START WORKING FOR
US
US MORE
THESE CURRENTS START WORKING FOR
US MORE THAN
US MORE THAN AGAINST
THESE CURRENTS START WORKING FOR
US MORE THAN AGAINST US.
AT
AT HER
US MORE THAN AGAINST US.
AT HER BEST,
AT HER BEST, THAT
US MORE THAN AGAINST US.
AT HER BEST, THAT IS
AT HER BEST, THAT IS WHAT
AMERICANS
AMERICANS DO.
AT HER BEST, THAT IS WHAT
WE
AMERICANS DO.
WE ARE
WE ARE PROBLEM
AMERICANS DO.
WE ARE PROBLEM SOLVERS,
WE ARE PROBLEM SOLVERS, NOT
DENIERS.
WE
WE ARE PROBLEM SOLVERS, NOT
DENIERS.
WE DO
WE ARE PROBLEM SOLVERS, NOT
DENIERS.
WE DO NOT
WE ARE PROBLEM SOLVERS, NOT
DENIERS.
WE DO NOT HIDE
WE DO NOT HIDE FROM
DENIERS.
WE DO NOT HIDE FROM CHANGE,
WE DO NOT HIDE FROM CHANGE, WE
HARNESS
HARNESS IT.
WE DO NOT HIDE FROM CHANGE, WE
WE
HARNESS IT.
WE CANNOT
WE CANNOT DO
HARNESS IT.
WE CANNOT DO THAT
WE CANNOT DO THAT IF
HARNESS IT.
WE CANNOT DO THAT IF WE
WE CANNOT DO THAT IF WE GO
WE CANNOT DO THAT IF WE GO BACK
TO
TO THE
WE CANNOT DO THAT IF WE GO BACK
TO THE TOP
TO THE TOP DOWN
WE CANNOT DO THAT IF WE GO BACK
TO THE TOP DOWN ECONOMIC
POLICIES
POLICIES THAT
TO THE TOP DOWN ECONOMIC
POLICIES THAT FAILED
POLICIES THAT FAILED US
POLICIES THAT FAILED US BEFORE.
AMERICANS
AMERICANS HAVE
POLICIES THAT FAILED US BEFORE.
AMERICANS HAVE COME
AMERICANS HAVE COME TOO
AMERICANS HAVE COME TOO FAR
AMERICANS HAVE COME TOO FAR TO
SEE
SEE OUR
AMERICANS HAVE COME TOO FAR TO
SEE OUR PROGRESS
SEE OUR PROGRESS RIPPED
AMERICANS HAVE COME TOO FAR TO
SEE OUR PROGRESS RIPPED AWAY.
THERE
THERE MAY
SEE OUR PROGRESS RIPPED AWAY.
THERE MAY BE
THERE MAY BE SOME
THERE MAY BE SOME NEW
THERE MAY BE SOME NEW VOICES
THERE MAY BE SOME NEW VOICES IN
THE
THE PRESIDENTIAL
THE PRESIDENTIAL REPUBLICAN
CHOIR.
[LAUGHTER]
[LAUGHTER] BUT
CHOIR.
[LAUGHTER] BUT THEY
[LAUGHTER] BUT THEY ARE
CHOIR.
[LAUGHTER] BUT THEY ARE ALL
SINGING
SINGING THE
[LAUGHTER] BUT THEY ARE ALL
SINGING THE SAME
SINGING THE SAME OLD
SINGING THE SAME OLD SONG,
SINGING THE SAME OLD SONG, A
SONG
SONG CALLED
SINGING THE SAME OLD SONG, A
SONG CALLED YESTERDAY.
YOU
YOU KNOW
YOU KNOW THE
YOU KNOW THE ONE,
YOU KNOW THE ONE, ALL
YOU KNOW THE ONE, ALL OUR
TROUBLES
TROUBLES LOOK
YOU KNOW THE ONE, ALL OUR
TROUBLES LOOK AS
TROUBLES LOOK AS THOUGH
TROUBLES LOOK AS THOUGH THEY
TROUBLES LOOK AS THOUGH THEY ARE
HERE
HERE TO
TROUBLES LOOK AS THOUGH THEY ARE
HERE TO STAY
HERE TO STAY AND
TROUBLES LOOK AS THOUGH THEY ARE
HERE TO STAY AND WE
HERE TO STAY AND WE NEED
HERE TO STAY AND WE NEED A
HERE TO STAY AND WE NEED A PLACE
TO
TO HIDE
HERE TO STAY AND WE NEED A PLACE
TO HIDE AWAY.
THEY
THEY BELIEVE
THEY BELIEVE IN
THEY BELIEVE IN YESTERDAY.
YOU
YOU ARE
YOU ARE LUCKY
YOU ARE LUCKY I
YOU ARE LUCKY I DID
YOU ARE LUCKY I DID NOT
YOU ARE LUCKY I DID NOT TRY
SINGING
SINGING THAT,
YOU ARE LUCKY I DID NOT TRY
SINGING THAT, TOO.
REPUBLICANS
REPUBLICANS TRIP
SINGING THAT, TOO.
REPUBLICANS TRIP OVER
REPUBLICANS TRIP OVER THEMSELVES
PROMISING
PROMISING LOWER
REPUBLICANS TRIP OVER THEMSELVES
PROMISING LOWER TAXES
PROMISING LOWER TAXES FOR
REPUBLICANS TRIP OVER THEMSELVES
PROMISING LOWER TAXES FOR THE
WEALTHY
WEALTHY AND
PROMISING LOWER TAXES FOR THE
WEALTHY AND FEWER
WEALTHY AND FEWER RULES
PROMISING LOWER TAXES FOR THE
WEALTHY AND FEWER RULES FOR
WEALTHY AND FEWER RULES FOR THE
PROMISING LOWER TAXES FOR THE
BIGGEST
WEALTHY AND FEWER RULES FOR THE
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS WITHOUT
WEALTHY AND FEWER RULES FOR THE
REGARD
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS WITHOUT
REGARD FOR
REGARD FOR HOW
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS WITHOUT
REGARD FOR HOW THAT
REGARD FOR HOW THAT WILL
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS WITHOUT
REGARD FOR HOW THAT WILL MAKE
INCOME
INCOME INEQUALITY
REGARD FOR HOW THAT WILL MAKE
INCOME INEQUALITY EVEN
INCOME INEQUALITY EVEN WORSE.
REGARD FOR HOW THAT WILL MAKE
WE
INCOME INEQUALITY EVEN WORSE.
WE HAVE
WE HAVE HEARD
INCOME INEQUALITY EVEN WORSE.
WE HAVE HEARD THIS
WE HAVE HEARD THIS TUNE
WE HAVE HEARD THIS TUNE BEFORE
AND
AND WE
WE HAVE HEARD THIS TUNE BEFORE
AND WE KNOW
AND WE KNOW HOW
WE HAVE HEARD THIS TUNE BEFORE
AND WE KNOW HOW IT
AND WE KNOW HOW IT TURNS
WE HAVE HEARD THIS TUNE BEFORE
AND WE KNOW HOW IT TURNS OUT.
AS
AS MANY
AND WE KNOW HOW IT TURNS OUT.
AS MANY OF
AS MANY OF THESE
AS MANY OF THESE CANDIDATES --
ASK
ASK MANY
AS MANY OF THESE CANDIDATES --
ASK MANY OF
ASK MANY OF THESE
AS MANY OF THESE CANDIDATES --
ASK MANY OF THESE CANDIDATES
ABOUT
ABOUT CLIMATE
ASK MANY OF THESE CANDIDATES
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE,
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE, ONE
ASK MANY OF THESE CANDIDATES
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE, ONE OF
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE, ONE OF THE
ASK MANY OF THESE CANDIDATES
DEFINING
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE, ONE OF THE
DEFINING THREATS
DEFINING THREATS OF
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE, ONE OF THE
DEFINING THREATS OF OUR
DEFINING THREATS OF OUR TIME,
AND
AND THEY
DEFINING THREATS OF OUR TIME,
AND THEY WILL
AND THEY WILL SAY,
DEFINING THREATS OF OUR TIME,
AND THEY WILL SAY, I
AND THEY WILL SAY, I AM
AND THEY WILL SAY, I AM NOT
AND THEY WILL SAY, I AM NOT A
SCIENTIST.
[LAUGHTER]
[LAUGHTER] WELL,
SCIENTIST.
[LAUGHTER] WELL, WHY
[LAUGHTER] WELL, WHY DON'T
[LAUGHTER] WELL, WHY DON'T THEY
START
START LISTENING
[LAUGHTER] WELL, WHY DON'T THEY
START LISTENING TO
START LISTENING TO THOSE
[LAUGHTER] WELL, WHY DON'T THEY
START LISTENING TO THOSE WHO
ARE?
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] THEY
[CHEERING] THEY PLEDGE
[CHEERING] THEY PLEDGE TO
[CHEERING] THEY PLEDGE TO WIPE
OUT
OUT RULES
[CHEERING] THEY PLEDGE TO WIPE
OUT RULES ON
OUT RULES ON WALL
[CHEERING] THEY PLEDGE TO WIPE
OUT RULES ON WALL STREET
OUT RULES ON WALL STREET RATHER
THAN
THAN RAIN
OUT RULES ON WALL STREET RATHER
THAN RAIN IN
THAN RAIN IN THE
OUT RULES ON WALL STREET RATHER
THAN RAIN IN THE BANKS
THAN RAIN IN THE BANKS THAT
OUT RULES ON WALL STREET RATHER
THAN RAIN IN THE BANKS THAT ARE
STILL
STILL TOO
STILL TOO RISKY,
STILL TOO RISKY, ACCORDING
FUTURE
FUTURE FAILURES
FUTURE FAILURES IN
FUTURE FAILURES IN A
FUTURE FAILURES IN A CASE
FUTURE FAILURES IN A CASE THAT
CAN
CAN ONLY
FUTURE FAILURES IN A CASE THAT
CAN ONLY BE
CAN ONLY BE CONSIDERED
CAN ONLY BE CONSIDERED MASS
AMNESIA.
THEY
THEY WANT
AMNESIA.
THEY WANT TO
THEY WANT TO TAKE
AMNESIA.
THEY WANT TO TAKE AWAY
THEY WANT TO TAKE AWAY HEALTH
AMNESIA.
INSURANCE
THEY WANT TO TAKE AWAY HEALTH
INSURANCE FOR
INSURANCE FOR MORE
THEY WANT TO TAKE AWAY HEALTH
INSURANCE FOR MORE THAN
INSURANCE FOR MORE THAN 16
MILLION
MILLION AMERICANS
MILLION AMERICANS WITHOUT
CREDIBLE
CREDIBLE ALTERNATIVES.
THEY
THEY SHAME
CREDIBLE ALTERNATIVES.
THEY SHAME AND
THEY SHAME AND BLAME
CREDIBLE ALTERNATIVES.
THEY SHAME AND BLAME WOMEN
RATHER
RATHER THAN
THEY SHAME AND BLAME WOMEN
RATHER THAN RESPECT
RATHER THAN RESPECT OUR
THEY SHAME AND BLAME WOMEN
RATHER THAN RESPECT OUR RIGHT
RATHER THAN RESPECT OUR RIGHT TO
THEY SHAME AND BLAME WOMEN
MAKE
RATHER THAN RESPECT OUR RIGHT TO
MAKE OUR
MAKE OUR OWN
RATHER THAN RESPECT OUR RIGHT TO
MAKE OUR OWN DECISIONS.
[CHEERING]
THEY
THEY WANT
THEY WANT TO
THEY WANT TO PUT
THEY WANT TO PUT IMMIGRANTS
THEY WANT TO PUT IMMIGRANTS WHO
WORK
WORK HARD
THEY WANT TO PUT IMMIGRANTS WHO
WORK HARD AND
WORK HARD AND PAY
WORK HARD AND PAY TAXES
WORK HARD AND PAY TAXES AT
WORK HARD AND PAY TAXES AT RISK
OF
OF DEPORTATION
OF DEPORTATION AND
OF DEPORTATION AND THEY
OF DEPORTATION AND THEY TURN
THEIR
THEIR BACK
OF DEPORTATION AND THEY TURN
THEIR BACK ON
THEIR BACK ON GAY
THEIR BACK ON GAY PEOPLE
THEIR BACK ON GAY PEOPLE WHO
LOVE
LOVE EACH
THEIR BACK ON GAY PEOPLE WHO
LOVE EACH OTHER.
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] FUNDAMENTALLY,
[CHEERING] FUNDAMENTALLY, THEY
REJECT
REJECT WHAT
[CHEERING] FUNDAMENTALLY, THEY
REJECT WHAT IT
REJECT WHAT IT TAKES
[CHEERING] FUNDAMENTALLY, THEY
REJECT WHAT IT TAKES TO
REJECT WHAT IT TAKES TO BUILD
REJECT WHAT IT TAKES TO BUILD AN
INCLUSIVE
INCLUSIVE ECONOMY.
IT
IT TAKES
INCLUSIVE ECONOMY.
IT TAKES AN
IT TAKES AN INCLUSIVE
IT TAKES AN INCLUSIVE SOCIETY.
WHAT
WHAT I
WHAT I ONCE
WHAT I ONCE CALLED
A
A VILLAGE
A VILLAGE THAT
A VILLAGE THAT HAS
A VILLAGE THAT HAS A
A VILLAGE THAT HAS A PLACE
A VILLAGE THAT HAS A PLACE FOR
EVERYONE.
MY
MY VALUES
MY VALUES HAVE
MY VALUES HAVE GIVEN
MY VALUES HAVE GIVEN ME
MY VALUES HAVE GIVEN ME A
DIFFERENT
DIFFERENT VISION
MY VALUES HAVE GIVEN ME A
DIFFERENT VISION FOR
DIFFERENT VISION FOR AMERICA.
I
I BELIEVE
I BELIEVE THAT
I BELIEVE THAT SUCCESS
I BELIEVE THAT SUCCESS IS
I BELIEVE THAT SUCCESS IS NOT
MEASURED
MEASURED BY
MEASURED BY HOW
MEASURED BY HOW MUCH
MEASURED BY HOW MUCH THE
WEALTHIEST
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS
MEASURED BY HOW MUCH THE
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS HAVE,
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS HAVE, BUT
HOW
HOW MANY
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS HAVE, BUT
HOW MANY CHILDREN
HOW MANY CHILDREN CLIMB
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS HAVE, BUT
HOW MANY CHILDREN CLIMB OUT
HOW MANY CHILDREN CLIMB OUT OF
POVERTY.
HOW
HOW MANY
HOW MANY STARTUPS
HOW MANY STARTUPS AND
HOW MANY STARTUPS AND SMALL
BUSINESSES
BUSINESSES OPEN
BUSINESSES OPEN AND
BUSINESSES OPEN AND THRIVE,
BUSINESSES OPEN AND THRIVE, HOW
MANY
MANY YOUNG
BUSINESSES OPEN AND THRIVE, HOW
MANY YOUNG PEOPLE
MANY YOUNG PEOPLE GO
MANY YOUNG PEOPLE GO TO
MANY YOUNG PEOPLE GO TO COLLEGE
WITHOUT
WITHOUT DROWNING
MANY YOUNG PEOPLE GO TO COLLEGE
WITHOUT DROWNING IN
WITHOUT DROWNING IN DEBT.
HOW
HOW MANY
HOW MANY PEOPLE
HOW MANY PEOPLE FIND
HOW MANY PEOPLE FIND A
HOW MANY PEOPLE FIND A GOOD
HOW MANY PEOPLE FIND A GOOD JOB,
HOW
HOW MANY
HOW MANY PEOPLE FIND A GOOD JOB,
HOW MANY FAMILIES
HOW MANY FAMILIES GET
HOW MANY PEOPLE FIND A GOOD JOB,
HOW MANY FAMILIES GET AHEAD
HOW MANY FAMILIES GET AHEAD AND
STAY
STAY AHEAD.
I
I DID
STAY AHEAD.
I DID NOT
I DID NOT LEARN
STAY AHEAD.
I DID NOT LEARN THIS
I DID NOT LEARN THIS FROM
STAY AHEAD.
POLITICS.
I DID NOT LEARN THIS FROM
I
POLITICS.
I LEARNED
I DID NOT LEARN THIS FROM
POLITICS.
I LEARNED IT
I DID NOT LEARN THIS FROM
POLITICS.
I LEARNED IT FROM
I DID NOT LEARN THIS FROM
POLITICS.
I LEARNED IT FROM MY
I LEARNED IT FROM MY OWN
I LEARNED IT FROM MY OWN FAMILY.
MY
MY MOTHER
I LEARNED IT FROM MY OWN FAMILY.
MY MOTHER TAUGHT
MY MOTHER TAUGHT ME
I LEARNED IT FROM MY OWN FAMILY.
MY MOTHER TAUGHT ME THAT
EVERYBODY
EVERYBODY NEEDS
MY MOTHER TAUGHT ME THAT
EVERYBODY NEEDS A
EVERYBODY NEEDS A CHANCE
MY MOTHER TAUGHT ME THAT
EVERYBODY NEEDS A CHANCE AND
CHAMPION.
SHE
SHE KNEW
CHAMPION.
SHE KNEW WHAT
SHE KNEW WHAT IT
CHAMPION.
SHE KNEW WHAT IT WAS
SHE KNEW WHAT IT WAS LIKE
SHE KNEW WHAT IT WAS LIKE NOT
SHE KNEW WHAT IT WAS LIKE NOT TO
HAVE
HAVE EITHER
SHE KNEW WHAT IT WAS LIKE NOT TO
HAVE EITHER ONE.
HER
HER OWN
HAVE EITHER ONE.
HER OWN PARENTS
HER OWN PARENTS ABANDONED
HER OWN PARENTS ABANDONED HER
AND
AND BY
HER OWN PARENTS ABANDONED HER
AND BY 14,
AND BY 14, SHE
HER OWN PARENTS ABANDONED HER
AND BY 14, SHE WAS
AND BY 14, SHE WAS OUT
HER OWN PARENTS ABANDONED HER
AND BY 14, SHE WAS OUT ON
AND BY 14, SHE WAS OUT ON HER
HER OWN PARENTS ABANDONED HER
OWN
AND BY 14, SHE WAS OUT ON HER
OWN WORKING
OWN WORKING AS
AND BY 14, SHE WAS OUT ON HER
OWN WORKING AS A
OWN WORKING AS A HOUSEMAID.
YEARS
YEARS LATER,
OWN WORKING AS A HOUSEMAID.
YEARS LATER, WHEN
YEARS LATER, WHEN I
OWN WORKING AS A HOUSEMAID.
YEARS LATER, WHEN I WAS
YEARS LATER, WHEN I WAS OLD
OWN WORKING AS A HOUSEMAID.
ENOUGH
YEARS LATER, WHEN I WAS OLD
ENOUGH TO
ENOUGH TO UNDERSTAND,
YEARS LATER, WHEN I WAS OLD
ENOUGH TO UNDERSTAND, I
ENOUGH TO UNDERSTAND, I ASKED
WHAT
WHAT KEPT
ENOUGH TO UNDERSTAND, I ASKED
WHAT KEPT HER
WHAT KEPT HER GOING.
HER
HER ANSWER
WHAT KEPT HER GOING.
HER ANSWER WAS
HER ANSWER WAS SOMETHING
WHAT KEPT HER GOING.
HER ANSWER WAS SOMETHING VERY
SIMPLE --
SIMPLE -- KINDNESS
HER ANSWER WAS SOMETHING VERY
SIMPLE -- KINDNESS FROM
SIMPLE -- KINDNESS FROM SOMEONE
HER ANSWER WAS SOMETHING VERY
WHO
SIMPLE -- KINDNESS FROM SOMEONE
WHO BELIEVED
WHO BELIEVED SHE
SIMPLE -- KINDNESS FROM SOMEONE
WHO BELIEVED SHE MATTERED.
THE
THE FIRST
WHO BELIEVED SHE MATTERED.
THE FIRST GRADE
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER
WHO BELIEVED SHE MATTERED.
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER WHO
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER WHO SAW
SHE
SHE HAD
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER WHO SAW
SHE HAD NOTHING
SHE HAD NOTHING TO
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER WHO SAW
SHE HAD NOTHING TO EAT
SHE HAD NOTHING TO EAT AT
SHE HAD NOTHING TO EAT AT LUNCH
AND
AND WITHOUT
SHE HAD NOTHING TO EAT AT LUNCH
AND WITHOUT EMBARRASSING
AND WITHOUT EMBARRASSING HER
SHE HAD NOTHING TO EAT AT LUNCH
BROUGHT
AND WITHOUT EMBARRASSING HER
BROUGHT EXTRA
BROUGHT EXTRA FOOD
AND WITHOUT EMBARRASSING HER
BROUGHT EXTRA FOOD TO
BROUGHT EXTRA FOOD TO SHARE.
AND WITHOUT EMBARRASSING HER
THE
BROUGHT EXTRA FOOD TO SHARE.
THE WOMAN
THE WOMAN WHOSE
BROUGHT EXTRA FOOD TO SHARE.
THE WOMAN WHOSE HOUSE
THE WOMAN WHOSE HOUSE SHE
CLEANED
CLEANED LETTING
THE WOMAN WHOSE HOUSE SHE
CLEANED LETTING HER
CLEANED LETTING HER GO
THE WOMAN WHOSE HOUSE SHE
CLEANED LETTING HER GO TO
CLEANED LETTING HER GO TO HIGH
THE WOMAN WHOSE HOUSE SHE
SCHOOL
CLEANED LETTING HER GO TO HIGH
SCHOOL SO
SCHOOL SO LONG
CLEANED LETTING HER GO TO HIGH
SCHOOL SO LONG AS
SCHOOL SO LONG AS HER
CLEANED LETTING HER GO TO HIGH
SCHOOL SO LONG AS HER WORK
SCHOOL SO LONG AS HER WORK GOT
DONE.
THAT
SCHOOL SO LONG AS HER WORK GOT
DONE.
THAT WAS
SCHOOL SO LONG AS HER WORK GOT
DONE.
THAT WAS A
THAT WAS A BARGAIN
THAT WAS A BARGAIN SHE
THAT WAS A BARGAIN SHE LESPT
THAT WAS A BARGAIN SHE LESPT TO
ACCEPT.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE SOME
ACCEPT.
BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE
BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE BELIEVED
BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE BELIEVED IN
HER,
HER, SHE
BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE BELIEVED IN
HER, SHE BELIEVED
HER, SHE BELIEVED IN
BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE BELIEVED IN
HER, SHE BELIEVED IN ME.
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] I
[CHEERING] I BELIEVE
[CHEERING] I BELIEVE WITH
[CHEERING] I BELIEVE WITH ALL
[CHEERING] I BELIEVE WITH ALL MY
HEART
HEART IN
[CHEERING] I BELIEVE WITH ALL MY
HEART IN AMERICA
HEART IN AMERICA AND
HEART IN AMERICA AND IN
HEART IN AMERICA AND IN THE
POTENTIAL
POTENTIAL OF
HEART IN AMERICA AND IN THE
POTENTIAL OF EVERY
POTENTIAL OF EVERY AMERICAN.
TO
TO MEET
POTENTIAL OF EVERY AMERICAN.
TO MEET EVERY
TO MEET EVERY CHALLENGE,
POTENTIAL OF EVERY AMERICAN.
TO MEET EVERY CHALLENGE, TO
TO MEET EVERY CHALLENGE, TO BE
RESILIENT
RESILIENT NO
TO MEET EVERY CHALLENGE, TO BE
RESILIENT NO MATTER
RESILIENT NO MATTER WHAT
TO MEET EVERY CHALLENGE, TO BE
RESILIENT NO MATTER WHAT THE
WORLD
WORLD THROWS
RESILIENT NO MATTER WHAT THE
WORLD THROWS AT
WORLD THROWS AT YOU,
WORLD THROWS AT YOU, TO
WORLD THROWS AT YOU, TO SOLVE
THE
THE TOUGHEST
WORLD THROWS AT YOU, TO SOLVE
THE TOUGHEST PROBLEMS,
THE TOUGHEST PROBLEMS, I
WORLD THROWS AT YOU, TO SOLVE
THE TOUGHEST PROBLEMS, I BELIEVE
WE
WE CAN
THE TOUGHEST PROBLEMS, I BELIEVE
WE CAN DO
WE CAN DO ALL
WE CAN DO ALL THESE
WE CAN DO ALL THESE THINGS
BECAUSE
BECAUSE I
WE CAN DO ALL THESE THINGS
BECAUSE I HAVE
BECAUSE I HAVE SEEN
WE CAN DO ALL THESE THINGS
BECAUSE I HAVE SEEN IT
BECAUSE I HAVE SEEN IT HAPPEN.
WE CAN DO ALL THESE THINGS
AS
BECAUSE I HAVE SEEN IT HAPPEN.
AS A
AS A YOUNG
AS A YOUNG GIRL,
AS A YOUNG GIRL, I
AS A YOUNG GIRL, I SIGNED
AS A YOUNG GIRL, I SIGNED UP
AS A YOUNG GIRL, I SIGNED UP AT
MY
MY METHODIST
AS A YOUNG GIRL, I SIGNED UP AT
MY METHODIST CHURCH
MY METHODIST CHURCH TO
MY METHODIST CHURCH TO BABYSIT
THE
THE CHILDREN
MY METHODIST CHURCH TO BABYSIT
THE CHILDREN OF
THE CHILDREN OF MEXICAN
MY METHODIST CHURCH TO BABYSIT
FARMWORKERS
THE CHILDREN OF MEXICAN
FARMWORKERS WHILE
FARMWORKERS WHILE THEIR
THE CHILDREN OF MEXICAN
FARMWORKERS WHILE THEIR PARENTS
WORKED
THE CHILDREN OF MEXICAN
FARMWORKERS WHILE THEIR PARENTS
WORKED IN
THE CHILDREN OF MEXICAN
FARMWORKERS WHILE THEIR PARENTS
WORKED IN THE
THE CHILDREN OF MEXICAN
FARMWORKERS WHILE THEIR PARENTS
WORKED IN THE FIELDS.
AS
FARMWORKERS WHILE THEIR PARENTS
WORKED IN THE FIELDS.
AS A
FARMWORKERS WHILE THEIR PARENTS
WORKED IN THE FIELDS.
AS A LAW
AS A LAW STUDENT,
WORKED IN THE FIELDS.
AS A LAW STUDENT, I
AS A LAW STUDENT, I ADVOCATED
WORKED IN THE FIELDS.
FOR
AS A LAW STUDENT, I ADVOCATED
FOR CONGRESS
FOR CONGRESS TO
AS A LAW STUDENT, I ADVOCATED
FOR CONGRESS TO REQUIRE
FOR CONGRESS TO REQUIRE THAT
AS A LAW STUDENT, I ADVOCATED
FOR CONGRESS TO REQUIRE THAT ARE
WORKING
WORKING AND
FOR CONGRESS TO REQUIRE THAT ARE
WORKING AND LIVING
WORKING AND LIVING CONDITIONS
FOR CONGRESS TO REQUIRE THAT ARE
FOR
WORKING AND LIVING CONDITIONS
FOR FARMWORKERS
FOR FARMWORKERS WHOSE
WORKING AND LIVING CONDITIONS
FOR FARMWORKERS WHOSE CHILDREN
DESERVED
DESERVED BETTER
FOR FARMWORKERS WHOSE CHILDREN
DESERVED BETTER OPPORTUNITIES.
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] MY
[CHEERING] MY FIRST
[CHEERING] MY FIRST JOB
[CHEERING] MY FIRST JOB OUT
[CHEERING] MY FIRST JOB OUT OF
LAW
LAW SCHOOL
[CHEERING] MY FIRST JOB OUT OF
LAW SCHOOL WAS
LAW SCHOOL WAS FOR
[CHEERING] MY FIRST JOB OUT OF
LAW SCHOOL WAS FOR THE
CHILDREN'S
CHILDREN'S DEFENSE
LAW SCHOOL WAS FOR THE
CHILDREN'S DEFENSE FUND.
I
I WALKED
I WALKED DOOR-TO-DOOR
I WALKED DOOR-TO-DOOR TO
I WALKED DOOR-TO-DOOR TO FIND
OUT
OUT HOW
I WALKED DOOR-TO-DOOR TO FIND
OUT HOW MANY
OUT HOW MANY CHILDREN
I WALKED DOOR-TO-DOOR TO FIND
OUT HOW MANY CHILDREN WITH
DISABILITIES
DISABILITIES COULD
OUT HOW MANY CHILDREN WITH
DISABILITIES COULD NOT
DISABILITIES COULD NOT GO
OUT HOW MANY CHILDREN WITH
DISABILITIES COULD NOT GO TO
SCHOOL
OUT HOW MANY CHILDREN WITH
DISABILITIES COULD NOT GO TO
SCHOOL AND
OUT HOW MANY CHILDREN WITH
DISABILITIES COULD NOT GO TO
SCHOOL AND TO
SCHOOL AND TO HELP
DISABILITIES COULD NOT GO TO
SCHOOL AND TO HELP BUILD
SCHOOL AND TO HELP BUILD THE
DISABILITIES COULD NOT GO TO
CASE
SCHOOL AND TO HELP BUILD THE
CASE FOR
CASE FOR A
SCHOOL AND TO HELP BUILD THE
CASE FOR A LAW
CASE FOR A LAW GUARANTEEING
CASE FOR A LAW GUARANTEEING THEM
ACCESS
ACCESS TO
CASE FOR A LAW GUARANTEEING THEM
ACCESS TO EDUCATION.
AS
AS A
AS A LEADER
AS A LEADER OF
AS A LEADER OF THE
AS A LEADER OF THE LEGAL
SERVICES
SERVICES CORPORATION,
AS A LEADER OF THE LEGAL
SERVICES CORPORATION, I
SERVICES CORPORATION, I DEFENDED
AS A LEADER OF THE LEGAL
THE
SERVICES CORPORATION, I DEFENDED
THE RIGHTS
THE RIGHTS OF
SERVICES CORPORATION, I DEFENDED
THE RIGHTS OF POOR
THE RIGHTS OF POOR PEOPLE
SERVICES CORPORATION, I DEFENDED
THE RIGHTS OF POOR PEOPLE TO
HAVE
HAVE A
THE RIGHTS OF POOR PEOPLE TO
HAVE A LAWYER
HAVE A LAWYER AND
THE RIGHTS OF POOR PEOPLE TO
HAVE A LAWYER AND I
HAVE A LAWYER AND I SAW
HAVE A LAWYER AND I SAW LIVES
CHANGED
CHANGED BECAUSE
HAVE A LAWYER AND I SAW LIVES
CHANGED BECAUSE AN
CHANGED BECAUSE AN ABUSIVE
MARRIAGE
MARRIAGE ENDED
CHANGED BECAUSE AN ABUSIVE
MARRIAGE ENDED OR
MARRIAGE ENDED OR AN
MARRIAGE ENDED OR AN ILLEGAL
EVICTION
EVICTION STOPPED.
IN
IN ARKANSAS,
EVICTION STOPPED.
IN ARKANSAS, I
IN ARKANSAS, I SUPERVISED
EVICTION STOPPED.
IN ARKANSAS, I SUPERVISED LAW
STUDENTS
STUDENTS WHO
IN ARKANSAS, I SUPERVISED LAW
STUDENTS WHO REPRESENTED
STUDENTS WHO REPRESENTED CLIENTS
IN ARKANSAS, I SUPERVISED LAW
IN
STUDENTS WHO REPRESENTED CLIENTS
IN COURTS
IN ARKANSAS, I SUPERVISED LAW
STUDENTS WHO REPRESENTED CLIENTS
IN COURTS AND
IN COURTS AND PRISONS,
STUDENTS WHO REPRESENTED CLIENTS
IN COURTS AND PRISONS, ORGANIZED
SCHOLARSHIPS
SCHOLARSHIPS FOR
IN COURTS AND PRISONS, ORGANIZED
SCHOLARSHIPS FOR SINGLE
SCHOLARSHIPS FOR SINGLE PARENTS
IN COURTS AND PRISONS, ORGANIZED
GOING
SCHOLARSHIPS FOR SINGLE PARENTS
GOING TO
GOING TO COLLEGE,
SCHOLARSHIPS FOR SINGLE PARENTS
GOING TO COLLEGE, LED
GOING TO COLLEGE, LED EFFORTS
SCHOLARSHIPS FOR SINGLE PARENTS
FOR
GOING TO COLLEGE, LED EFFORTS
FOR BETTER
FOR BETTER SCHOOLS
GOING TO COLLEGE, LED EFFORTS
FOR BETTER SCHOOLS AND
FOR BETTER SCHOOLS AND HEALTH
GOING TO COLLEGE, LED EFFORTS
CARE
FOR BETTER SCHOOLS AND HEALTH
CARE AND
CARE AND PERSONALLY
FOR BETTER SCHOOLS AND HEALTH
CARE AND PERSONALLY KNEW
CARE AND PERSONALLY KNEW THE
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WHOSE
CARE AND PERSONALLY KNEW THE
PEOPLE WHOSE LIVES
PEOPLE WHOSE LIVES WERE
IMPROVED.
AS
AS SENATOR,
IMPROVED.
AS SENATOR, I
AS SENATOR, I HAVE
AS SENATOR, I HAVE THE
AS SENATOR, I HAVE THE HONOR
AS SENATOR, I HAVE THE HONOR OF
REPRESENTING
REPRESENTING FIREFIGHTERS,
POLICE
POLICE OFFICERS,
POLICE OFFICERS, EMTS,
CONSTRUCTION
CONSTRUCTION WORKERS,
POLICE OFFICERS, EMTS,
CONSTRUCTION WORKERS, AND
VOLUNTEERS
VOLUNTEERS WHO
CONSTRUCTION WORKERS, AND
VOLUNTEERS WHO RAN
VOLUNTEERS WHO RAN TOWARD
VOLUNTEERS WHO RAN TOWARD DANGER
ON
ON 9/11
VOLUNTEERS WHO RAN TOWARD DANGER
ON 9/11 AND
ON 9/11 AND STAYED
ON 9/11 AND STAYED THERE,
BECOMING
BECOMING SICK
ON 9/11 AND STAYED THERE,
BECOMING SICK THEMSELVES.
IT
IT TOOK
BECOMING SICK THEMSELVES.
IT TOOK YEARS
IT TOOK YEARS OF
IT TOOK YEARS OF EFFORT,
IT TOOK YEARS OF EFFORT, BUT
CONGRESS
CONGRESS FINALLY
IT TOOK YEARS OF EFFORT, BUT
CONGRESS FINALLY APPROVED
CONGRESS FINALLY APPROVED THE
HEALTH
HEALTH CARE
CONGRESS FINALLY APPROVED THE
HEALTH CARE THEY
HEALTH CARE THEY NEEDED.
THERE
THERE ARE
HEALTH CARE THEY NEEDED.
THERE ARE SO
THERE ARE SO MANY
HEALTH CARE THEY NEEDED.
THERE ARE SO MANY FACES
THERE ARE SO MANY FACES AND
HEALTH CARE THEY NEEDED.
STORIES
THERE ARE SO MANY FACES AND
STORIES THAT
STORIES THAT I
THERE ARE SO MANY FACES AND
STORIES THAT I CARRY
STORIES THAT I CARRY WITH
THERE ARE SO MANY FACES AND
STORIES THAT I CARRY WITH ME
STORIES THAT I CARRY WITH ME OF
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WHO
STORIES THAT I CARRY WITH ME OF
PEOPLE WHO GAVE
PEOPLE WHO GAVE THEIR
STORIES THAT I CARRY WITH ME OF
PEOPLE WHO GAVE THEIR BEST
PEOPLE WHO GAVE THEIR BEST AND
NEEDED
NEEDED HELP
NEEDED HELP THEMSELVES.
WEEKS
WEEKS AGO,
NEEDED HELP THEMSELVES.
WEEKS AGO, I
WEEKS AGO, I MET
WEEKS AGO, I MET ANOTHER
WEEKS AGO, I MET ANOTHER PERSON
LIKE
LIKE THAT,
WEEKS AGO, I MET ANOTHER PERSON
LIKE THAT, A
LIKE THAT, A SINGLE
LIKE THAT, A SINGLE MOM
LIKE THAT, A SINGLE MOM JUGGLING
A
A JOB
LIKE THAT, A SINGLE MOM JUGGLING
A JOB AND
A JOB AND CLASSES
A JOB AND CLASSES AT
A JOB AND CLASSES AT COMMUNITY
COLLEGE
COLLEGE WHILE
A JOB AND CLASSES AT COMMUNITY
COLLEGE WHILE RAISING
COLLEGE WHILE RAISING THREE
KIDS.
SHE
COLLEGE WHILE RAISING THREE
KIDS.
SHE DOES
SHE DOES NOT
SHE DOES NOT EXPECT
SHE DOES NOT EXPECT ANYTHING
SHE DOES NOT EXPECT ANYTHING TO
COME
COME EASY,
SHE DOES NOT EXPECT ANYTHING TO
COME EASY, BUT
COME EASY, BUT SHE
SHE DOES NOT EXPECT ANYTHING TO
COME EASY, BUT SHE DID
COME EASY, BUT SHE DID ASK
SHE DOES NOT EXPECT ANYTHING TO
COME EASY, BUT SHE DID ASK ME
WHAT
WHAT MORE
COME EASY, BUT SHE DID ASK ME
WHAT MORE CAN
WHAT MORE CAN BE
COME EASY, BUT SHE DID ASK ME
WHAT MORE CAN BE DONE
WHAT MORE CAN BE DONE SO
COME EASY, BUT SHE DID ASK ME
WHAT MORE CAN BE DONE SO IT
ISN'T
ISN'T QUITE
WHAT MORE CAN BE DONE SO IT
ISN'T QUITE SO
ISN'T QUITE SO HARD
WHAT MORE CAN BE DONE SO IT
ISN'T QUITE SO HARD FOR
ISN'T QUITE SO HARD FOR FAMILIES
LIKE
LIKE HERS.
ISN'T QUITE SO HARD FOR FAMILIES
I
LIKE HERS.
I WANT
I WANT TO
LIKE HERS.
I WANT TO BE
I WANT TO BE HER
I WANT TO BE HER CHAMPION
I WANT TO BE HER CHAMPION AND
YOUR
YOUR CHAMPION.
I WANT TO BE HER CHAMPION AND
[CHEERING]
YOUR CHAMPION.
[CHEERING] IF
[CHEERING] IF YOU'LL
[CHEERING] IF YOU'LL GIVE
[CHEERING] IF YOU'LL GIVE ME
[CHEERING] IF YOU'LL GIVE ME THE
CHANCE,
CHANCE, I'LL
[CHEERING] IF YOU'LL GIVE ME THE
CHANCE, I'LL WAGE
CHANCE, I'LL WAGE AND
CHANCE, I'LL WAGE AND WIN
CHANCE, I'LL WAGE AND WIN FOUR
FIGHTS
FIGHTS FOR
CHANCE, I'LL WAGE AND WIN FOUR
FIGHTS FOR YOU.
THE
THE FIRST
FIGHTS FOR YOU.
THE FIRST IS
THE FIRST IS TO
FIGHTS FOR YOU.
THE FIRST IS TO MAKE
THE FIRST IS TO MAKE THE
FIGHTS FOR YOU.
THE FIRST IS TO MAKE THE ECONOMY
WORK
WORK FOR
THE FIRST IS TO MAKE THE ECONOMY
WORK FOR EVERY
WORK FOR EVERY DAY
THE FIRST IS TO MAKE THE ECONOMY
WORK FOR EVERY DAY AMERICANS
WORK FOR EVERY DAY AMERICANS NOT
JUST
JUST THOSE
WORK FOR EVERY DAY AMERICANS NOT
JUST THOSE AT
JUST THOSE AT THE
JUST THOSE AT THE TOP.
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] TO
[CHEERING] TO MAKE
[CHEERING] TO MAKE THE
[CHEERING] TO MAKE THE MIDDLE
CLASS
CLASS MEAN
[CHEERING] TO MAKE THE MIDDLE
CLASS MEAN SOMETHING
CLASS MEAN SOMETHING AGAIN,
CLASS MEAN SOMETHING AGAIN, WITH
RISING
RISING INCOMES
CLASS MEAN SOMETHING AGAIN, WITH
RISING INCOMES AND
RISING INCOMES AND BROADER
HORIZONS
HORIZONS AND
RISING INCOMES AND BROADER
HORIZONS AND TO
HORIZONS AND TO GIVE
RISING INCOMES AND BROADER
HORIZONS AND TO GIVE THE
HORIZONS AND TO GIVE THE POOR
RISING INCOMES AND BROADER
HORIZONS AND TO GIVE THE POOR A
CHANCE
CHANCE TO
HORIZONS AND TO GIVE THE POOR A
CHANCE TO WORK
CHANCE TO WORK THEIR
CHANCE TO WORK THEIR WAY
CHANCE TO WORK THEIR WAY INTO
IT.
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] THE
IT.
[CHEERING] THE MIDDLE
[CHEERING] THE MIDDLE CLASS
NEEDS
NEEDS MORE
[CHEERING] THE MIDDLE CLASS
NEEDS MORE GROWTH
NEEDS MORE GROWTH AND
NEEDS MORE GROWTH AND MORE
FAIRNESS.
GROWTH
NEEDS MORE GROWTH AND MORE
FAIRNESS.
GROWTH AND
GROWTH AND FAIRNESS
FAIRNESS.
GROWTH AND FAIRNESS GO
GROWTH AND FAIRNESS GO TOGETHER.
FOR
FOR LASTING
GROWTH AND FAIRNESS GO TOGETHER.
FOR LASTING PROSPERITY,
FOR LASTING PROSPERITY, YOU
CAN'T
CAN'T HAVE
FOR LASTING PROSPERITY, YOU
CAN'T HAVE ONE
CAN'T HAVE ONE WITHOUT
FOR LASTING PROSPERITY, YOU
CAN'T HAVE ONE WITHOUT THE
OTHER.
IS
CAN'T HAVE ONE WITHOUT THE
OTHER.
IS THIS
CAN'T HAVE ONE WITHOUT THE
OTHER.
IS THIS POSSIBLE
IS THIS POSSIBLE IN
OTHER.
IS THIS POSSIBLE IN TODAY'S
WORLD?
>>
IS THIS POSSIBLE IN TODAY'S
WORLD?
>> YES.
I
WORLD?
>> YES.
I BELIEVE
WORLD?
>> YES.
I BELIEVE IT
WORLD?
>> YES.
I BELIEVE IT IS.
OR
>> YES.
I BELIEVE IT IS.
OR I
>> YES.
I BELIEVE IT IS.
OR I WOULDN'T
OR I WOULDN'T BE
I BELIEVE IT IS.
OR I WOULDN'T BE STANDING
OR I WOULDN'T BE STANDING HERE.
DO
DO I
OR I WOULDN'T BE STANDING HERE.
DO I THINK
DO I THINK IT
DO I THINK IT WILL
DO I THINK IT WILL BE
DO I THINK IT WILL BE EASY?
OF
OF COURSE
DO I THINK IT WILL BE EASY?
OF COURSE NOT.
BUT
BUT HERE'S
OF COURSE NOT.
BUT HERE'S THE
BUT HERE'S THE GOOD
OF COURSE NOT.
BUT HERE'S THE GOOD NEWS.
THERE
THERE ARE
BUT HERE'S THE GOOD NEWS.
THERE ARE ALLIES
THERE ARE ALLIES FOR
BUT HERE'S THE GOOD NEWS.
THERE ARE ALLIES FOR CHANGE
EVERYWHERE
EVERYWHERE WHO
THERE ARE ALLIES FOR CHANGE
EVERYWHERE WHO KNOW
EVERYWHERE WHO KNOW WE
THERE ARE ALLIES FOR CHANGE
EVERYWHERE WHO KNOW WE CAN'T
STAND
STAND BY
EVERYWHERE WHO KNOW WE CAN'T
STAND BY WHILE
STAND BY WHILE INEQUALITY
INCREASES,
INCREASES, WAGES
STAND BY WHILE INEQUALITY
INCREASES, WAGES STAGNATE,
INCREASES, WAGES STAGNATE, AND
STAND BY WHILE INEQUALITY
THE
INCREASES, WAGES STAGNATE, AND
THE PROMISE
THE PROMISE OF
INCREASES, WAGES STAGNATE, AND
THE PROMISE OF AMERICA
THE PROMISE OF AMERICA DIMS.
INCREASES, WAGES STAGNATE, AND
THE PROMISE OF AMERICA DIMS. WE
SHOULD
SHOULD WELCOME
THE PROMISE OF AMERICA DIMS. WE
SHOULD WELCOME THE
SHOULD WELCOME THE SUPPORT
THE PROMISE OF AMERICA DIMS. WE
SHOULD WELCOME THE SUPPORT OF
ALL
ALL AMERICANS
SHOULD WELCOME THE SUPPORT OF
ALL AMERICANS WHO
ALL AMERICANS WHO WANT
SHOULD WELCOME THE SUPPORT OF
ALL AMERICANS WHO WANT TO
ALL AMERICANS WHO WANT TO GO
SHOULD WELCOME THE SUPPORT OF
FORWARD
ALL AMERICANS WHO WANT TO GO
FORWARD TOGETHER
FORWARD TOGETHER WITH
FORWARD TOGETHER WITH US.
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] THERE
FORWARD TOGETHER WITH US.
[CHEERING] THERE ARE
[CHEERING] THERE ARE PUBLIC
OFFICIALS
OFFICIALS WHO
[CHEERING] THERE ARE PUBLIC
OFFICIALS WHO KNOW
OFFICIALS WHO KNOW AMERICANS
[CHEERING] THERE ARE PUBLIC
NEED
OFFICIALS WHO KNOW AMERICANS
NEED A
NEED A BETTER
DEAL.
THOSE
THOSE WHO
THOSE WHO WANT
THOSE WHO WANT HIGHER
THOSE WHO WANT HIGHER PAY
THOSE WHO WANT HIGHER PAY FOR
EMPLOYEES,
EMPLOYEES, EQUAL
THOSE WHO WANT HIGHER PAY FOR
EMPLOYEES, EQUAL PAY
EMPLOYEES, EQUAL PAY FOR
EMPLOYEES, EQUAL PAY FOR WOMEN,
AND
AND NO
EMPLOYEES, EQUAL PAY FOR WOMEN,
AND NO DISCRIMINATION
AND NO DISCRIMINATION AGAINST
THE
THE LGBT
AND NO DISCRIMINATION AGAINST
THE LGBT COMMUNITY
EITHER.
THERE
THERE ARE
THERE ARE LEADERS
THERE ARE LEADERS OF
THERE ARE LEADERS OF FINANCE
THERE ARE LEADERS OF FINANCE WHO
WANT
WANT LESS
THERE ARE LEADERS OF FINANCE WHO
WANT LESS SHORT-TERM
WANT LESS SHORT-TERM TRADING
THERE ARE LEADERS OF FINANCE WHO
WANT LESS SHORT-TERM TRADING AND
MORE
MORE LONG-TERM
WANT LESS SHORT-TERM TRADING AND
MORE LONG-TERM INVESTING.
THERE
THERE ARE
MORE LONG-TERM INVESTING.
THERE ARE UNION
THERE ARE UNION LEADERS
INVESTING
INVESTING THEIR
THERE ARE UNION LEADERS
INVESTING THEIR OWN
INVESTING THEIR OWN PENSION
FUNDS
FUNDS IN
INVESTING THEIR OWN PENSION
FUNDS IN PUTTING
FUNDS IN PUTTING PEOPLE
INVESTING THEIR OWN PENSION
FUNDS IN PUTTING PEOPLE TO
FUNDS IN PUTTING PEOPLE TO WORK
TO
TO BUILD
TO BUILD TOMORROW'S
TO BUILD TOMORROW'S ECONOMY.
WE
WE NEED
TO BUILD TOMORROW'S ECONOMY.
WE NEED EVERYONE
WE NEED EVERYONE TO
TO BUILD TOMORROW'S ECONOMY.
WE NEED EVERYONE TO COME
WE NEED EVERYONE TO COME TO
TO BUILD TOMORROW'S ECONOMY.
WE NEED EVERYONE TO COME TO THE
TABLE
TABLE AND
WE NEED EVERYONE TO COME TO THE
TABLE AND WORK
TABLE AND WORK WITH
WE NEED EVERYONE TO COME TO THE
TABLE AND WORK WITH US
TABLE AND WORK WITH US IN
TABLE AND WORK WITH US IN THE
COMING
COMING WEEKS
COMING WEEKS I'LL
COMING WEEKS I'LL PROPOSE
SPECIFIC
SPECIFIC POLICIES.
COMING WEEKS I'LL PROPOSE
TO
SPECIFIC POLICIES.
TO REWARD
TO REWARD BUSINESSES
SPECIFIC POLICIES.
TO REWARD BUSINESSES WHO
TO REWARD BUSINESSES WHO INVEST
IN
IN LONG-TERM
TO REWARD BUSINESSES WHO INVEST
IN LONG-TERM VALUE
IN LONG-TERM VALUE RATHER
IN LONG-TERM VALUE RATHER THAN
THE
THE QUICK
IN LONG-TERM VALUE RATHER THAN
THE QUICK BUCK.
THAT
THAT LEADS
THE QUICK BUCK.
THAT LEADS TO
THAT LEADS TO HIGHER
THE QUICK BUCK.
THAT LEADS TO HIGHER GROWTH
THAT LEADS TO HIGHER GROWTH FOR
THE QUICK BUCK.
THE
THAT LEADS TO HIGHER GROWTH FOR
THE ECONOMY,
THE ECONOMY, HIGHER
THAT LEADS TO HIGHER GROWTH FOR
THE ECONOMY, HIGHER WAGES
THE ECONOMY, HIGHER WAGES FOR
WORKERS
WORKERS AND,
THE ECONOMY, HIGHER WAGES FOR
WORKERS AND, YES,
WORKERS AND, YES, EVERYBODY
WORKERS AND, YES, EVERYBODY WILL
HAVE
HAVE A
WORKERS AND, YES, EVERYBODY WILL
HAVE A BETTER
HAVE A BETTER TIME.
WORKERS AND, YES, EVERYBODY WILL
I
HAVE A BETTER TIME.
I WILL
I WILL REWRITE
HAVE A BETTER TIME.
I WILL REWRITE THE
I WILL REWRITE THE TAX
HAVE A BETTER TIME.
I WILL REWRITE THE TAX CODE
I WILL REWRITE THE TAX CODE SO
HAVE A BETTER TIME.
IT
I WILL REWRITE THE TAX CODE SO
IT REWARDS
IT REWARDS HARD
I WILL REWRITE THE TAX CODE SO
IT REWARDS HARD WORK
IT REWARDS HARD WORK AND
I WILL REWRITE THE TAX CODE SO
INVESTMENTS
IT REWARDS HARD WORK AND
INVESTMENTS HERE
INVESTMENTS HERE AT
IT REWARDS HARD WORK AND
INVESTMENTS HERE AT HOME
INVESTMENTS HERE AT HOME NOT
IT REWARDS HARD WORK AND
TRADE
INVESTMENTS HERE AT HOME NOT
TRADE OR
TRADE OR STASHING
INVESTMENTS HERE AT HOME NOT
TRADE OR STASHING PROFITS
OVERSEAS.
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] I
OVERSEAS.
[CHEERING] I WILL
[CHEERING] I WILL GIVE
[CHEERING] I WILL GIVE NEW
INCENTIVES
INCENTIVES TO
[CHEERING] I WILL GIVE NEW
INCENTIVES TO COMPANIES
INCENTIVES TO COMPANIES THAT
GIVE
GIVE THEIR
INCENTIVES TO COMPANIES THAT
GIVE THEIR EMPLOYEES
GIVE THEIR EMPLOYEES A
INCENTIVES TO COMPANIES THAT
GIVE THEIR EMPLOYEES A FAIR
SHARE
SHARE OF
GIVE THEIR EMPLOYEES A FAIR
SHARE OF THE
SHARE OF THE PROFITS
GIVE THEIR EMPLOYEES A FAIR
SHARE OF THE PROFITS THEIR
SHARE OF THE PROFITS THEIR HARD
WORK
WORK EARNS.
WE
WE WILL
WORK EARNS.
WE WILL UNLEASH
WE WILL UNLEASH NEW
WE WILL UNLEASH NEW GENERATION
OF
OF ENTREPRENEURS
WE WILL UNLEASH NEW GENERATION
OF ENTREPRENEURS AND
OF ENTREPRENEURS AND SMALL
WE WILL UNLEASH NEW GENERATION
BUSINESS
OF ENTREPRENEURS AND SMALL
BUSINESS OWNERS
BUSINESS OWNERS BY
OF ENTREPRENEURS AND SMALL
BUSINESS OWNERS BY PROVIDING
BUSINESS OWNERS BY PROVIDING TAX
OF ENTREPRENEURS AND SMALL
RELIEF,
BUSINESS OWNERS BY PROVIDING TAX
RELIEF, CUTTING
RELIEF, CUTTING RED
BUSINESS OWNERS BY PROVIDING TAX
RELIEF, CUTTING RED TAPE,
RELIEF, CUTTING RED TAPE, AND
BUSINESS OWNERS BY PROVIDING TAX
MAKING
RELIEF, CUTTING RED TAPE, AND
MAKING IT
MAKING IT EASIER
RELIEF, CUTTING RED TAPE, AND
MAKING IT EASIER TO
MAKING IT EASIER TO GET
RELIEF, CUTTING RED TAPE, AND
MAKING IT EASIER TO GET A
MAKING IT EASIER TO GET A SMALL
RELIEF, CUTTING RED TAPE, AND
BUSINESS
MAKING IT EASIER TO GET A SMALL
BUSINESS LOAN.
WE
MAKING IT EASIER TO GET A SMALL
BUSINESS LOAN.
WE WILL
MAKING IT EASIER TO GET A SMALL
BUSINESS LOAN.
WE WILL RESTORE
WE WILL RESTORE AMERICA
BUSINESS LOAN.
WE WILL RESTORE AMERICA TO
WE WILL RESTORE AMERICA TO THE
BUSINESS LOAN.
CUTTING
WE WILL RESTORE AMERICA TO THE
CUTTING EDGE
CUTTING EDGE OF
WE WILL RESTORE AMERICA TO THE
CUTTING EDGE OF INNOVATION,
SCIENCE,
SCIENCE, AND
CUTTING EDGE OF INNOVATION,
SCIENCE, AND RESEARCH
SCIENCE, AND RESEARCH BY
CUTTING EDGE OF INNOVATION,
INCREASING
SCIENCE, AND RESEARCH BY
INCREASING BOTH
INCREASING BOTH PUBLIC
SCIENCE, AND RESEARCH BY
INCREASING BOTH PUBLIC AND
PRIVATE
PRIVATE INVESTMENTS.
INCREASING BOTH PUBLIC AND
AND
PRIVATE INVESTMENTS.
AND WE
AND WE WILL
PRIVATE INVESTMENTS.
AND WE WILL MAKE
AND WE WILL MAKE AMERICA
AND WE WILL MAKE AMERICA THE
CLEAN
CLEAN ENERGY
AND WE WILL MAKE AMERICA THE
CLEAN ENERGY SUPER
CLEAN ENERGY SUPER POWER
AND WE WILL MAKE AMERICA THE
CLEAN ENERGY SUPER POWER OF
CLEAN ENERGY SUPER POWER OF THE
21ST
CENTURY.
DEVELOPING
DEVELOPING RENEWABLE
DEVELOPING RENEWABLE POWER --
WIND,
WIND, SOLAR,
DEVELOPING RENEWABLE POWER --
WIND, SOLAR, ADVANCED
WIND, SOLAR, ADVANCED BIOFUELS,
BUILDING
BUILDING CLEANER
WIND, SOLAR, ADVANCED BIOFUELS,
BUILDING CLEANER POWER
BUILDING CLEANER POWER PLANTS,
WIND, SOLAR, ADVANCED BIOFUELS,
SMARTER
BUILDING CLEANER POWER PLANTS,
SMARTER ELECTRIC
SMARTER ELECTRIC GRIDS,
BUILDING CLEANER POWER PLANTS,
SMARTER ELECTRIC GRIDS, GREENER
BUILDINGS.
USING
SMARTER ELECTRIC GRIDS, GREENER
BUILDINGS.
USING ADDITIONAL
SMARTER ELECTRIC GRIDS, GREENER
BUILDINGS.
USING ADDITIONAL FEES
USING ADDITIONAL FEES AND
BUILDINGS.
ROYALTIES
USING ADDITIONAL FEES AND
ROYALTIES FROM
ROYALTIES FROM FOSSIL
USING ADDITIONAL FEES AND
ROYALTIES FROM FOSSIL FUEL
EXTRACTION
EXTRACTION TO
ROYALTIES FROM FOSSIL FUEL
EXTRACTION TO PROTECT
EXTRACTION TO PROTECT THE
ROYALTIES FROM FOSSIL FUEL
ENVIRONMENT
EXTRACTION TO PROTECT THE
ENVIRONMENT AND
ENVIRONMENT AND EASE
EXTRACTION TO PROTECT THE
ENVIRONMENT AND EASE THE
TRANSITION
TRANSITION FOR
ENVIRONMENT AND EASE THE
TRANSITION FOR DISTRESSED
COMMUNITIES
COMMUNITIES TO
TRANSITION FOR DISTRESSED
COMMUNITIES TO A
COMMUNITIES TO A MORE
TRANSITION FOR DISTRESSED
COMMUNITIES TO A MORE DIVERSE
AND
AND SUSTAINABLE
COMMUNITIES TO A MORE DIVERSE
AND SUSTAINABLE ECONOMIC
AND SUSTAINABLE ECONOMIC FUTURE
FROM
FROM COAL
AND SUSTAINABLE ECONOMIC FUTURE
FROM COAL COUNTRY
FROM COAL COUNTRY TO
AND SUSTAINABLE ECONOMIC FUTURE
FROM COAL COUNTRY TO INDIAN
COUNTRY
COUNTRY TO
FROM COAL COUNTRY TO INDIAN
COUNTRY TO SMALL
COUNTRY TO SMALL TOWNS
FROM COAL COUNTRY TO INDIAN
COUNTRY TO SMALL TOWNS OF
COUNTRY TO SMALL TOWNS OF THE
FROM COAL COUNTRY TO INDIAN
MISSISSIPPI
COUNTRY TO SMALL TOWNS OF THE
MISSISSIPPI DELTA
MISSISSIPPI DELTA TO
COUNTRY TO SMALL TOWNS OF THE
MISSISSIPPI DELTA TO THE
MISSISSIPPI DELTA TO THE RIO
COUNTRY TO SMALL TOWNS OF THE
GRANDE
MISSISSIPPI DELTA TO THE RIO
GRANDE VALLEY
GRANDE VALLEY TO
MISSISSIPPI DELTA TO THE RIO
GRANDE VALLEY TO OUR
GRANDE VALLEY TO OUR INNER
MISSISSIPPI DELTA TO THE RIO
CITIES
GRANDE VALLEY TO OUR INNER
CITIES WE
CITIES WE HAVE
GRANDE VALLEY TO OUR INNER
CITIES WE HAVE TO
CITIES WE HAVE TO HELP
GRANDE VALLEY TO OUR INNER
CITIES WE HAVE TO HELP OUR
FELLOW
FELLOW AMERICANS.
CITIES WE HAVE TO HELP OUR
[CHEERING]
FELLOW AMERICANS.
[CHEERING] NOW,
[CHEERING] NOW, THIS
FELLOW AMERICANS.
[CHEERING] NOW, THIS WILL
[CHEERING] NOW, THIS WILL CREATE
MILLIONS
MILLIONS OF
[CHEERING] NOW, THIS WILL CREATE
MILLIONS OF JOBS
MILLIONS OF JOBS AND
MILLIONS OF JOBS AND COUNTLESS
NEW
NEW BUSINESSES
NEW BUSINESSES AND
NEW BUSINESSES AND ENABLE
AMERICA
AMERICA TO
AMERICA TO LEAD
AMERICA TO LEAD THE
AMERICA TO LEAD THE GLOBAL
AMERICA TO LEAD THE GLOBAL FIGHT
AGAINST
AGAINST CLIMATE
AGAINST CLIMATE CHANGE.
WE
WE WILL
AGAINST CLIMATE CHANGE.
WE WILL ALSO
WE WILL ALSO CONNECT
AGAINST CLIMATE CHANGE.
WE WILL ALSO CONNECT WORKERS
WE WILL ALSO CONNECT WORKERS TO
THEIR
THEIR JOBS
WE WILL ALSO CONNECT WORKERS TO
THEIR JOBS AND
THEIR JOBS AND BUSINESSES.
CUSTOMERS
CUSTOMERS WILL
THEIR JOBS AND BUSINESSES.
CUSTOMERS WILL HAVE
CUSTOMERS WILL HAVE A
CUSTOMERS WILL HAVE A BETTER
CHANCE
CHANCE TO
CUSTOMERS WILL HAVE A BETTER
CHANCE TO ACTUALLY
CHANCE TO ACTUALLY GET
CUSTOMERS WILL HAVE A BETTER
CHANCE TO ACTUALLY GET WHERE
THEY
THEY NEED
CHANCE TO ACTUALLY GET WHERE
THEY NEED AND
THEY NEED AND GET
CHANCE TO ACTUALLY GET WHERE
THEY NEED AND GET WHAT
THEY NEED AND GET WHAT THEY
DESIRE
DESIRE WITH
THEY NEED AND GET WHAT THEY
DESIRE WITH ROADS,
DESIRE WITH ROADS, RAILWAYS,
BRIDGES,
BRIDGES, AIRPORTS,
DESIRE WITH ROADS, RAILWAYS,
BRIDGES, AIRPORTS, PORTS,
BRIDGES, AIRPORTS, PORTS, AND
BROADBAND
BROADBAND BROUGHT
BRIDGES, AIRPORTS, PORTS, AND
BROADBAND BROUGHT UP
BROADBAND BROUGHT UP TO
BRIDGES, AIRPORTS, PORTS, AND
BROADBAND BROUGHT UP TO GLOBAL
STANDARDS
STANDARDS FOR
BROADBAND BROUGHT UP TO GLOBAL
STANDARDS FOR THE
STANDARDS FOR THE 21ST
STANDARDS FOR THE 21ST CENTURY.
WE
WE WILL
STANDARDS FOR THE 21ST CENTURY.
WE WILL ESTABLISH
WE WILL ESTABLISH AN
INFRASTRUCTURE
INFRASTRUCTURE BANK
WE WILL ESTABLISH AN
INFRASTRUCTURE BANK AND
INFRASTRUCTURE BANK AND SELL
WE WILL ESTABLISH AN
BONDS
INFRASTRUCTURE BANK AND SELL
BONDS TO
BONDS TO PAY
INFRASTRUCTURE BANK AND SELL
BONDS TO PAY FOR
BONDS TO PAY FOR SOME
INFRASTRUCTURE BANK AND SELL
BONDS TO PAY FOR SOME OF
BONDS TO PAY FOR SOME OF THESE
IMPROVEMENTS.
NOW,
BONDS TO PAY FOR SOME OF THESE
IMPROVEMENTS.
NOW, BUILDING
NOW, BUILDING AN
IMPROVEMENTS.
NOW, BUILDING AN ECONOMY
NOW, BUILDING AN ECONOMY FOR
IMPROVEMENTS.
TOMORROW
NOW, BUILDING AN ECONOMY FOR
TOMORROW ALSO
TOMORROW ALSO REQUIRES
NOW, BUILDING AN ECONOMY FOR
TOMORROW ALSO REQUIRES INVESTING
IN
IN OUR
TOMORROW ALSO REQUIRES INVESTING
IN OUR MOST
IN OUR MOST IMPORTANT
TOMORROW ALSO REQUIRES INVESTING
IN OUR MOST IMPORTANT ASSET,
IN OUR MOST IMPORTANT ASSET, OUR
PEOPLE,
PEOPLE, BEGINNING
IN OUR MOST IMPORTANT ASSET, OUR
PEOPLE, BEGINNING WITH
PEOPLE, BEGINNING WITH OUR
YOUNGEST.
YOUNGEST. THAT'S
PEOPLE, BEGINNING WITH OUR
YOUNGEST. THAT'S WHY
YOUNGEST. THAT'S WHY I
PEOPLE, BEGINNING WITH OUR
YOUNGEST. THAT'S WHY I WILL
PROPOSE
PROPOSE THAT
YOUNGEST. THAT'S WHY I WILL
PROPOSE THAT WE
PROPOSE THAT WE MAKE
YOUNGEST. THAT'S WHY I WILL
PROPOSE THAT WE MAKE PRESCHOOL
AND
AND QUALITY
PROPOSE THAT WE MAKE PRESCHOOL
AND QUALITY CHILD
AND QUALITY CHILD CARE
PROPOSE THAT WE MAKE PRESCHOOL
AND QUALITY CHILD CARE AVAILABLE
TO
TO EVERY
AND QUALITY CHILD CARE AVAILABLE
TO EVERY CHILD
TO EVERY CHILD IN
TO EVERY CHILD IN AMERICA.
[CHEERING]
AND
AND I
AND I WANT
AND I WANT YOU
AND I WANT YOU TO
AND I WANT YOU TO REMEMBER
AND I WANT YOU TO REMEMBER THIS,
BECAUSE
BECAUSE TO
AND I WANT YOU TO REMEMBER THIS,
BECAUSE TO ME
BECAUSE TO ME THIS
BECAUSE TO ME THIS IS
BECAUSE TO ME THIS IS ABSOLUTELY
THE
THE MOST
BECAUSE TO ME THIS IS ABSOLUTELY
THE MOST COMPELLING
THE MOST COMPELLING ARGUMENT
BECAUSE TO ME THIS IS ABSOLUTELY
THE MOST COMPELLING ARGUMENT WHY
WE
WE SHOULD
THE MOST COMPELLING ARGUMENT WHY
WE SHOULD DO
WE SHOULD DO THIS.
RESEARCH
RESEARCH TELLS
WE SHOULD DO THIS.
RESEARCH TELLS US
RESEARCH TELLS US HOW
RESEARCH TELLS US HOW MUCH
RESEARCH TELLS US HOW MUCH EARLY
LEARNING
LEARNING AND
RESEARCH TELLS US HOW MUCH EARLY
LEARNING AND THE
LEARNING AND THE FIRST
RESEARCH TELLS US HOW MUCH EARLY
LEARNING AND THE FIRST FIVE
YEARS
YEARS OF
LEARNING AND THE FIRST FIVE
YEARS OF LIFE
YEARS OF LIFE CAN
LEARNING AND THE FIRST FIVE
YEARS OF LIFE CAN IMPACT
YEARS OF LIFE CAN IMPACT LIFE
LONG
LONG SUCCESS.
YEARS OF LIFE CAN IMPACT LIFE
IN
LONG SUCCESS.
IN FACT,
IN FACT, 80%
LONG SUCCESS.
IN FACT, 80% OF
IN FACT, 80% OF YOUR
LONG SUCCESS.
IN FACT, 80% OF YOUR BRAIN
IN FACT, 80% OF YOUR BRAIN IS
DEVELOPED
DEVELOPED BY
IN FACT, 80% OF YOUR BRAIN IS
DEVELOPED BY AGE
DEVELOPED BY AGE 3.
IN FACT, 80% OF YOUR BRAIN IS
DEVELOPED BY AGE 3. AND
DEVELOPED BY AGE 3. AND ONE
THING
THING I'VE
DEVELOPED BY AGE 3. AND ONE
THING I'VE LEARNED
THING I'VE LEARNED IS
DEVELOPED BY AGE 3. AND ONE
THING I'VE LEARNED IS THAT
TALENT
TALENT IS
THING I'VE LEARNED IS THAT
TALENT IS UNIVERSAL.
YOU
THING I'VE LEARNED IS THAT
TALENT IS UNIVERSAL.
YOU CAN
THING I'VE LEARNED IS THAT
TALENT IS UNIVERSAL.
YOU CAN FIND
YOU CAN FIND IT
TALENT IS UNIVERSAL.
YOU CAN FIND IT ANYWHERE.
BUT
BUT OPPORTUNITY
YOU CAN FIND IT ANYWHERE.
BUT OPPORTUNITY IS
BUT OPPORTUNITY IS NOT.
TOO
TOO MANY
BUT OPPORTUNITY IS NOT.
TOO MANY OF
TOO MANY OF OUR
BUT OPPORTUNITY IS NOT.
TOO MANY OF OUR KIDS
TOO MANY OF OUR KIDS NEVER
BUT OPPORTUNITY IS NOT.
TOO MANY OF OUR KIDS NEVER HAVE
THE
THE CHANCE
TOO MANY OF OUR KIDS NEVER HAVE
THE CHANCE TO
THE CHANCE TO LEARN
TOO MANY OF OUR KIDS NEVER HAVE
THE CHANCE TO LEARN AND
THE CHANCE TO LEARN AND THRIVE
AS
AS THEY
THE CHANCE TO LEARN AND THRIVE
AS THEY SHOULD
AS THEY SHOULD AND
THE CHANCE TO LEARN AND THRIVE
AS THEY SHOULD AND AS
AS THEY SHOULD AND AS WE
THE CHANCE TO LEARN AND THRIVE
AS THEY SHOULD AND AS WE NEED
THEM
THEM TO.
AS THEY SHOULD AND AS WE NEED
OUR
THEM TO.
OUR COUNTRY
OUR COUNTRY WON'T
THEM TO.
OUR COUNTRY WON'T BE
OUR COUNTRY WON'T BE COMPETITIVE
THEM TO.
OR
OUR COUNTRY WON'T BE COMPETITIVE
OR FAIR
OR FAIR IF
OUR COUNTRY WON'T BE COMPETITIVE
OR FAIR IF WE
OR FAIR IF WE DON'T
OUR COUNTRY WON'T BE COMPETITIVE
OR FAIR IF WE DON'T HELP
OR FAIR IF WE DON'T HELP MORE
OUR COUNTRY WON'T BE COMPETITIVE
FAMILIES
OR FAIR IF WE DON'T HELP MORE
FAMILIES GIVE
FAMILIES GIVE THEIR
OR FAIR IF WE DON'T HELP MORE
FAMILIES GIVE THEIR KIDS
FAMILIES GIVE THEIR KIDS THE
OR FAIR IF WE DON'T HELP MORE
BEST
FAMILIES GIVE THEIR KIDS THE
BEST POSSIBLE
BEST POSSIBLE START
FAMILIES GIVE THEIR KIDS THE
BEST POSSIBLE START IN
BEST POSSIBLE START IN LIFE.
FAMILIES GIVE THEIR KIDS THE
SO
BEST POSSIBLE START IN LIFE.
SO LET'S
SO LET'S STAFF
BEST POSSIBLE START IN LIFE.
SO LET'S STAFF OUR
SO LET'S STAFF OUR PRIMARY
BEST POSSIBLE START IN LIFE.
SO LET'S STAFF OUR PRIMARY AND
SECONDARY
SECONDARY SCHOOLS
SO LET'S STAFF OUR PRIMARY AND
SECONDARY SCHOOLS WITH
SECONDARY SCHOOLS WITH TEACHERS
SO LET'S STAFF OUR PRIMARY AND
WHO
SECONDARY SCHOOLS WITH TEACHERS
WHO ARE
WHO ARE SECOND
SECONDARY SCHOOLS WITH TEACHERS
WHO ARE SECOND TO
WHO ARE SECOND TO NONE
SECONDARY SCHOOLS WITH TEACHERS
WHO ARE SECOND TO NONE IN
WHO ARE SECOND TO NONE IN THE
SECONDARY SCHOOLS WITH TEACHERS
WORLD
WHO ARE SECOND TO NONE IN THE
WORLD AND
WORLD AND RECEIVE
WHO ARE SECOND TO NONE IN THE
WORLD AND RECEIVE THE
WORLD AND RECEIVE THE RESPECT
WHO ARE SECOND TO NONE IN THE
THEY
WORLD AND RECEIVE THE RESPECT
THEY DESERVE
THEY DESERVE FOR
WORLD AND RECEIVE THE RESPECT
THEY DESERVE FOR SPARKING
THEY DESERVE FOR SPARKING THE
WORLD AND RECEIVE THE RESPECT
LOVE
THEY DESERVE FOR SPARKING THE
LOVE OF
LOVE OF LEARNING
THEY DESERVE FOR SPARKING THE
LOVE OF LEARNING IN
LOVE OF LEARNING IN EVERY
CHILD.
LET'S
LET'S MAKE
CHILD.
LET'S MAKE COLLEGE
LET'S MAKE COLLEGE AFFORDABLE
AND
AND AVAILABLE
LET'S MAKE COLLEGE AFFORDABLE
AND AVAILABLE TO
AND AVAILABLE TO ALL
AND AVAILABLE TO ALL AND
AND AVAILABLE TO ALL AND LIFT
THE
THE CRUSHING
AND AVAILABLE TO ALL AND LIFT
THE CRUSHING BURDEN
THE CRUSHING BURDEN OF
AND AVAILABLE TO ALL AND LIFT
THE CRUSHING BURDEN OF STUDENT
DEBT.
LET'S
THE CRUSHING BURDEN OF STUDENT
DEBT.
LET'S PROVIDE
THE CRUSHING BURDEN OF STUDENT
DEBT.
LET'S PROVIDE LIFE
THE CRUSHING BURDEN OF STUDENT
DEBT.
LET'S PROVIDE LIFE LONG
LET'S PROVIDE LIFE LONG LEARNING
DEBT.
FOR
LET'S PROVIDE LIFE LONG LEARNING
FOR WORKERS
FOR WORKERS TO
LET'S PROVIDE LIFE LONG LEARNING
FOR WORKERS TO GAIN
FOR WORKERS TO GAIN OR
FOR WORKERS TO GAIN OR IMPROVE
SKILLS
SKILLS THAT
FOR WORKERS TO GAIN OR IMPROVE
SKILLS THAT THE
SKILLS THAT THE ECONOMY
FOR WORKERS TO GAIN OR IMPROVE
REQUIRES,
SKILLS THAT THE ECONOMY
REQUIRES, SETTING
REQUIRES, SETTING UP
SKILLS THAT THE ECONOMY
REQUIRES, SETTING UP MANY
REQUIRES, SETTING UP MANY MORE
AMERICANS
AMERICANS FOR
REQUIRES, SETTING UP MANY MORE
AMERICANS FOR SUCCESS.
THE
THE SECOND
AMERICANS FOR SUCCESS.
THE SECOND FIGHT
THE SECOND FIGHT IS
AMERICANS FOR SUCCESS.
THE SECOND FIGHT IS TO
STRENGTHEN
STRENGTHEN AMERICA'S
THE SECOND FIGHT IS TO
STRENGTHEN AMERICA'S FAMILIES
BECAUSE
THE SECOND FIGHT IS TO
STRENGTHEN AMERICA'S FAMILIES
BECAUSE WHEN
THE SECOND FIGHT IS TO
STRENGTHEN AMERICA'S FAMILIES
BECAUSE WHEN OUR
BECAUSE WHEN OUR FAMILIES
STRENGTHEN AMERICA'S FAMILIES
BECAUSE WHEN OUR FAMILIES ARE
STRONG,
STRENGTHEN AMERICA'S FAMILIES
BECAUSE WHEN OUR FAMILIES ARE
STRONG, AMERICA
STRONG, AMERICA IS
BECAUSE WHEN OUR FAMILIES ARE
STRONG, AMERICA IS STRONG.
AND
AND TODAY'S
STRONG, AMERICA IS STRONG.
AND TODAY'S FAMILIES
AND TODAY'S FAMILIES FACE
STRONG, AMERICA IS STRONG.
AND TODAY'S FAMILIES FACE NEW
AND
AND UNIQUE
AND TODAY'S FAMILIES FACE NEW
AND UNIQUE PRESSURES.
PARENTS
PARENTS NEED
AND UNIQUE PRESSURES.
PARENTS NEED MORE
PARENTS NEED MORE SUPPORT
AND UNIQUE PRESSURES.
PARENTS NEED MORE SUPPORT AND
FLEXIBILITY
FLEXIBILITY TO
PARENTS NEED MORE SUPPORT AND
FLEXIBILITY TO DO
FLEXIBILITY TO DO THEIR
PARENTS NEED MORE SUPPORT AND
FLEXIBILITY TO DO THEIR JOB
FLEXIBILITY TO DO THEIR JOB AT
PARENTS NEED MORE SUPPORT AND
WORK
FLEXIBILITY TO DO THEIR JOB AT
WORK AND
WORK AND AT
FLEXIBILITY TO DO THEIR JOB AT
WORK AND AT HOME.
I
I BELIEVE
WORK AND AT HOME.
I BELIEVE YOU
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD
WORK AND AT HOME.
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD HAVE
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD HAVE THE
RIGHT
RIGHT TO
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD HAVE THE
RIGHT TO EARN
RIGHT TO EARN PAID
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD HAVE THE
RIGHT TO EARN PAID SICK
RIGHT TO EARN PAID SICK DAYS.
I
I BELIEVE
RIGHT TO EARN PAID SICK DAYS.
I BELIEVE YOU
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD RECEIVE
YOUR
YOUR WORK
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD RECEIVE
YOUR WORK SCHEDULE
YOUR WORK SCHEDULE WITH
YOUR WORK SCHEDULE WITH ENOUGH
NOTICE
NOTICE TO
YOUR WORK SCHEDULE WITH ENOUGH
NOTICE TO ARRANGE
NOTICE TO ARRANGE CHILD
YOUR WORK SCHEDULE WITH ENOUGH
NOTICE TO ARRANGE CHILD CARE
NOTICE TO ARRANGE CHILD CARE OR
TAKE
TAKE COLLEGE
NOTICE TO ARRANGE CHILD CARE OR
TAKE COLLEGE COURSES
TAKE COLLEGE COURSES TO
NOTICE TO ARRANGE CHILD CARE OR
TAKE COLLEGE COURSES TO GET
AHEAD.
I
I BELIEVE
AHEAD.
I BELIEVE YOU
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD LOOK
FORWARD
FORWARD TO
I BELIEVE YOU SHOULD LOOK
FORWARD TO RETIREMENT
FORWARD TO RETIREMENT WITH
CONFIDENCE
CONFIDENCE NOT
FORWARD TO RETIREMENT WITH
CONFIDENCE NOT ANXIETY.
THAT
FORWARD TO RETIREMENT WITH
CONFIDENCE NOT ANXIETY.
THAT YOU
THAT YOU SHOULD
CONFIDENCE NOT ANXIETY.
THAT YOU SHOULD HAVE
THAT YOU SHOULD HAVE THE
CONFIDENCE NOT ANXIETY.
THAT YOU SHOULD HAVE THE PEACE
OF
OF MIND
THAT YOU SHOULD HAVE THE PEACE
OF MIND THAT
OF MIND THAT YOUR
THAT YOU SHOULD HAVE THE PEACE
OF MIND THAT YOUR HEALTHCARE
WILL
WILL BE
OF MIND THAT YOUR HEALTHCARE
WILL BE THERE
WILL BE THERE WHEN
OF MIND THAT YOUR HEALTHCARE
WILL BE THERE WHEN YOU
WILL BE THERE WHEN YOU NEED
OF MIND THAT YOUR HEALTHCARE
WILL BE THERE WHEN YOU NEED IT
WITHOUT
WITHOUT BREAKING
WILL BE THERE WHEN YOU NEED IT
WITHOUT BREAKING THE
WITHOUT BREAKING THE BANK.
I
I BELIEVE
I BELIEVE WE
I BELIEVE WE SHOULD
I BELIEVE WE SHOULD OFFER
I BELIEVE WE SHOULD OFFER PAID
FAMILY
FAMILY LEAVE.
SO
SO NO
FAMILY LEAVE.
SO NO ONE,
SO NO ONE, NO
FAMILY LEAVE.
SO NO ONE, NO ONE
SO NO ONE, NO ONE HAS
SO NO ONE, NO ONE HAS TO
SO NO ONE, NO ONE HAS TO CHOOSE
BETWEEN
BETWEEN KEEPING
SO NO ONE, NO ONE HAS TO CHOOSE
BETWEEN KEEPING A
BETWEEN KEEPING A PAYCHECK
BETWEEN KEEPING A PAYCHECK AND
CARING
CARING FOR
BETWEEN KEEPING A PAYCHECK AND
CARING FOR A
CARING FOR A NEW
BETWEEN KEEPING A PAYCHECK AND
CARING FOR A NEW BABY
CARING FOR A NEW BABY OR
BETWEEN KEEPING A PAYCHECK AND
CARING FOR A NEW BABY OR A
CARING FOR A NEW BABY OR A SICK
RELATIVE.
AND
AND IT
RELATIVE.
AND IT IS
AND IT IS WAY
AND IT IS WAY PASTIME
AND IT IS WAY PASTIME TO
AND IT IS WAY PASTIME TO END
AND IT IS WAY PASTIME TO END THE
OUTRAGE
OUTRAGE OF
AND IT IS WAY PASTIME TO END THE
OUTRAGE OF SO
OUTRAGE OF SO MANY
OUTRAGE OF SO MANY WOMEN
OUTRAGE OF SO MANY WOMEN STILL
EARNING
EARNING LESS
OUTRAGE OF SO MANY WOMEN STILL
EARNING LESS THAN
EARNING LESS THAN MEN
EARNING LESS THAN MEN ON
EARNING LESS THAN MEN ON THE
JOB.
AND
AND WOMEN
JOB.
AND WOMEN OF
AND WOMEN OF COLOR
AND WOMEN OF COLOR OFTEN
AND WOMEN OF COLOR OFTEN MAKING
EVEN
EVEN LESS.
AND WOMEN OF COLOR OFTEN MAKING
THIS
EVEN LESS.
THIS ISN'T
THIS ISN'T A
EVEN LESS.
THIS ISN'T A WOMEN'S
THIS ISN'T A WOMEN'S ISSUE.
IT'S
IT'S A
THIS ISN'T A WOMEN'S ISSUE.
IT'S A FAMILY
IT'S A FAMILY ISSUE.
JUST
JUST LIKE
IT'S A FAMILY ISSUE.
JUST LIKE RAISING
JUST LIKE RAISING THE
IT'S A FAMILY ISSUE.
JUST LIKE RAISING THE MINIMUM
WAGE
WAGE IS
JUST LIKE RAISING THE MINIMUM
WAGE IS A
WAGE IS A FAMILY
WAGE IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
EXPANDING
EXPANDING CHILD
WAGE IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
EXPANDING CHILD CARE
EXPANDING CHILD CARE IS
WAGE IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
EXPANDING CHILD CARE IS A
EXPANDING CHILD CARE IS A FAMILY
ISSUE.
DECLINING
EXPANDING CHILD CARE IS A FAMILY
ISSUE.
DECLINING MARRIAGE
EXPANDING CHILD CARE IS A FAMILY
ISSUE.
DECLINING MARRIAGE RATES
DECLINING MARRIAGE RATES IS
ISSUE.
DECLINING MARRIAGE RATES IS A
FAMILY
FAMILY ISSUE.
DECLINING MARRIAGE RATES IS A
UNEQUAL
FAMILY ISSUE.
UNEQUAL RATES
DECLINING MARRIAGE RATES IS A
FAMILY ISSUE.
UNEQUAL RATES OF
UNEQUAL RATES OF INCARCERATION
FAMILY ISSUE.
IS
UNEQUAL RATES OF INCARCERATION
IS A
IS A FAMILY
IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
HELPING
HELPING MORE
IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
HELPING MORE PEOPLE
HELPING MORE PEOPLE WITH
IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
HELPING MORE PEOPLE WITH AN
ADDICTION
ADDICTION OR
HELPING MORE PEOPLE WITH AN
ADDICTION OR A
ADDICTION OR A MENTAL
ADDICTION OR A MENTAL HEALTH
PROBLEM
PROBLEM GET
ADDICTION OR A MENTAL HEALTH
PROBLEM GET HELP
PROBLEM GET HELP IS
ADDICTION OR A MENTAL HEALTH
PROBLEM GET HELP IS A
PROBLEM GET HELP IS A FAMILY
ISSUE.
AND
AND IN
AND IN AMERICA
AND IN AMERICA EVERY
AND IN AMERICA EVERY FAMILY
SHOULD
SHOULD FEEL
AND IN AMERICA EVERY FAMILY
SHOULD FEEL LIKE
SHOULD FEEL LIKE THEY
AND IN AMERICA EVERY FAMILY
SHOULD FEEL LIKE THEY BELONG
SHOULD FEEL LIKE THEY BELONG SO
WE
WE SHOULD
SHOULD FEEL LIKE THEY BELONG SO
WE SHOULD OFFER
WE SHOULD OFFER HARD
WE SHOULD OFFER HARD WORKING,
LAW-ABIDING
LAW-ABIDING IMMIGRANT
LAW-ABIDING IMMIGRANT FAMILIES
LAW-ABIDING IMMIGRANT FAMILIES A
PATH
PATH TO
CITIZENSHIP.
NOT
NOT SECOND
NOT SECOND CLASS
NOT SECOND CLASS STATUS.
AND
AND WE
AND WE SHOULD
AND WE SHOULD BAN
AND WE SHOULD BAN DISCRIMINATION
AGAINST
AGAINST LGBT
AGAINST LGBT AMERICANS
AGAINST LGBT AMERICANS AND
AGAINST LGBT AMERICANS AND THEIR
FAMILIES
FAMILIES SO
FAMILIES SO THEY
FAMILIES SO THEY CAN
FAMILIES SO THEY CAN LIVE,
LEARN,
LEARN, MARRY,
LEARN, MARRY, AND
LEARN, MARRY, AND WORK
LEARN, MARRY, AND WORK JUST
LEARN, MARRY, AND WORK JUST LIKE
EVERYBODY
EVERYBODY ELSE.
YOU
YOU KNOW,
YOU KNOW, AMERICA'S
YOU KNOW, AMERICA'S DIVERSITY,
OUR
OUR OPENNESS,
YOU KNOW, AMERICA'S DIVERSITY,
OUR OPENNESS, OUR
OUR OPENNESS, OUR DEVOTION
YOU KNOW, AMERICA'S DIVERSITY,
OUR OPENNESS, OUR DEVOTION TO
HUMAN
HUMAN RIGHTS
OUR OPENNESS, OUR DEVOTION TO
HUMAN RIGHTS AND
HUMAN RIGHTS AND FREEDOM
OUR OPENNESS, OUR DEVOTION TO
HUMAN RIGHTS AND FREEDOM IS
WHAT'S
WHAT'S DRAWN
HUMAN RIGHTS AND FREEDOM IS
WHAT'S DRAWN SO
WHAT'S DRAWN SO MANY
HUMAN RIGHTS AND FREEDOM IS
WHAT'S DRAWN SO MANY TO
WHAT'S DRAWN SO MANY TO OUR
HUMAN RIGHTS AND FREEDOM IS
SHORES,
WHAT'S DRAWN SO MANY TO OUR
SHORES, WHAT'S
SHORES, WHAT'S INSPIRED
WHAT'S DRAWN SO MANY TO OUR
SHORES, WHAT'S INSPIRED PEOPLE
ALL
ALL OVER
SHORES, WHAT'S INSPIRED PEOPLE
ALL OVER THE
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
SHORES, WHAT'S INSPIRED PEOPLE
I
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
I KNOW.
I'VE
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
I KNOW.
I'VE SEEN
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
I KNOW.
I'VE SEEN IT
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
I KNOW.
I'VE SEEN IT WITH
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
I KNOW.
I'VE SEEN IT WITH MY
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
I KNOW.
I'VE SEEN IT WITH MY OWN
I'VE SEEN IT WITH MY OWN EYES.
I KNOW.
THESE
I'VE SEEN IT WITH MY OWN EYES.
THESE ARE
I KNOW.
I'VE SEEN IT WITH MY OWN EYES.
THESE ARE ALSO
THESE ARE ALSO THE
I'VE SEEN IT WITH MY OWN EYES.
THESE ARE ALSO THE QUALITIES
THAT
I'VE SEEN IT WITH MY OWN EYES.
THESE ARE ALSO THE QUALITIES
THAT PREPARE
THAT PREPARE US
THESE ARE ALSO THE QUALITIES
THAT PREPARE US WELL
THAT PREPARE US WELL FOR
THESE ARE ALSO THE QUALITIES
THAT PREPARE US WELL FOR THE
DEMANDS
DEMANDS OF
THAT PREPARE US WELL FOR THE
DEMANDS OF A
DEMANDS OF A WORLD
THAT PREPARE US WELL FOR THE
DEMANDS OF A WORLD THAT
DEMANDS OF A WORLD THAT IS
THAT PREPARE US WELL FOR THE
DEMANDS OF A WORLD THAT IS MORE
INTERCONNECTED
INTERCONNECTED THAN
DEMANDS OF A WORLD THAT IS MORE
INTERCONNECTED THAN EVER
INTERCONNECTED THAN EVER BEFORE.
DEMANDS OF A WORLD THAT IS MORE
SO
INTERCONNECTED THAN EVER BEFORE.
SO WE
SO WE HAVE
INTERCONNECTED THAN EVER BEFORE.
SO WE HAVE A
SO WE HAVE A THIRD
INTERCONNECTED THAN EVER BEFORE.
SO WE HAVE A THIRD FIGHT.
TO
TO HARNESS
SO WE HAVE A THIRD FIGHT.
TO HARNESS ALL
TO HARNESS ALL OF
SO WE HAVE A THIRD FIGHT.
TO HARNESS ALL OF AMERICA'S
POWER,
POWER, SMARTS,
TO HARNESS ALL OF AMERICA'S
POWER, SMARTS, AND
POWER, SMARTS, AND VALUES,
TO HARNESS ALL OF AMERICA'S
POWER, SMARTS, AND VALUES, TO
MAINTAIN
MAINTAIN OUR
POWER, SMARTS, AND VALUES, TO
MAINTAIN OUR LEADERSHIP
MAINTAIN OUR LEADERSHIP FOR
POWER, SMARTS, AND VALUES, TO
PEACE,
MAINTAIN OUR LEADERSHIP FOR
PEACE, SECURITY,
PEACE, SECURITY, AND
PEACE, SECURITY, AND PROSPERITY.
NO
NO OTHER
PEACE, SECURITY, AND PROSPERITY.
NO OTHER COUNTRY
NO OTHER COUNTRY ON
PEACE, SECURITY, AND PROSPERITY.
NO OTHER COUNTRY ON EARTH
NO OTHER COUNTRY ON EARTH IS
BETTER
BETTER POSITIONED
NO OTHER COUNTRY ON EARTH IS
BETTER POSITIONED TO
BETTER POSITIONED TO THRIVE
NO OTHER COUNTRY ON EARTH IS
BETTER POSITIONED TO THRIVE IN
THE
THE 21ST
BETTER POSITIONED TO THRIVE IN
THE 21ST CENTURY.
NO
NO OTHER
THE 21ST CENTURY.
NO OTHER COUNTRY
NO OTHER COUNTRY IS
THE 21ST CENTURY.
NO OTHER COUNTRY IS BETTER
EQUIPPED
EQUIPPED TO
NO OTHER COUNTRY IS BETTER
EQUIPPED TO MEET
EQUIPPED TO MEET TRADITIONAL
NO OTHER COUNTRY IS BETTER
STRESS
EQUIPPED TO MEET TRADITIONAL
STRESS FROM
STRESS FROM COUNTRIES
EQUIPPED TO MEET TRADITIONAL
STRESS FROM COUNTRIES LIKE
RUSSIA,
RUSSIA, NORTH
STRESS FROM COUNTRIES LIKE
RUSSIA, NORTH KOREA,
RUSSIA, NORTH KOREA, AND
STRESS FROM COUNTRIES LIKE
RUSSIA, NORTH KOREA, AND RYAN,
AND
AND TO
RUSSIA, NORTH KOREA, AND RYAN,
AND TO DEAL
AND TO DEAL WITH
RUSSIA, NORTH KOREA, AND RYAN,
AND TO DEAL WITH THE
AND TO DEAL WITH THE RISE
RUSSIA, NORTH KOREA, AND RYAN,
AND TO DEAL WITH THE RISE OF
AND TO DEAL WITH THE RISE OF NEW
POWERS
POWERS LIKE
AND TO DEAL WITH THE RISE OF NEW
POWERS LIKE CHINA.
NO
NO OTHER
POWERS LIKE CHINA.
NO OTHER COUNTRY
NO OTHER COUNTRY IS
POWERS LIKE CHINA.
NO OTHER COUNTRY IS BETTER
PREPARED
PREPARED TO
NO OTHER COUNTRY IS BETTER
PREPARED TO MEET
PREPARED TO MEET EMERGING
NO OTHER COUNTRY IS BETTER
THREATS
PREPARED TO MEET EMERGING
THREATS FROM
THREATS FROM CYBER
PREPARED TO MEET EMERGING
THREATS FROM CYBER ATTACKS,
TRANS
TRANS NATIONAL
THREATS FROM CYBER ATTACKS,
TRANS NATIONAL TERROR
TRANS NATIONAL TERROR NETWORKS
THREATS FROM CYBER ATTACKS,
LIKE
TRANS NATIONAL TERROR NETWORKS
LIKE ISIS,
LIKE ISIS, AND
TRANS NATIONAL TERROR NETWORKS
LIKE ISIS, AND DISEASES
LIKE ISIS, AND DISEASES THAT
TRANS NATIONAL TERROR NETWORKS
SPREAD
LIKE ISIS, AND DISEASES THAT
SPREAD ACROSS
SPREAD ACROSS OCEANS
LIKE ISIS, AND DISEASES THAT
SPREAD ACROSS OCEANS AND
CONTINENTS.
AS
SPREAD ACROSS OCEANS AND
CONTINENTS.
AS YOUR
SPREAD ACROSS OCEANS AND
CONTINENTS.
AS YOUR PRESIDENT,
SPREAD ACROSS OCEANS AND
CONTINENTS.
AS YOUR PRESIDENT, I'LL
AS YOUR PRESIDENT, I'LL DO
CONTINENTS.
WHATEVER
AS YOUR PRESIDENT, I'LL DO
WHATEVER IT
WHATEVER IT TAKES
AS YOUR PRESIDENT, I'LL DO
WHATEVER IT TAKES TO
WHATEVER IT TAKES TO KEEP
AMERICANS
AMERICANS SAFE.
IF
IF YOU
AMERICANS SAFE.
IF YOU LOOK,
IF YOU LOOK, OVER
IF YOU LOOK, OVER MY
IF YOU LOOK, OVER MY LEFT
SHOULDER,
SHOULDER, YOU
IF YOU LOOK, OVER MY LEFT
SHOULDER, YOU CAN
SHOULDER, YOU CAN SEE
SHOULDER, YOU CAN SEE THE
SHOULDER, YOU CAN SEE THE NEW
WORLD
WORLD TRADE
SHOULDER, YOU CAN SEE THE NEW
WORLD TRADE CENTER
WORLD TRADE CENTER SOARING
SKYWARD.
[CHEERING
[AS
[AS A
[CHEERING
[AS A SENATOR
[AS A SENATOR FROM
[CHEERING
[AS A SENATOR FROM NEW
[AS A SENATOR FROM NEW YORK,
[AS A SENATOR FROM NEW YORK, I
DEDICATED
DEDICATED MYSELF
[AS A SENATOR FROM NEW YORK, I
DEDICATED MYSELF TO
DEDICATED MYSELF TO GETTING
[AS A SENATOR FROM NEW YORK, I
DEDICATED MYSELF TO GETTING OUR
CITY
CITY AND
DEDICATED MYSELF TO GETTING OUR
CITY AND STATE
CITY AND STATE THE
DEDICATED MYSELF TO GETTING OUR
CITY AND STATE THE HELP
CITY AND STATE THE HELP WE
DEDICATED MYSELF TO GETTING OUR
NEEDED
CITY AND STATE THE HELP WE
NEEDED TO
NEEDED TO RECOVER.
CITY AND STATE THE HELP WE
AND
NEEDED TO RECOVER.
AND AS
CITY AND STATE THE HELP WE
NEEDED TO RECOVER.
AND AS A
CITY AND STATE THE HELP WE
NEEDED TO RECOVER.
AND AS A MEMBER
CITY AND STATE THE HELP WE
NEEDED TO RECOVER.
AND AS A MEMBER OF
AND AS A MEMBER OF THE
NEEDED TO RECOVER.
AND AS A MEMBER OF THE ARMED
SERVICES
NEEDED TO RECOVER.
AND AS A MEMBER OF THE ARMED
SERVICES COMMITTEE,
SERVICES COMMITTEE, I
AND AS A MEMBER OF THE ARMED
SERVICES COMMITTEE, I WORKED
SERVICES COMMITTEE, I WORKED TO
AND AS A MEMBER OF THE ARMED
MAINTAIN
SERVICES COMMITTEE, I WORKED TO
MAINTAIN THE
MAINTAIN THE BEST
SERVICES COMMITTEE, I WORKED TO
MAINTAIN THE BEST TRAINED,
MAINTAIN THE BEST TRAINED, BEST
SERVICES COMMITTEE, I WORKED TO
EQUIPPED,
MAINTAIN THE BEST TRAINED, BEST
EQUIPPED, STRONGEST
EQUIPPED, STRONGEST MILITARY,
MAINTAIN THE BEST TRAINED, BEST
READY
EQUIPPED, STRONGEST MILITARY,
READY FOR
READY FOR TODAY'S
EQUIPPED, STRONGEST MILITARY,
READY FOR TODAY'S STRESS
READY FOR TODAY'S STRESS AND
EQUIPPED, STRONGEST MILITARY,
TOMORROW'S.
READY FOR TODAY'S STRESS AND
AND
TOMORROW'S.
AND WHEN
READY FOR TODAY'S STRESS AND
TOMORROW'S.
AND WHEN OUR
AND WHEN OUR BRAVE
TOMORROW'S.
AND WHEN OUR BRAVE MEN
AND WHEN OUR BRAVE MEN AND
AND WHEN OUR BRAVE MEN AND WOMEN
COME
COME HOME
AND WHEN OUR BRAVE MEN AND WOMEN
COME HOME FROM
COME HOME FROM WAR
AND WHEN OUR BRAVE MEN AND WOMEN
COME HOME FROM WAR OR
COME HOME FROM WAR OR FINISH
THEIR
THEIR SERVICE,
COME HOME FROM WAR OR FINISH
THEIR SERVICE, I'LL
THEIR SERVICE, I'LL SEE
COME HOME FROM WAR OR FINISH
THEIR SERVICE, I'LL SEE TO
THEIR SERVICE, I'LL SEE TO IT
THAT
THAT THEY
THEIR SERVICE, I'LL SEE TO IT
THAT THEY GET
THAT THEY GET NOT
THEIR SERVICE, I'LL SEE TO IT
THAT THEY GET NOT JUST
THAT THEY GET NOT JUST THE
THEIR SERVICE, I'LL SEE TO IT
THANKS
THAT THEY GET NOT JUST THE
THANKS OF
THANKS OF A
THAT THEY GET NOT JUST THE
THANKS OF A GRATEFUL
THANKS OF A GRATEFUL NATION
THAT THEY GET NOT JUST THE
THANKS OF A GRATEFUL NATION BUT
THE
THE CARE
THANKS OF A GRATEFUL NATION BUT
THE CARE AND
THE CARE AND BENEFITS
THE CARE AND BENEFITS THEY'VE
EARNED.
I'VE
I'VE STOOD
I'VE STOOD UP
I'VE STOOD UP TO
I'VE STOOD UP TO ADVERSARIES
LIKE
LIKE PUTIN
I'VE STOOD UP TO ADVERSARIES
LIKE PUTIN AND
LIKE PUTIN AND REINFORCED
LIKE PUTIN AND REINFORCED ALLIES
LIKE
LIKE ISRAEL
LIKE PUTIN AND REINFORCED ALLIES
LIKE ISRAEL AND
LIKE ISRAEL AND I
LIKE PUTIN AND REINFORCED ALLIES
LIKE ISRAEL AND I WAS
LIKE ISRAEL AND I WAS IN
LIKE PUTIN AND REINFORCED ALLIES
LIKE ISRAEL AND I WAS IN THE
SITUATION
SITUATION ROOM
LIKE ISRAEL AND I WAS IN THE
SITUATION ROOM ON
SITUATION ROOM ON THE
LIKE ISRAEL AND I WAS IN THE
SITUATION ROOM ON THE DAY
SITUATION ROOM ON THE DAY WE
LIKE ISRAEL AND I WAS IN THE
SITUATION ROOM ON THE DAY WE GOT
BIN
BIN LADEN.
SITUATION ROOM ON THE DAY WE GOT
BUT
BIN LADEN.
BUT I
BUT I KNOW,
BIN LADEN.
BUT I KNOW, I
BUT I KNOW, I KNOW
BIN LADEN.
BUT I KNOW, I KNOW WE
BUT I KNOW, I KNOW WE HAVE
BIN LADEN.
BUT I KNOW, I KNOW WE HAVE TO
BUT I KNOW, I KNOW WE HAVE TO BE
SMART
SMART AS
BUT I KNOW, I KNOW WE HAVE TO BE
SMART AS WELL
SMART AS WELL AS
BUT I KNOW, I KNOW WE HAVE TO BE
SMART AS WELL AS STRONG.
MEETING
MEETING TODAY'S
SMART AS WELL AS STRONG.
MEETING TODAY'S GLOBAL
CHALLENGES
CHALLENGES REQUIRES
MEETING TODAY'S GLOBAL
CHALLENGES REQUIRES EVERY
ELEMENT
MEETING TODAY'S GLOBAL
CHALLENGES REQUIRES EVERY
ELEMENT OF
ELEMENT OF AMERICA'S
CHALLENGES REQUIRES EVERY
ELEMENT OF AMERICA'S POWER
INCLUDING
INCLUDING SKILLFUL
ELEMENT OF AMERICA'S POWER
INCLUDING SKILLFUL DIPLOMACY,
ECONOMIC
ECONOMIC INFLUENCE,
INCLUDING SKILLFUL DIPLOMACY,
ECONOMIC INFLUENCE, AND
ECONOMIC INFLUENCE, AND BUILDING
INCLUDING SKILLFUL DIPLOMACY,
PARTNERSHIPS
ECONOMIC INFLUENCE, AND BUILDING
PARTNERSHIPS TO
PARTNERSHIPS TO IMPROVE
ECONOMIC INFLUENCE, AND BUILDING
PARTNERSHIPS TO IMPROVE LIVES
AROUND
AROUND THE
PARTNERSHIPS TO IMPROVE LIVES
AROUND THE WORLD
AROUND THE WORLD WITH
PARTNERSHIPS TO IMPROVE LIVES
AROUND THE WORLD WITH PEOPLE
AROUND THE WORLD WITH PEOPLE NOT
PARTNERSHIPS TO IMPROVE LIVES
JUST
AROUND THE WORLD WITH PEOPLE NOT
JUST THEIR
JUST THEIR GOVERNMENTS.
AROUND THE WORLD WITH PEOPLE NOT
THERE
JUST THEIR GOVERNMENTS.
THERE ARE
THERE ARE A
JUST THEIR GOVERNMENTS.
THERE ARE A LOT
THERE ARE A LOT OF
JUST THEIR GOVERNMENTS.
THERE ARE A LOT OF TROUBLE
THERE ARE A LOT OF TROUBLE SPOTS
JUST THEIR GOVERNMENTS.
IN
THERE ARE A LOT OF TROUBLE SPOTS
IN THE
IN THE WORLD,
THERE ARE A LOT OF TROUBLE SPOTS
IN THE WORLD, BUT
IN THE WORLD, BUT THERE'S
THERE ARE A LOT OF TROUBLE SPOTS
IN THE WORLD, BUT THERE'S A
IN THE WORLD, BUT THERE'S A LOT
THERE ARE A LOT OF TROUBLE SPOTS
OF
IN THE WORLD, BUT THERE'S A LOT
OF GOOD
OF GOOD NEWS
IN THE WORLD, BUT THERE'S A LOT
OF GOOD NEWS OUT
OF GOOD NEWS OUT THERE,
IN THE WORLD, BUT THERE'S A LOT
OF GOOD NEWS OUT THERE, TOO.
I
I BELIEVE
OF GOOD NEWS OUT THERE, TOO.
I BELIEVE THE
I BELIEVE THE FUTURE
I BELIEVE THE FUTURE HOLDS
I BELIEVE THE FUTURE HOLDS FAR
MORE
MORE OPPORTUNITIES
I BELIEVE THE FUTURE HOLDS FAR
MORE OPPORTUNITIES THAN
MORE OPPORTUNITIES THAN THREATS
IF
IF WE
IF WE EXERCISE
IF WE EXERCISE CREATIVE
IF WE EXERCISE CREATIVE AND
CONFIDENT
CONFIDENT LEADERSHIP
IF WE EXERCISE CREATIVE AND
CONFIDENT LEADERSHIP THAT
ENABLES
ENABLES US
CONFIDENT LEADERSHIP THAT
ENABLES US TO
ENABLES US TO SHAPE
CONFIDENT LEADERSHIP THAT
ENABLES US TO SHAPE GLOBAL
EVENTS
EVENTS RATHER
ENABLES US TO SHAPE GLOBAL
EVENTS RATHER THAN
EVENTS RATHER THAN BE
ENABLES US TO SHAPE GLOBAL
EVENTS RATHER THAN BE SHAPED
EVENTS RATHER THAN BE SHAPED BY
THEM.
[CHEERING]
[CHEERING] AND
THEM.
[CHEERING] AND WE
[CHEERING] AND WE ALL
THEM.
[CHEERING] AND WE ALL KNOW
[CHEERING] AND WE ALL KNOW THAT
IN
IN ORDER
[CHEERING] AND WE ALL KNOW THAT
IN ORDER TO
IN ORDER TO BE
[CHEERING] AND WE ALL KNOW THAT
IN ORDER TO BE STRONG
IN ORDER TO BE STRONG IN
IN ORDER TO BE STRONG IN THE
WORLD
WORLD WE
IN ORDER TO BE STRONG IN THE
WORLD WE FIRST
WORLD WE FIRST HAVE
IN ORDER TO BE STRONG IN THE
WORLD WE FIRST HAVE TO
WORLD WE FIRST HAVE TO BE
WORLD WE FIRST HAVE TO BE STRONG
AT
AT HOME.
WORLD WE FIRST HAVE TO BE STRONG
THAT'S
AT HOME.
THAT'S WHY
THAT'S WHY WE
AT HOME.
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE TO
AT HOME.
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE TO WIN
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE TO WIN THE
AT HOME.
FOURTH
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE TO WIN THE
FOURTH FIGHT.
REFORMING
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE TO WIN THE
FOURTH FIGHT.
REFORMING OUR
REFORMING OUR GOVERNMENT
FOURTH FIGHT.
REFORMING OUR GOVERNMENT AND
REVITALIZING
REVITALIZING OUR
REFORMING OUR GOVERNMENT AND
REVITALIZING OUR DEMOCRACY
REVITALIZING OUR DEMOCRACY SO
REFORMING OUR GOVERNMENT AND
THAT
REVITALIZING OUR DEMOCRACY SO
THAT IT
THAT IT WORKS
REVITALIZING OUR DEMOCRACY SO
THAT IT WORKS FOR
THAT IT WORKS FOR EVERY
THAT IT WORKS FOR EVERY DAY
AMERICANS.
WE
WE HAVE
WE HAVE TO
WE HAVE TO STOP
WE HAVE TO STOP THE
WE HAVE TO STOP THE ENDLESS
WE HAVE TO STOP THE ENDLESS FLOW
OF
OF SECRET,
WE HAVE TO STOP THE ENDLESS FLOW
OF SECRET, UNACCOUNTABLE
OF SECRET, UNACCOUNTABLE MONEY
THAT
THAT IS
OF SECRET, UNACCOUNTABLE MONEY
THAT IS DISTORTING
THAT IS DISTORTING OUR
ELECTIONS,
ELECTIONS, CORRUPTING
THAT IS DISTORTING OUR
ELECTIONS, CORRUPTING OUR
POLITICAL
POLITICAL PROCESS,
ELECTIONS, CORRUPTING OUR
POLITICAL PROCESS, AND
POLITICAL PROCESS, AND DROWNING
ELECTIONS, CORRUPTING OUR
OUT
POLITICAL PROCESS, AND DROWNING
OUT THE
OUT THE VOICES
POLITICAL PROCESS, AND DROWNING
OUT THE VOICES OF
OUT THE VOICES OF OUR
OUT THE VOICES OF OUR PEOPLE.
WE
WE NEED
OUT THE VOICES OF OUR PEOPLE.
WE NEED JUSTICES
WE NEED JUSTICES ON
OUT THE VOICES OF OUR PEOPLE.
WE NEED JUSTICES ON THE
WE NEED JUSTICES ON THE SUPREME
COURT
COURT WHO
WE NEED JUSTICES ON THE SUPREME
COURT WHO WILL
COURT WHO WILL PROTECT
COURT WHO WILL PROTECT EVERY
CITIZEN'S
CITIZEN'S RIGHT
COURT WHO WILL PROTECT EVERY
CITIZEN'S RIGHT TO
CITIZEN'S RIGHT TO VOTE.
RATHER
RATHER THAN
CITIZEN'S RIGHT TO VOTE.
RATHER THAN EVERY
RATHER THAN EVERY CORPORATION'S
RIGHT
RIGHT TO
RATHER THAN EVERY CORPORATION'S
RIGHT TO BUY
ELECTIONS.
IF
IF NECESSARY
IF NECESSARY I
IF NECESSARY I WILL
IF NECESSARY I WILL SUPPORT
IF NECESSARY I WILL SUPPORT A
CONSTITUTIONAL
CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT
IF NECESSARY I WILL SUPPORT A
CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT TO
CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT TO UNDO
IF NECESSARY I WILL SUPPORT A
THE
CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT TO UNDO
THE SUPREME
THE SUPREME COURT'S
CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT TO UNDO
THE SUPREME COURT'S DECISION
THE SUPREME COURT'S DECISION IN
CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT TO UNDO
CITIZENS
THE SUPREME COURT'S DECISION IN
CITIZENS UNITED.
[CHEERING
THE SUPREME COURT'S DECISION IN
CITIZENS UNITED.
[CHEERING AND
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE] I
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE] I WANT
TO
TO MAKE
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE] I WANT
TO MAKE IT
TO MAKE IT EASIER
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE] I WANT
TO MAKE IT EASIER FOR
TO MAKE IT EASIER FOR EVERY
CITIZEN
CITIZEN TO
TO MAKE IT EASIER FOR EVERY
CITIZEN TO VOTE.
THAT'S
TO MAKE IT EASIER FOR EVERY
CITIZEN TO VOTE.
THAT'S WHY
THAT'S WHY I
CITIZEN TO VOTE.
THAT'S WHY I PROPOSE
THAT'S WHY I PROPOSE UNIVERSAL,
AUTOMATIC
AUTOMATIC REGISTRATION,
THAT'S WHY I PROPOSE UNIVERSAL,
AUTOMATIC REGISTRATION, AND
EXPANDED
EXPANDED EARLY
AUTOMATIC REGISTRATION, AND
EXPANDED EARLY VOTES.
I'LL
I'LL FIGHT
EXPANDED EARLY VOTES.
I'LL FIGHT BACK
I'LL FIGHT BACK AGAINST
REPUBLICAN
REPUBLICAN EFFORTS
I'LL FIGHT BACK AGAINST
REPUBLICAN EFFORTS TO
REPUBLICAN EFFORTS TO DISEMPOWER
AND
AND DISENFRANCHISE
REPUBLICAN EFFORTS TO DISEMPOWER
AND DISENFRANCHISE YOUNG
AND DISENFRANCHISE YOUNG PEOPLE,
POOR
POOR PEOPLE,
AND DISENFRANCHISE YOUNG PEOPLE,
POOR PEOPLE, PEOPLE
POOR PEOPLE, PEOPLE WITH
AND DISENFRANCHISE YOUNG PEOPLE,
DISABILITIES,
POOR PEOPLE, PEOPLE WITH
DISABILITIES, AND
DISABILITIES, AND PEOPLE
POOR PEOPLE, PEOPLE WITH
DISABILITIES, AND PEOPLE OF
COLOR.
WHAT
WHAT PART
COLOR.
WHAT PART OF
WHAT PART OF DEMOCRACY
COLOR.
WHAT PART OF DEMOCRACY ARE
WHAT PART OF DEMOCRACY ARE THEY
AFRAID
AFRAID OF?
BUT
BUT NO
AFRAID OF?
BUT NO MATTER
BUT NO MATTER HOW
AFRAID OF?
BUT NO MATTER HOW EASY
BUT NO MATTER HOW EASY WE
BUT NO MATTER HOW EASY WE MAKE
IT
IT TO
BUT NO MATTER HOW EASY WE MAKE
IT TO VOTE,
IT TO VOTE, WE
BUT NO MATTER HOW EASY WE MAKE
IT TO VOTE, WE STILL
IT TO VOTE, WE STILL HAVE
IT TO VOTE, WE STILL HAVE TO
GIVE
GIVE AMERICANS
IT TO VOTE, WE STILL HAVE TO
GIVE AMERICANS SOMETHING
GIVE AMERICANS SOMETHING WORTH
VOTING
VOTING FOR.
GOVERNMENT
GOVERNMENT IS
VOTING FOR.
GOVERNMENT IS NEVER
GOVERNMENT IS NEVER GOING
VOTING FOR.
GOVERNMENT IS NEVER GOING TO
HAVE
HAVE ALL
GOVERNMENT IS NEVER GOING TO
HAVE ALL THE
HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS
GOVERNMENT IS NEVER GOING TO
HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS BUT
HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS BUT IT
GOVERNMENT IS NEVER GOING TO
HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS BUT IT HAS
TO
TO BE
HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS BUT IT HAS
TO BE SMARTER,
TO BE SMARTER, SIMPLER
HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS BUT IT HAS
TO BE SMARTER, SIMPLER KS
TO BE SMARTER, SIMPLER KS MORE
HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS BUT IT HAS
EFFICIENT,
TO BE SMARTER, SIMPLER KS MORE
EFFICIENT, AND
EFFICIENT, AND A
TO BE SMARTER, SIMPLER KS MORE
EFFICIENT, AND A BETTER
EFFICIENT, AND A BETTER PARTNER.
TO BE SMARTER, SIMPLER KS MORE
THAT
EFFICIENT, AND A BETTER PARTNER.
THAT MEANS
THAT MEANS ACCESS
EFFICIENT, AND A BETTER PARTNER.
THAT MEANS ACCESS TO
THAT MEANS ACCESS TO ADVANCED
EFFICIENT, AND A BETTER PARTNER.
TECHNOLOGY
THAT MEANS ACCESS TO ADVANCED
TECHNOLOGY SO
TECHNOLOGY SO GOVERNMENT
THAT MEANS ACCESS TO ADVANCED
AGENCIES
TECHNOLOGY SO GOVERNMENT
AGENCIES CAN
AGENCIES CAN MORE
TECHNOLOGY SO GOVERNMENT
AGENCIES CAN MORE EFFECTIVELY
SERVE
SERVE THEIR
AGENCIES CAN MORE EFFECTIVELY
SERVE THEIR CUSTOMERS,
SERVE THEIR CUSTOMERS, THE
AGENCIES CAN MORE EFFECTIVELY
AMERICAN
SERVE THEIR CUSTOMERS, THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
WE
SERVE THEIR CUSTOMERS, THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
WE NEED
SERVE THEIR CUSTOMERS, THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
WE NEED EXPERTISE
WE NEED EXPERTISE AND
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
WE NEED EXPERTISE AND INNOVATION
FROM
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
WE NEED EXPERTISE AND INNOVATION
FROM THE
FROM THE PRIVATE
WE NEED EXPERTISE AND INNOVATION
FROM THE PRIVATE SECTOR
FROM THE PRIVATE SECTOR TO
WE NEED EXPERTISE AND INNOVATION
FROM THE PRIVATE SECTOR TO HELP
CUT
CUT WASTE
FROM THE PRIVATE SECTOR TO HELP
CUT WASTE AND
CUT WASTE AND STREAMLINE
SERVICES.
THERE
THERE IS
SERVICES.
THERE IS SO
THERE IS SO MUCH
SERVICES.
THERE IS SO MUCH THAT
THERE IS SO MUCH THAT WORKS
THERE IS SO MUCH THAT WORKS IN
AMERICA.
FOR
THERE IS SO MUCH THAT WORKS IN
AMERICA.
FOR EVERY
FOR EVERY PROBLEM
AMERICA.
FOR EVERY PROBLEM WE
FOR EVERY PROBLEM WE FACE,
SOMEONE,
SOMEONE, SOMEWHERE
FOR EVERY PROBLEM WE FACE,
SOMEONE, SOMEWHERE IN
SOMEONE, SOMEWHERE IN AMERICA,
IS
IS SOLVING
SOMEONE, SOMEWHERE IN AMERICA,
IS SOLVING IT.
SILICON
SILICON VALLEY
IS SOLVING IT.
SILICON VALLEY CRACKED
SILICON VALLEY CRACKED THE
IS SOLVING IT.
SILICON VALLEY CRACKED THE CODE
ON
ON SHARING
SILICON VALLEY CRACKED THE CODE
ON SHARING AND
ON SHARING AND SCALING
SILICON VALLEY CRACKED THE CODE
ON SHARING AND SCALING A
ON SHARING AND SCALING A WHILE
AGO.
MANY
ON SHARING AND SCALING A WHILE
AGO.
MANY STATES
ON SHARING AND SCALING A WHILE
AGO.
MANY STATES ARE
MANY STATES ARE PIONEERING
AGO.
MANY STATES ARE PIONEERING NEW
WAYS
AGO.
MANY STATES ARE PIONEERING NEW
WAYS TO
WAYS TO DELIVER
MANY STATES ARE PIONEERING NEW
WAYS TO DELIVER SERVICES.
I
I WANT
WAYS TO DELIVER SERVICES.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO HELP
WAYS TO DELIVER SERVICES.
I WANT TO HELP WASHINGTON
I WANT TO HELP WASHINGTON CATCH
UP.
TO
TO DO
TO DO THAT,
TO DO THAT, WE
TO DO THAT, WE NEED
TO DO THAT, WE NEED A
TO DO THAT, WE NEED A POLITICAL
SYSTEM
SYSTEM THAT
TO DO THAT, WE NEED A POLITICAL
SYSTEM THAT PRODUCES
SYSTEM THAT PRODUCES RESULTS.
BY
BY SOLVING
SYSTEM THAT PRODUCES RESULTS.
BY SOLVING PROBLEMS
BY SOLVING PROBLEMS THAT
BY SOLVING PROBLEMS THAT HOLD
BY SOLVING PROBLEMS THAT HOLD US
BACK,
BACK, NOT
BY SOLVING PROBLEMS THAT HOLD US
BACK, NOT ONE
BACK, NOT ONE OVERWHELMED
BY SOLVING PROBLEMS THAT HOLD US
BACK, NOT ONE OVERWHELMED BY
EXTREME
EXTREME PARTISANSHIP
BACK, NOT ONE OVERWHELMED BY
EXTREME PARTISANSHIP AND
INFLEXIBILITYY.
I'LL
EXTREME PARTISANSHIP AND
INFLEXIBILITYY.
I'LL ALWAYS
I'LL ALWAYS SEEK
INFLEXIBILITYY.
I'LL ALWAYS SEEK COMMON
I'LL ALWAYS SEEK COMMON GROUND
INFLEXIBILITYY.
WITH
I'LL ALWAYS SEEK COMMON GROUND
WITH FRIEND
WITH FRIEND AND
I'LL ALWAYS SEEK COMMON GROUND
WITH FRIEND AND OPPONENT
WITH FRIEND AND OPPONENT ALIKE.
I'LL ALWAYS SEEK COMMON GROUND
BUT
WITH FRIEND AND OPPONENT ALIKE.
BUT I'LL
BUT I'LL ALSO
WITH FRIEND AND OPPONENT ALIKE.
BUT I'LL ALSO STAND
BUT I'LL ALSO STAND MY
WITH FRIEND AND OPPONENT ALIKE.
BUT I'LL ALSO STAND MY GROUND
WHEN
WHEN I
MUST.
MUST. THAT'S
MUST. THAT'S SOMETHING
MUST. THAT'S SOMETHING I
MUST. THAT'S SOMETHING I DID,
WHETHER
WHETHER IT
MUST. THAT'S SOMETHING I DID,
WHETHER IT WAS
WHETHER IT WAS WORKING
MUST. THAT'S SOMETHING I DID,
WHETHER IT WAS WORKING WITH
REPUBLICANS
REPUBLICANS FOR
WHETHER IT WAS WORKING WITH
REPUBLICANS FOR HEALTHCARE,
REPUBLICANS FOR HEALTHCARE, FOR
WHETHER IT WAS WORKING WITH
CHILDREN
REPUBLICANS FOR HEALTHCARE, FOR
CHILDREN WITH
CHILDREN WITH OUR
REPUBLICANS FOR HEALTHCARE, FOR
CHILDREN WITH OUR NATIONAL
CHILDREN WITH OUR NATIONAL GUARD
REPUBLICANS FOR HEALTHCARE, FOR
OR
CHILDREN WITH OUR NATIONAL GUARD
OR IMPROVE
OR IMPROVE OUR
CHILDREN WITH OUR NATIONAL GUARD
OR IMPROVE OUR FOSTER
OR IMPROVE OUR FOSTER CARE
CHILDREN WITH OUR NATIONAL GUARD
OR IMPROVE OUR FOSTER CARE AND
ADOPTION
ADOPTION SYSTEM
OR IMPROVE OUR FOSTER CARE AND
ADOPTION SYSTEM OR
ADOPTION SYSTEM OR PASS
OR IMPROVE OUR FOSTER CARE AND
ADOPTION SYSTEM OR PASS A
ADOPTION SYSTEM OR PASS A TREATY
OR IMPROVE OUR FOSTER CARE AND
TO
ADOPTION SYSTEM OR PASS A TREATY
TO REDUCE
TO REDUCE THE
ADOPTION SYSTEM OR PASS A TREATY
TO REDUCE THE NUMBER
TO REDUCE THE NUMBER OF
ADOPTION SYSTEM OR PASS A TREATY
TO REDUCE THE NUMBER OF RUSSIAN
NUCLEAR
NUCLEAR WARHEADS
TO REDUCE THE NUMBER OF RUSSIAN
NUCLEAR WARHEADS THAT
NUCLEAR WARHEADS THAT COULD
TO REDUCE THE NUMBER OF RUSSIAN
THREATEN
NUCLEAR WARHEADS THAT COULD
THREATEN OUR
TO REDUCE THE NUMBER OF RUSSIAN
NUCLEAR WARHEADS THAT COULD
THREATEN OUR CITIES
THREATEN OUR CITIES AND
NUCLEAR WARHEADS THAT COULD
THREATEN OUR CITIES AND IT
THREATEN OUR CITIES AND IT IS
NUCLEAR WARHEADS THAT COULD
SOMETHING
THREATEN OUR CITIES AND IT IS
SOMETHING I
NUCLEAR WARHEADS THAT COULD
THREATEN OUR CITIES AND IT IS
SOMETHING I WILL
SOMETHING I WILL ALWAYS
THREATEN OUR CITIES AND IT IS
SOMETHING I WILL ALWAYS DO
SOMETHING I WILL ALWAYS DO AS
THREATEN OUR CITIES AND IT IS
YOUR
SOMETHING I WILL ALWAYS DO AS
YOUR PRESIDENT.
WE
WE AMERICANS
YOUR PRESIDENT.
WE AMERICANS MAY
WE AMERICANS MAY DIFFER,
YOUR PRESIDENT.
WE AMERICANS MAY DIFFER, DICKER,
STUMBLE,
STUMBLE, AND
WE AMERICANS MAY DIFFER, DICKER,
STUMBLE, AND FALL,
STUMBLE, AND FALL, BUT
WE AMERICANS MAY DIFFER, DICKER,
STUMBLE, AND FALL, BUT WE
STUMBLE, AND FALL, BUT WE ARE
WE AMERICANS MAY DIFFER, DICKER,
STUMBLE, AND FALL, BUT WE ARE AT
OUR
OUR BEST
STUMBLE, AND FALL, BUT WE ARE AT
OUR BEST WHEN
OUR BEST WHEN WE
STUMBLE, AND FALL, BUT WE ARE AT
OUR BEST WHEN WE PICK
OUR BEST WHEN WE PICK EACH
STUMBLE, AND FALL, BUT WE ARE AT
OUR BEST WHEN WE PICK EACH OTHER
UP,
UP, WHEN
OUR BEST WHEN WE PICK EACH OTHER
UP, WHEN WE
UP, WHEN WE HAVE
OUR BEST WHEN WE PICK EACH OTHER
UP, WHEN WE HAVE EACH
UP, WHEN WE HAVE EACH OTHER'S
BACK.
LIKE
LIKE ANY
BACK.
LIKE ANY FAMILY
LIKE ANY FAMILY OUR
LIKE ANY FAMILY OUR AMERICAN
FAMILY
FAMILY IS
LIKE ANY FAMILY OUR AMERICAN
FAMILY IS STRONGEST
FAMILY IS STRONGEST WHEN
LIKE ANY FAMILY OUR AMERICAN
FAMILY IS STRONGEST WHEN WE
CHERISH
CHERISH WHAT
FAMILY IS STRONGEST WHEN WE
CHERISH WHAT WE
CHERISH WHAT WE HAVE
FAMILY IS STRONGEST WHEN WE
CHERISH WHAT WE HAVE IN
CHERISH WHAT WE HAVE IN COMMON
FAMILY IS STRONGEST WHEN WE
AND
CHERISH WHAT WE HAVE IN COMMON
AND FIGHT
AND FIGHT BACK
CHERISH WHAT WE HAVE IN COMMON
AND FIGHT BACK AGAINST
AND FIGHT BACK AGAINST THOSE
CHERISH WHAT WE HAVE IN COMMON
AND FIGHT BACK AGAINST THOSE WHO
WOULD
WOULD DRIVE
AND FIGHT BACK AGAINST THOSE WHO
WOULD DRIVE US
WOULD DRIVE US APART.
PEOPLE
PEOPLE ALL
WOULD DRIVE US APART.
PEOPLE ALL OVER
PEOPLE ALL OVER THE
WOULD DRIVE US APART.
PEOPLE ALL OVER THE WORLD
PEOPLE ALL OVER THE WORLD HAVE
WOULD DRIVE US APART.
ASKED
PEOPLE ALL OVER THE WORLD HAVE
ASKED ME
ASKED ME HOW
PEOPLE ALL OVER THE WORLD HAVE
ASKED ME HOW COULD
ASKED ME HOW COULD YOU
ASKED ME HOW COULD YOU AND
PRESIDENT
PRESIDENT OBAMA
ASKED ME HOW COULD YOU AND
PRESIDENT OBAMA WORK
PRESIDENT OBAMA WORK TOGETHER
ASKED ME HOW COULD YOU AND
AFTER
PRESIDENT OBAMA WORK TOGETHER
AFTER YOU
AFTER YOU FOUGHT
PRESIDENT OBAMA WORK TOGETHER
AFTER YOU FOUGHT SO
AFTER YOU FOUGHT SO HARD
PRESIDENT OBAMA WORK TOGETHER
AFTER YOU FOUGHT SO HARD AGAINST
EACH
EACH OTHER
AFTER YOU FOUGHT SO HARD AGAINST
EACH OTHER IN
EACH OTHER IN THAT
AFTER YOU FOUGHT SO HARD AGAINST
EACH OTHER IN THAT LONG
CAMPAIGN?
NOW,
EACH OTHER IN THAT LONG
CAMPAIGN?
NOW, THAT
EACH OTHER IN THAT LONG
CAMPAIGN?
NOW, THAT IS
NOW, THAT IS AN
CAMPAIGN?
NOW, THAT IS AN UNDERSTANDABLE
QUESTION
CAMPAIGN?
NOW, THAT IS AN UNDERSTANDABLE
QUESTION CONSIDERING
QUESTION CONSIDERING THAT
NOW, THAT IS AN UNDERSTANDABLE
QUESTION CONSIDERING THAT IN
MANY
NOW, THAT IS AN UNDERSTANDABLE
QUESTION CONSIDERING THAT IN
MANY PLACES
MANY PLACES IF
QUESTION CONSIDERING THAT IN
MANY PLACES IF YOU
MANY PLACES IF YOU LOSE
QUESTION CONSIDERING THAT IN
MANY PLACES IF YOU LOSE AN
ELECTION
ELECTION YOU
MANY PLACES IF YOU LOSE AN
ELECTION YOU COULD
ELECTION YOU COULD GET
MANY PLACES IF YOU LOSE AN
IMPRISONED
ELECTION YOU COULD GET
IMPRISONED OR
IMPRISONED OR EXILED
ELECTION YOU COULD GET
IMPRISONED OR EXILED EVEN
KILLED,
KILLED, NOT
IMPRISONED OR EXILED EVEN
KILLED, NOT HIRED
KILLED, NOT HIRED AS
IMPRISONED OR EXILED EVEN
KILLED, NOT HIRED AS SECRETARY
OF
OF STATE.
BUT
BUT PRESIDENT
OF STATE.
BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA
BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA ASKED
OF STATE.
BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA ASKED ME
BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA ASKED ME TO
SERVE
SERVE AND
BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA ASKED ME TO
SERVE AND I
SERVE AND I ACCEPTED
BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA ASKED ME TO
SERVE AND I ACCEPTED BECAUSE
SERVE AND I ACCEPTED BECAUSE WE
BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA ASKED ME TO
BOTH
SERVE AND I ACCEPTED BECAUSE WE
BOTH LOVE
BOTH LOVE OUR
COUNTRY.
THAT'S
THAT'S HOW
COUNTRY.
THAT'S HOW WE
THAT'S HOW WE DO
THAT'S HOW WE DO IT
THAT'S HOW WE DO IT IN
THAT'S HOW WE DO IT IN AMERICA.
WITH
WITH THAT
THAT'S HOW WE DO IT IN AMERICA.
WITH THAT SAME
WITH THAT SAME SPIRIT
THAT'S HOW WE DO IT IN AMERICA.
WITH THAT SAME SPIRIT TOGETHER
WE
WE CAN
WITH THAT SAME SPIRIT TOGETHER
WE CAN WIN
WE CAN WIN THESE
WITH THAT SAME SPIRIT TOGETHER
WE CAN WIN THESE FOUR
WE CAN WIN THESE FOUR FIGHTS.
WITH THAT SAME SPIRIT TOGETHER
WE
WE CAN WIN THESE FOUR FIGHTS.
WE CAN
WE CAN BUILD
WE CAN WIN THESE FOUR FIGHTS.
WE CAN BUILD AN
WE CAN BUILD AN ECONOMY
WE CAN WIN THESE FOUR FIGHTS.
WE CAN BUILD AN ECONOMY WHERE
HARD
HARD WORK
WE CAN BUILD AN ECONOMY WHERE
HARD WORK IS
HARD WORK IS REWARDED.
WE CAN BUILD AN ECONOMY WHERE
WE
HARD WORK IS REWARDED.
WE CAN
WE CAN STRENGTHEN
HARD WORK IS REWARDED.
WE CAN STRENGTHEN OUR
WE CAN STRENGTHEN OUR FAMILIES.
HARD WORK IS REWARDED.
WE
WE CAN STRENGTHEN OUR FAMILIES.
WE CAN
WE CAN DEFEND
WE CAN STRENGTHEN OUR FAMILIES.
WE CAN DEFEND OUR
WE CAN DEFEND OUR COUNTRY
WE CAN DEFEND OUR COUNTRY AND
INCREASE
INCREASE OUR
WE CAN DEFEND OUR COUNTRY AND
INCREASE OUR OPPORTUNITIES
INCREASE OUR OPPORTUNITIES ALL
OVER
OVER THE
INCREASE OUR OPPORTUNITIES ALL
OVER THE WORLD
OVER THE WORLD AND
INCREASE OUR OPPORTUNITIES ALL
OVER THE WORLD AND WE
OVER THE WORLD AND WE CAN
INCREASE OUR OPPORTUNITIES ALL
OVER THE WORLD AND WE CAN RENEW
THE
THE PROMISE
OVER THE WORLD AND WE CAN RENEW
THE PROMISE OF
THE PROMISE OF OUR
OVER THE WORLD AND WE CAN RENEW
THE PROMISE OF OUR DEMOCRACY
THE PROMISE OF OUR DEMOCRACY IF
OVER THE WORLD AND WE CAN RENEW
WE
THE PROMISE OF OUR DEMOCRACY IF
WE ALL
WE ALL DO
THE PROMISE OF OUR DEMOCRACY IF
WE ALL DO OUR
WE ALL DO OUR PART
THE PROMISE OF OUR DEMOCRACY IF
WE ALL DO OUR PART IN
WE ALL DO OUR PART IN OUR
BUSINESSES,
BUSINESSES, UNIONS,
WE ALL DO OUR PART IN OUR
BUSINESSES, UNIONS, HOUSES
BUSINESSES, UNIONS, HOUSES OF
WORSHIP,
WORSHIP, SCHOOLS,
BUSINESSES, UNIONS, HOUSES OF
WORSHIP, SCHOOLS, AND,
WORSHIP, SCHOOLS, AND, YES,
BUSINESSES, UNIONS, HOUSES OF
WORSHIP, SCHOOLS, AND, YES, IN
THE
THE VOTING
WORSHIP, SCHOOLS, AND, YES, IN
THE VOTING BOOTH.
I
WORSHIP, SCHOOLS, AND, YES, IN
THE VOTING BOOTH.
I WANT
I WANT YOU
THE VOTING BOOTH.
I WANT YOU TO
I WANT YOU TO JOIN
THE VOTING BOOTH.
I WANT YOU TO JOIN ME
I WANT YOU TO JOIN ME IN
THE VOTING BOOTH.
I WANT YOU TO JOIN ME IN THIS
EFFORT.
HELP
I WANT YOU TO JOIN ME IN THIS
EFFORT.
HELP ME
I WANT YOU TO JOIN ME IN THIS
EFFORT.
HELP ME BUILD
I WANT YOU TO JOIN ME IN THIS
EFFORT.
HELP ME BUILD THIS
I WANT YOU TO JOIN ME IN THIS
EFFORT.
HELP ME BUILD THIS CAMPAIGN
I WANT YOU TO JOIN ME IN THIS
EFFORT.
HELP ME BUILD THIS CAMPAIGN AND
MAKE
EFFORT.
HELP ME BUILD THIS CAMPAIGN AND
MAKE IT
EFFORT.
HELP ME BUILD THIS CAMPAIGN AND
MAKE IT YOUR
EFFORT.
HELP ME BUILD THIS CAMPAIGN AND
MAKE IT YOUR OWN.
TALK
HELP ME BUILD THIS CAMPAIGN AND
MAKE IT YOUR OWN.
TALK TO
HELP ME BUILD THIS CAMPAIGN AND
MAKE IT YOUR OWN.
TALK TO YOUR
HELP ME BUILD THIS CAMPAIGN AND
MAKE IT YOUR OWN.
TALK TO YOUR FRIENDS,
HELP ME BUILD THIS CAMPAIGN AND
MAKE IT YOUR OWN.
TALK TO YOUR FRIENDS, YOUR
FAMILY,
MAKE IT YOUR OWN.
TALK TO YOUR FRIENDS, YOUR
FAMILY, YOUR
FAMILY, YOUR NEIGHBORS,
TALK TO YOUR FRIENDS, YOUR
FAMILY, YOUR NEIGHBORS, TEXT,
JOIN
JOIN TO
FAMILY, YOUR NEIGHBORS, TEXT,
JOIN TO 47246.
JOIN TO 47246. GO
FAMILY, YOUR NEIGHBORS, TEXT,
JOIN TO 47246. GO TO
JOIN TO 47246. GO TO HILLARY
CLINTON.COM
CLINTON.COM AND
JOIN TO 47246. GO TO HILLARY
CLINTON.COM AND SIGN
CLINTON.COM AND SIGN UP
JOIN TO 47246. GO TO HILLARY
CLINTON.COM AND SIGN UP TO
CLINTON.COM AND SIGN UP TO MAKE
JOIN TO 47246. GO TO HILLARY
CALLS
CLINTON.COM AND SIGN UP TO MAKE
CALLS AND
CALLS AND KNOCK
CLINTON.COM AND SIGN UP TO MAKE
CALLS AND KNOCK ON
DOORS.
IT
IT IS
DOORS.
IT IS NO
IT IS NO SECRET
IT IS NO SECRET THAT
IT IS NO SECRET THAT WE'RE
IT IS NO SECRET THAT WE'RE GOING
UP
UP SOME
IT IS NO SECRET THAT WE'RE GOING
UP SOME PRETTY
UP SOME PRETTY POWERFUL
IT IS NO SECRET THAT WE'RE GOING
UP SOME PRETTY POWERFUL FORCES
THAT
THAT WILL
UP SOME PRETTY POWERFUL FORCES
THAT WILL DO
THAT WILL DO AND
UP SOME PRETTY POWERFUL FORCES
THAT WILL DO AND SPEND
THAT WILL DO AND SPEND WHATEVER
IT
IT TAKES
THAT WILL DO AND SPEND WHATEVER
IT TAKES TO
IT TAKES TO ADVANCE
IT TAKES TO ADVANCE A
IT TAKES TO ADVANCE A VERY
DIFFERENT
DIFFERENT VISION
IT TAKES TO ADVANCE A VERY
DIFFERENT VISION FOR
DIFFERENT VISION FOR AMERICA.
IT TAKES TO ADVANCE A VERY
BUT
DIFFERENT VISION FOR AMERICA.
BUT I'VE
BUT I'VE SPENT
DIFFERENT VISION FOR AMERICA.
BUT I'VE SPENT MY
BUT I'VE SPENT MY LIFE
DIFFERENT VISION FOR AMERICA.
BUT I'VE SPENT MY LIFE FIGHTING
FOR
FOR CHILDREN,
BUT I'VE SPENT MY LIFE FIGHTING
FOR CHILDREN, FAMILIES,
FOR CHILDREN, FAMILIES, AND
BUT I'VE SPENT MY LIFE FIGHTING
FOR CHILDREN, FAMILIES, AND OUR
COUNTRY,
COUNTRY, AND
FOR CHILDREN, FAMILIES, AND OUR
COUNTRY, AND I'M
COUNTRY, AND I'M NOT
COUNTRY, AND I'M NOT STOPPING
NOW.
[CHEERING
[CHEERING AND
APPLAUSE]
[CHANTING]
[CHANTING] HILLARY!
HILLARY!
>>
>> NOW,
HILLARY!
>> NOW, I
>> NOW, I KNOW
HILLARY!
>> NOW, I KNOW HOW
>> NOW, I KNOW HOW HARD
HILLARY!
>> NOW, I KNOW HOW HARD THIS
>> NOW, I KNOW HOW HARD THIS JOB
IS.
I'VE
>> NOW, I KNOW HOW HARD THIS JOB
IS.
I'VE SEEN
>> NOW, I KNOW HOW HARD THIS JOB
IS.
I'VE SEEN IT
I'VE SEEN IT UP
IS.
I'VE SEEN IT UP CLOSE
I'VE SEEN IT UP CLOSE AND
PERSONAL.
ALL
I'VE SEEN IT UP CLOSE AND
PERSONAL.
ALL OUR
ALL OUR PRESIDENTS
PERSONAL.
ALL OUR PRESIDENTS COME
ALL OUR PRESIDENTS COME INTO
OFFICE
OFFICE LOOKING
ALL OUR PRESIDENTS COME INTO
OFFICE LOOKING SO
OFFICE LOOKING SO VIGOROUS
OFFICE LOOKING SO VIGOROUS AND
THEN
THEN WE
OFFICE LOOKING SO VIGOROUS AND
THEN WE WATCH
THEN WE WATCH THEIR
THEN WE WATCH THEIR HAIR
THEN WE WATCH THEIR HAIR GROW
GRAYER
GRAYER AND
THEN WE WATCH THEIR HAIR GROW
GRAYER AND GRAYER.
WELL,
WELL, I
GRAYER AND GRAYER.
WELL, I MAY
WELL, I MAY NOT
GRAYER AND GRAYER.
WELL, I MAY NOT BE
WELL, I MAY NOT BE THE
GRAYER AND GRAYER.
WELL, I MAY NOT BE THE YOUNGEST
CANDIDATE
CANDIDATE IN
WELL, I MAY NOT BE THE YOUNGEST
CANDIDATE IN THIS
CANDIDATE IN THIS RACE,
CANDIDATE IN THIS RACE, BUT
CANDIDATE IN THIS RACE, BUT I
WILL
WILL BE
CANDIDATE IN THIS RACE, BUT I
WILL BE THE
WILL BE THE YOUNGEST
CANDIDATE IN THIS RACE, BUT I
WILL BE THE YOUNGEST WOMAN
PRESIDENT
PRESIDENT IN
WILL BE THE YOUNGEST WOMAN
PRESIDENT IN THE
PRESIDENT IN THE HISTORY
WILL BE THE YOUNGEST WOMAN
PRESIDENT IN THE HISTORY OF
PRESIDENT IN THE HISTORY OF THE
UNITED
STATES.
[CHEERING
[CHEERING AND
APPLAUSE]
APPLAUSE] AND,
APPLAUSE] AND, AND
APPLAUSE] AND, AND THE
APPLAUSE] AND, AND THE FIRST
GRANDMOTHER
GRANDMOTHER AS
APPLAUSE] AND, AND THE FIRST
GRANDMOTHER AS WELL!
[CHEERING
[CHEERING AND
GRANDMOTHER AS WELL!
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE] AND
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE] AND ONE
ADDITIONAL
ADDITIONAL ADVANTAGE?
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE] AND ONE
YOU
ADDITIONAL ADVANTAGE?
YOU WON'T
YOU WON'T SEE
ADDITIONAL ADVANTAGE?
YOU WON'T SEE MY
YOU WON'T SEE MY HAIR
ADDITIONAL ADVANTAGE?
YOU WON'T SEE MY HAIR TURN
YOU WON'T SEE MY HAIR TURN WHITE
ADDITIONAL ADVANTAGE?
IN
YOU WON'T SEE MY HAIR TURN WHITE
IN THE
IN THE WHITE
YOU WON'T SEE MY HAIR TURN WHITE
IN THE WHITE HOUSE.
I'VE
I'VE BEEN
IN THE WHITE HOUSE.
I'VE BEEN COLORING
I'VE BEEN COLORING IT
IN THE WHITE HOUSE.
I'VE BEEN COLORING IT FOR
I'VE BEEN COLORING IT FOR YEARS.
SO,
SO, I'M
I'VE BEEN COLORING IT FOR YEARS.
SO, I'M LOOKING
SO, I'M LOOKING FOR
SO, I'M LOOKING FOR A
SO, I'M LOOKING FOR A GREAT
DEBATE
DEBATE AMONG
SO, I'M LOOKING FOR A GREAT
DEBATE AMONG DEMOCRATS,
REPUBLICANS,
REPUBLICANS, AND
DEBATE AMONG DEMOCRATS,
REPUBLICANS, AND INDEPENDENTS.
I'M
I'M NOT
REPUBLICANS, AND INDEPENDENTS.
I'M NOT RUNNING
I'M NOT RUNNING TO
REPUBLICANS, AND INDEPENDENTS.
I'M NOT RUNNING TO BE
I'M NOT RUNNING TO BE PRESIDENT
REPUBLICANS, AND INDEPENDENTS.
ONLY
I'M NOT RUNNING TO BE PRESIDENT
ONLY FOR
ONLY FOR THOSE
I'M NOT RUNNING TO BE PRESIDENT
ONLY FOR THOSE AMERICANS
ONLY FOR THOSE AMERICANS WHO
I'M NOT RUNNING TO BE PRESIDENT
ALREADY
ONLY FOR THOSE AMERICANS WHO
ALREADY AGREE
ALREADY AGREE WITH
ONLY FOR THOSE AMERICANS WHO
ALREADY AGREE WITH ME.
I
ONLY FOR THOSE AMERICANS WHO
ALREADY AGREE WITH ME.
I WANT
I WANT TO
ALREADY AGREE WITH ME.
I WANT TO BE
I WANT TO BE PRESIDENT
ALREADY AGREE WITH ME.
I WANT TO BE PRESIDENT FOR
I WANT TO BE PRESIDENT FOR ALL
AMERICANS.
ALONG
I WANT TO BE PRESIDENT FOR ALL
AMERICANS.
ALONG THE
ALONG THE WAY
AMERICANS.
ALONG THE WAY I'LL
ALONG THE WAY I'LL JUST
AMERICANS.
ALONG THE WAY I'LL JUST LET
ALONG THE WAY I'LL JUST LET YOU
AMERICANS.
IN
ALONG THE WAY I'LL JUST LET YOU
IN ON
IN ON THIS
ALONG THE WAY I'LL JUST LET YOU
IN ON THIS LITTLE
IN ON THIS LITTLE SECRET.
I
I WON'T
IN ON THIS LITTLE SECRET.
I WON'T GET
I WON'T GET EVERYTHING
I WON'T GET EVERYTHING RIGHT.
LORD
LORD KNOWS,
I WON'T GET EVERYTHING RIGHT.
LORD KNOWS, I'VE
LORD KNOWS, I'VE MADE
I WON'T GET EVERYTHING RIGHT.
LORD KNOWS, I'VE MADE MY
LORD KNOWS, I'VE MADE MY SHARE
I WON'T GET EVERYTHING RIGHT.
OF
LORD KNOWS, I'VE MADE MY SHARE
OF MISTAKES.
WELL,
LORD KNOWS, I'VE MADE MY SHARE
OF MISTAKES.
WELL, THERE'S
LORD KNOWS, I'VE MADE MY SHARE
OF MISTAKES.
WELL, THERE'S NO
WELL, THERE'S NO SHORTAGE
OF MISTAKES.
WELL, THERE'S NO SHORTAGE OF
PEOPLE
PEOPLE POINTING
WELL, THERE'S NO SHORTAGE OF
PEOPLE POINTING THEM
PEOPLE POINTING THEM OUT.
AND
AND I
PEOPLE POINTING THEM OUT.
AND I CERTAINLY
AND I CERTAINLY HAVEN'T
PEOPLE POINTING THEM OUT.
AND I CERTAINLY HAVEN'T WON
EVERY
EVERY BATTLE
AND I CERTAINLY HAVEN'T WON
EVERY BATTLE I'VE
EVERY BATTLE I'VE FOUGHT,
AND I CERTAINLY HAVEN'T WON
EVERY BATTLE I'VE FOUGHT, BUT
LEADERSHIP
LEADERSHIP MEANS
EVERY BATTLE I'VE FOUGHT, BUT
LEADERSHIP MEANS PERSEVERANCE
AND
AND HARD
LEADERSHIP MEANS PERSEVERANCE
AND HARD CHOICES.
YOU
LEADERSHIP MEANS PERSEVERANCE
AND HARD CHOICES.
YOU HAVE
LEADERSHIP MEANS PERSEVERANCE
AND HARD CHOICES.
YOU HAVE TO
LEADERSHIP MEANS PERSEVERANCE
AND HARD CHOICES.
YOU HAVE TO PUSH
YOU HAVE TO PUSH THROUGH
AND HARD CHOICES.
YOU HAVE TO PUSH THROUGH THE
SETBACKS
AND HARD CHOICES.
YOU HAVE TO PUSH THROUGH THE
SETBACKS AND
SETBACKS AND THE
YOU HAVE TO PUSH THROUGH THE
SETBACKS AND THE DISAPPOINTMENTS
AND
AND KEEP
SETBACKS AND THE DISAPPOINTMENTS
AND KEEP AT
AND KEEP AT IT.
SETBACKS AND THE DISAPPOINTMENTS
I
AND KEEP AT IT.
I THINK
I THINK YOU
AND KEEP AT IT.
I THINK YOU KNOW
I THINK YOU KNOW BY
AND KEEP AT IT.
I THINK YOU KNOW BY NOW
I THINK YOU KNOW BY NOW THAT
AND KEEP AT IT.
I'VE
I THINK YOU KNOW BY NOW THAT
I'VE BEEN
I'VE BEEN CALLED
I THINK YOU KNOW BY NOW THAT
I'VE BEEN CALLED MANY
I'VE BEEN CALLED MANY THINGS
I'VE BEEN CALLED MANY THINGS BY
MANY
MANY PEOPLE.
QUITTER
QUITTER IS
MANY PEOPLE.
QUITTER IS NOT
QUITTER IS NOT ONE
MANY PEOPLE.
QUITTER IS NOT ONE OF
THEM.
LIKE
LIKE SO
THEM.
LIKE SO MUCH
LIKE SO MUCH ELSE
LIKE SO MUCH ELSE IN
LIKE SO MUCH ELSE IN MY
LIKE SO MUCH ELSE IN MY LIFE,
LIKE SO MUCH ELSE IN MY LIFE, I
GOT
GOT THIS
LIKE SO MUCH ELSE IN MY LIFE, I
GOT THIS FROM
GOT THIS FROM MY
GOT THIS FROM MY MOTHER.
WHEN
WHEN I
GOT THIS FROM MY MOTHER.
WHEN I WAS
WHEN I WAS A
GOT THIS FROM MY MOTHER.
WHEN I WAS A GIRL
WHEN I WAS A GIRL SHE
GOT THIS FROM MY MOTHER.
WHEN I WAS A GIRL SHE NEVER
WHEN I WAS A GIRL SHE NEVER LET
GOT THIS FROM MY MOTHER.
ME
WHEN I WAS A GIRL SHE NEVER LET
ME BACK
ME BACK DOWN
WHEN I WAS A GIRL SHE NEVER LET
ME BACK DOWN FROM
ME BACK DOWN FROM ANY
WHEN I WAS A GIRL SHE NEVER LET
ME BACK DOWN FROM ANY BULLY
ME BACK DOWN FROM ANY BULLY OR
BARRIER.
IN
ME BACK DOWN FROM ANY BULLY OR
BARRIER.
IN HER
ME BACK DOWN FROM ANY BULLY OR
BARRIER.
IN HER LATER
ME BACK DOWN FROM ANY BULLY OR
BARRIER.
IN HER LATER YEARS,
IN HER LATER YEARS, MOM
BARRIER.
IN HER LATER YEARS, MOM LIVED
WITH
BARRIER.
IN HER LATER YEARS, MOM LIVED
WITH US
WITH US AND
IN HER LATER YEARS, MOM LIVED
WITH US AND SHE
WITH US AND SHE WOULD
IN HER LATER YEARS, MOM LIVED
WITH US AND SHE WOULD STILL
TEACH
TEACH ME
WITH US AND SHE WOULD STILL
TEACH ME THE
TEACH ME THE SAME
WITH US AND SHE WOULD STILL
TEACH ME THE SAME LESSONS.
I'D
I'D COME
TEACH ME THE SAME LESSONS.
I'D COME HOME
I'D COME HOME FROM
TEACH ME THE SAME LESSONS.
I'D COME HOME FROM A
I'D COME HOME FROM A HARD
TEACH ME THE SAME LESSONS.
I'D COME HOME FROM A HARD DAY
I'D COME HOME FROM A HARD DAY AT
TEACH ME THE SAME LESSONS.
THE
I'D COME HOME FROM A HARD DAY AT
THE SENATE
THE SENATE OR
I'D COME HOME FROM A HARD DAY AT
THE SENATE OR THE
THE SENATE OR THE STATE
I'D COME HOME FROM A HARD DAY AT
DEPARTMENT,
THE SENATE OR THE STATE
DEPARTMENT, SIT
DEPARTMENT, SIT DOWN
THE SENATE OR THE STATE
DEPARTMENT, SIT DOWN WITH
DEPARTMENT, SIT DOWN WITH HER
THE SENATE OR THE STATE
DEPARTMENT, SIT DOWN WITH HER AT
THE
THE SENATE OR THE STATE
DEPARTMENT, SIT DOWN WITH HER AT
THE SMALL
THE SMALL TABLE
DEPARTMENT, SIT DOWN WITH HER AT
THE SMALL TABLE IN
THE SMALL TABLE IN OUR
DEPARTMENT, SIT DOWN WITH HER AT
THE SMALL TABLE IN OUR BREAKFAST
NOOK,
NOOK, AND
THE SMALL TABLE IN OUR BREAKFAST
NOOK, AND JUST
NOOK, AND JUST LET
THE SMALL TABLE IN OUR BREAKFAST
NOOK, AND JUST LET EVERYTHING
POUR
POUR OUT.
NOOK, AND JUST LET EVERYTHING
AND
POUR OUT.
AND SHE
AND SHE WOULD
POUR OUT.
AND SHE WOULD REMIND
AND SHE WOULD REMIND ME
POUR OUT.
AND SHE WOULD REMIND ME WHY
AND SHE WOULD REMIND ME WHY WE
POUR OUT.
KEEP
AND SHE WOULD REMIND ME WHY WE
KEEP FIGHTING.
EVEN
AND SHE WOULD REMIND ME WHY WE
KEEP FIGHTING.
EVEN WHEN
AND SHE WOULD REMIND ME WHY WE
KEEP FIGHTING.
EVEN WHEN THE
AND SHE WOULD REMIND ME WHY WE
KEEP FIGHTING.
EVEN WHEN THE ODDS
EVEN WHEN THE ODDS ARE
KEEP FIGHTING.
EVEN WHEN THE ODDS ARE LONG
EVEN WHEN THE ODDS ARE LONG AND
KEEP FIGHTING.
THE
EVEN WHEN THE ODDS ARE LONG AND
THE OPPOSITION
THE OPPOSITION IS
EVEN WHEN THE ODDS ARE LONG AND
THE OPPOSITION IS FIERCE.
I
I CAN
THE OPPOSITION IS FIERCE.
I CAN STILL
I CAN STILL HEAR
THE OPPOSITION IS FIERCE.
I CAN STILL HEAR HER
I CAN STILL HEAR HER SAYING,
LIFE'S
LIFE'S NOT
I CAN STILL HEAR HER SAYING,
LIFE'S NOT ABOUT
LIFE'S NOT ABOUT WHAT
I CAN STILL HEAR HER SAYING,
LIFE'S NOT ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS
LIFE'S NOT ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS TO
YOU.
IT'S
LIFE'S NOT ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS TO
YOU.
IT'S ABOUT
IT'S ABOUT WHAT
YOU.
IT'S ABOUT WHAT YOU
IT'S ABOUT WHAT YOU DO
IT'S ABOUT WHAT YOU DO WITH
IT'S ABOUT WHAT YOU DO WITH WHAT
HAPPENS
HAPPENS TO
IT'S ABOUT WHAT YOU DO WITH WHAT
HAPPENS TO YOU.
SO
SO GET
HAPPENS TO YOU.
SO GET BACK
SO GET BACK OUT
SO GET BACK OUT THERE.
[APPLAUSE]
[APPLAUSE] SHE
SO GET BACK OUT THERE.
[APPLAUSE] SHE LIVED
[APPLAUSE] SHE LIVED TO
SO GET BACK OUT THERE.
[APPLAUSE] SHE LIVED TO BE
[APPLAUSE] SHE LIVED TO BE 92
YEARS
YEARS OLD,
[APPLAUSE] SHE LIVED TO BE 92
YEARS OLD, AND
YEARS OLD, AND I
[APPLAUSE] SHE LIVED TO BE 92
YEARS OLD, AND I OFTEN
YEARS OLD, AND I OFTEN THINK
ABOUT
ABOUT ALL
YEARS OLD, AND I OFTEN THINK
ABOUT ALL THE
ABOUT ALL THE BATTLES
YEARS OLD, AND I OFTEN THINK
ABOUT ALL THE BATTLES SHE
WITNESSED
WITNESSED OVER
ABOUT ALL THE BATTLES SHE
WITNESSED OVER THE
WITNESSED OVER THE COURSE
ABOUT ALL THE BATTLES SHE
WITNESSED OVER THE COURSE OF
WITNESSED OVER THE COURSE OF THE
ABOUT ALL THE BATTLES SHE
LAST
WITNESSED OVER THE COURSE OF THE
LAST CENTURY --
LAST CENTURY -- ALL
WITNESSED OVER THE COURSE OF THE
LAST CENTURY -- ALL THE
LAST CENTURY -- ALL THE PROGRESS
THAT
THAT WAS
LAST CENTURY -- ALL THE PROGRESS
THAT WAS WON
THAT WAS WON BECAUSE
THAT WAS WON BECAUSE AMERICANS
REFUSED
REFUSED TO
THAT WAS WON BECAUSE AMERICANS
REFUSED TO GIVE
REFUSED TO GIVE UP
THAT WAS WON BECAUSE AMERICANS
REFUSED TO GIVE UP OR
REFUSED TO GIVE UP OR BACK
REFUSED TO GIVE UP OR BACK DOWN.
SHE
SHE WAS
REFUSED TO GIVE UP OR BACK DOWN.
SHE WAS BORN
SHE WAS BORN ON
SHE WAS BORN ON JUNE
SHE WAS BORN ON JUNE 4,
SHE WAS BORN ON JUNE 4, 1919,
BEFORE
BEFORE WOMEN
SHE WAS BORN ON JUNE 4, 1919,
BEFORE WOMEN IN
BEFORE WOMEN IN AMERICA
BEFORE WOMEN IN AMERICA HAD
BEFORE WOMEN IN AMERICA HAD THE
RIGHT
RIGHT TO
BEFORE WOMEN IN AMERICA HAD THE
RIGHT TO VOTE,
RIGHT TO VOTE, BUT
BEFORE WOMEN IN AMERICA HAD THE
RIGHT TO VOTE, BUT ON
RIGHT TO VOTE, BUT ON THAT
RIGHT TO VOTE, BUT ON THAT VERY
DAY,
DAY, AFTER
RIGHT TO VOTE, BUT ON THAT VERY
DAY, AFTER YEARS
DAY, AFTER YEARS OF
RIGHT TO VOTE, BUT ON THAT VERY
DAY, AFTER YEARS OF STRUGGLE,
CONGRESS
CONGRESS PASSED
DAY, AFTER YEARS OF STRUGGLE,
CONGRESS PASSED THE
CONSTITUTIONAL
CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT
CONGRESS PASSED THE
CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT THAT
WOULD
WOULD CHANGE
CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT THAT
WOULD CHANGE THAT
WOULD CHANGE THAT FOREVER.
THE
THE STORY
WOULD CHANGE THAT FOREVER.
THE STORY OF
THE STORY OF AMERICA
WOULD CHANGE THAT FOREVER.
THE STORY OF AMERICA IS
THE STORY OF AMERICA IS A
WOULD CHANGE THAT FOREVER.
THE STORY OF AMERICA IS A STORY
OF
OF HARD
THE STORY OF AMERICA IS A STORY
OF HARD FOUGHT,
OF HARD FOUGHT, HARD
THE STORY OF AMERICA IS A STORY
OF HARD FOUGHT, HARD WON
PROGRESS.
AND
AND IT
PROGRESS.
AND IT CONTINUES
AND IT CONTINUES TODAY.
PROGRESS.
NEW
AND IT CONTINUES TODAY.
NEW CHAPTERS
PROGRESS.
AND IT CONTINUES TODAY.
NEW CHAPTERS ARE
NEW CHAPTERS ARE BEING
AND IT CONTINUES TODAY.
NEW CHAPTERS ARE BEING WRITTEN
BY
AND IT CONTINUES TODAY.
NEW CHAPTERS ARE BEING WRITTEN
BY MEN
AND IT CONTINUES TODAY.
NEW CHAPTERS ARE BEING WRITTEN
BY MEN AND
AND IT CONTINUES TODAY.
NEW CHAPTERS ARE BEING WRITTEN
BY MEN AND WOMEN
BY MEN AND WOMEN WHO
NEW CHAPTERS ARE BEING WRITTEN
BY MEN AND WOMEN WHO BELIEVE
THAT
NEW CHAPTERS ARE BEING WRITTEN
BY MEN AND WOMEN WHO BELIEVE
THAT ALL
NEW CHAPTERS ARE BEING WRITTEN
BY MEN AND WOMEN WHO BELIEVE
THAT ALL OF
NEW CHAPTERS ARE BEING WRITTEN
BY MEN AND WOMEN WHO BELIEVE
THAT ALL OF US,
THAT ALL OF US, NOT
BY MEN AND WOMEN WHO BELIEVE
THAT ALL OF US, NOT JUST
THAT ALL OF US, NOT JUST SOME,
BY MEN AND WOMEN WHO BELIEVE
BUT
THAT ALL OF US, NOT JUST SOME,
BUT ALL,
BUT ALL, SHOULD
THAT ALL OF US, NOT JUST SOME,
BUT ALL, SHOULD HAVE
BUT ALL, SHOULD HAVE THE
THAT ALL OF US, NOT JUST SOME,
BUT ALL, SHOULD HAVE THE CHANCE
TO
TO LIVE
BUT ALL, SHOULD HAVE THE CHANCE
TO LIVE UP
TO LIVE UP TO
BUT ALL, SHOULD HAVE THE CHANCE
TO LIVE UP TO OUR
TO LIVE UP TO OUR GOD
TO LIVE UP TO OUR GOD GIVEN
POTENTIAL.
NOT
TO LIVE UP TO OUR GOD GIVEN
POTENTIAL.
NOT ONLY
NOT ONLY BECAUSE
POTENTIAL.
NOT ONLY BECAUSE WE'RE
NOT ONLY BECAUSE WE'RE A
TOLERANT
TOLERANT COUNTRY
NOT ONLY BECAUSE WE'RE A
TOLERANT COUNTRY OR
TOLERANT COUNTRY OR A
NOT ONLY BECAUSE WE'RE A
TOLERANT COUNTRY OR A GENEROUS
COUNTRY
COUNTRY OR
TOLERANT COUNTRY OR A GENEROUS
COUNTRY OR A
COUNTRY OR A COMPASSIONATE
TOLERANT COUNTRY OR A GENEROUS
COUNTRY,
COUNTRY OR A COMPASSIONATE
COUNTRY, BUT
COUNTRY, BUT BECAUSE
COUNTRY OR A COMPASSIONATE
COUNTRY, BUT BECAUSE WE'RE
COUNTRY, BUT BECAUSE WE'RE A
BETTER,
BETTER, STRONGER,
COUNTRY, BUT BECAUSE WE'RE A
BETTER, STRONGER, MORE
PROSPEROUS
PROSPEROUS COUNTRY
BETTER, STRONGER, MORE
PROSPEROUS COUNTRY WHEN
PROSPEROUS COUNTRY WHEN WE
BETTER, STRONGER, MORE
HARNESS
PROSPEROUS COUNTRY WHEN WE
HARNESS THE
HARNESS THE TALENT,
PROSPEROUS COUNTRY WHEN WE
HARNESS THE TALENT, HARD
HARNESS THE TALENT, HARD WORK,
AND
AND INGENUITY
HARNESS THE TALENT, HARD WORK,
AND INGENUITY OF
AND INGENUITY OF EVERY
AND INGENUITY OF EVERY SINGLE
AMERICAN.
I
I WISH
AMERICAN.
I WISH MY
I WISH MY MOTHER
AMERICAN.
I WISH MY MOTHER COULD
I WISH MY MOTHER COULD HAVE
I WISH MY MOTHER COULD HAVE BEEN
WITH
WITH US
I WISH MY MOTHER COULD HAVE BEEN
WITH US LONGER.
I
I WISH
WITH US LONGER.
I WISH SHE
I WISH SHE COULD
WITH US LONGER.
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE SEEN
WITH US LONGER.
CHELSEA
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE SEEN
CHELSEA BECOME
CHELSEA BECOME A
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE SEEN
CHELSEA BECOME A MOTHER
CHELSEA BECOME A MOTHER HERSELF.
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE SEEN
I
CHELSEA BECOME A MOTHER HERSELF.
I WISH
I WISH SHE
CHELSEA BECOME A MOTHER HERSELF.
I WISH SHE COULD
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE
CHELSEA BECOME A MOTHER HERSELF.
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE MET
CHARLOTTE.
I
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE MET
CHARLOTTE.
I WISH
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE MET
CHARLOTTE.
I WISH SHE
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE MET
CHARLOTTE.
I WISH SHE COULD
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE MET
CHARLOTTE.
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE MET
CHARLOTTE.
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE SEEN
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE SEEN THE
CHARLOTTE.
AMERICA
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE SEEN THE
AMERICA WE'RE
CHARLOTTE.
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE SEEN THE
AMERICA WE'RE GOING
AMERICA WE'RE GOING TO
I WISH SHE COULD HAVE SEEN THE
AMERICA WE'RE GOING TO BUILD
TOGETHER.
ON
AMERICA WE'RE GOING TO BUILD
TOGETHER.
ON AMERICA,
AMERICA WE'RE GOING TO BUILD
TOGETHER.
ON AMERICA, WHERE
ON AMERICA, WHERE IF
TOGETHER.
ON AMERICA, WHERE IF YOU
ON AMERICA, WHERE IF YOU DO
TOGETHER.
ON AMERICA, WHERE IF YOU DO YOUR
PART,
PART, YOU
ON AMERICA, WHERE IF YOU DO YOUR
PART, YOU REAP
PART, YOU REAP THE
PART, YOU REAP THE REWARDS.
WHERE
WHERE WE
PART, YOU REAP THE REWARDS.
WHERE WE DON'T
WHERE WE DON'T LEAVE
WHERE WE DON'T LEAVE ANYONE
WHERE WE DON'T LEAVE ANYONE OUT
OR
OR ANYONE
OR ANYONE BEHIND.
AN
AN AMERICA
OR ANYONE BEHIND.
AN AMERICA WHERE
AN AMERICA WHERE A
AN AMERICA WHERE A FATHER
AN AMERICA WHERE A FATHER CAN
TELL
TELL HIS
AN AMERICA WHERE A FATHER CAN
TELL HIS DAUGHTER,
TELL HIS DAUGHTER, YES,
TELL HIS DAUGHTER, YES, YOU
TELL HIS DAUGHTER, YES, YOU CAN
BE
BE ANYTHING
TELL HIS DAUGHTER, YES, YOU CAN
BE ANYTHING YOU
BE ANYTHING YOU WANT
BE ANYTHING YOU WANT TO
BE ANYTHING YOU WANT TO BE,
BE ANYTHING YOU WANT TO BE, EVEN
PRESIDENT
PRESIDENT OF
BE ANYTHING YOU WANT TO BE, EVEN
PRESIDENT OF THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
THANK
THANK YOU
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
THANK YOU ALL!
GOD
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
THANK YOU ALL!
GOD BLESS
GOD BLESS YOU!
THANK YOU ALL!
AND
GOD BLESS YOU!
AND MAY
AND MAY GOD
GOD BLESS YOU!
AND MAY GOD BLESS
AND MAY GOD BLESS AMERICA!
[APPLAUSE
[APPLAUSE AND
CHEERING]
(music)(music)
IT(music) (music)
(music) (music)
(music) (music) >>